<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Akash Goswami</title>
    <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Akash Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 21:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Skyth3r.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customising my Hugo Theme</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</guid>
      <description>My Hugo website uses the Digital Garden Hugo theme but I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes in addition to using the theme. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed these changes below both for myself to refer back to and for anyone else that might find these useful to include in their own Hugo website 👇🏽
Updating lastmod text One of the first changes I made was to change the lastmod front matter text that was displayed on the theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>In the last few months, there has been a flurry of activity around personal blogs and owning your own data, since Musk took the reins of Twitter.
With that, a lot of people have been wondering how they can start their own websites. Since re-launching my website, I&amp;rsquo;ve had people ask me how they can make their own website in the last few weeks. To avoid repeating myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a guide on how you can build a website using Hugo and GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a personal website</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>Time and time again, we are shown that we cannot rely on third-party platforms to host our content.
The internet is constantly changing and with that, the platforms that host our content are constantly in flux. Platforms can fall just as quickly as they can rise, either by just going completely offline or by making drastic changes to how people interact with content on their site/platform.
There are countless examples of this happening in the past and more recently the 2022 Twitter meltdown has led to some massive changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
