<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guide on Akash Goswami</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guide on Akash Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language></language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 12:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remove files from Git history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/remove-files-from-git-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/remove-files-from-git-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A note for myself because I know I&amp;rsquo;ll probably do it again in the future&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to accidently commited a text file to a repository and pushed it to GitHub 🤦🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it didn&amp;rsquo;t contain any sensitive data, I still wanted to remove it from the repository&amp;rsquo;s history. I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/keeping-your-account-and-data-secure/removing-sensitive-data-from-a-repository&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;this guide on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and these are the exact steps I followed to resolve this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://formulae.brew.sh/formula/bfg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;bfg via Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;brew install bfg
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the file from the local repository and push this change to the GitHub repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository from GitHub to a new location on my machine
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;gh repo clone GITHUB_USERNAME_HERE/REPOSITORY_NAME_HERE
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ran the following command to remove the file from the repository&amp;rsquo;s history
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;bfg --delete-files FILENAME_HERE_WITH_EXTENSION
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then I ran these commands together (This was what was recommended after running the command above)
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git reflog expire --expire&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;now --all &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; git gc --prune&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;now --aggressive
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force push the changes to GitHub
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git push --force
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file should now be removed from GitHub and you should see a new commit message with no changes made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRM free books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy reading books on my Kindle. I also buy most of my digital books via Amazon. I never thought about making DRM-free copies of my eBooks until I read about how &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bjax_/a-tale-of-unwanted-disruption-my-week-without-amazon-df1074e3818b&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;an engineer had his Amazon account suspended&lt;/a&gt; due to a delivery driver&amp;rsquo;s false claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That really got me thinking about how I would feel if I lost access to my Amazon account. I’ve purchased most of my ebooks from Amazon. Losing access would mean losing the majority of my digital library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid such a situation, I decided it was time to make a copy of the digital eBooks I purchased from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article covers how I removed the DRM from my Kindle ebooks so I can read my books on any device without needing to use a Kindle app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going further, I’ll answer some questions some folks might have 👇🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-frequently-asked-questions-faq&#34;&gt;Quick Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is DRM?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRM stands for Digital Rights Management. It’s a type of tech used to control and manage access to copyrighted content. Its main purpose is to prevent content from being shared with those that did not pay for it and to also prevent the content from being modified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What issues does it pose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While DRM is used to prevent piracy, it can cause issues for legitimate users as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, say you bought a video game that comes with some DRM that checks you own the game by contacting the game publisher’s server before you can play the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine if the game publisher went out of business and with that, the server used for the DRM check goes offline with it. Now you’re in a situation where you’ve paid for a video game but you can no longer access it due to the DRM server going offline (Also what if you just wanted to play the game offline/without an internet connection?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital books from Amazon, are only intended to be read on Kindle devices and via the Kindle app using your Amazon account. If you lost access to your Amazon account for any reason, you would essentially lose access to the books you bought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should you care about removing DRM from your eBooks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s simple. Not having DRM on your eBooks means you can read them on any device using any app you want without having to worry about losing access to your books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it illegal to remove DRM from your digital items?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Just don’t distribute the DRM-free books you have as that would be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There a several guides online that explain how to do this, I initially followed those methods but I got some errors when following these guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I’ve listed the steps that worked for me. You might find that this exact approach might not work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need a Kindle eReader or the Kindle app on your machine. I personally used my Kindle eReader for this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - I use MacOS so these steps will be MacOS specific but the steps are similar if you are using a different operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First download &lt;a href=&#34;https://calibre-ebook.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a free open source e-book manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have Calibre installed, you’ll need to download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noDRM/DeDRM_tools/releases&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;NoDRM plugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the settings/preferences menu within Calibre and then click plug-ins under ‘Advanced’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the ‘Load plug-in from file’ option and then select the noDRM zip file you downloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your Kindle’s serial number from your Kindle device. You can find it under Settings &amp;gt; Device options &amp;gt; Device info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to the plug-in menu in Calibre, select the NoDRM plug-in (under the file type sub-heading) and click ‘Customise plug-in’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select ‘Kindle eInk ebooks’, click the green plus icon and enter your Kindle serial number and then click ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to the plug-ins menu, click ‘Get new plug-ins’ and then install the ‘KFX Input’ plug-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the Amazon website and then select the ‘Manage Your Content and Devices’ under your account menu and then click ‘Books’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the eBook you want to download and then select more actions &amp;gt; download and transfer via USB to download the eBook (Note - the file extension should be ‘AZW3’. I wasn’t able to get the ‘AFX’ file extension decryption/DRM removal working)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag and drop the eBook into the Calibre and then select ‘Convert Book” and then convert the book into whatever format you like (I usually go with ePub) and your eBook should have the DRM removed from it now 🎉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re able to remove DRM from your Kindle books you can read them on any device you like! If you want a Kindle like e-reader without having to buy a Kindle, you might want to consider a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pocketbook.ch/en-ch&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Pocketbook&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-to-buy-ebooks-going-forward&#34;&gt;Where to buy eBooks going forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can of course still buy your eBooks from Amazon, but it might be worth exploring what other options exist that allow you to get DRM free books way more easily. One of my favourites is a website called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/eBooks&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hive&lt;/a&gt; which sells eBooks in ePub and PDF formats by default and most books are similarly priced to their Amazon counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s everything you should need to build a DRM-free digital library. All that’s left to do is to back up your eBooks somewhere (like a digital cloud provider) so you can always keep a copy of the books you bought).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/community/file/1047875211730430527/Amazon-Kindle-Paperwhite-Mockup&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Article header image by Vyshnav Gangadharan under CC 4.0 license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, there has been a flurry of activity around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23513418/bring-back-personal-blogging&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;personal blogs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brycewray.com/posts/2022/11/own-your-stuff/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;owning your own data&lt;/a&gt;, since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23551060/elon-musk-twitter-takeover-layoffs-workplace-salute-emoji&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Musk took the reins of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, a lot of people have been wondering how they can start their own websites. Since re-launching my website, I&amp;rsquo;ve had people ask me how they can make their own website in the last few weeks. To avoid repeating myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a guide on how you can build a website using Hugo and GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kinsta.com/blog/hugo-static-site/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Other guides exist&lt;/a&gt;, but this one covers how I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my website in a simple and easy-to-follow guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this demo, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo Bear Blog theme&lt;/a&gt; as it&amp;rsquo;s a nice minimalist theme to start with. My website uses a theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Digital Garden&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-garden-hugo-theme.vercel.app/articles/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;installation steps&lt;/a&gt; for this theme are slightly more complicated. This guide will focus on using a simpler theme to demonstrate the basics of building websites with Hugo. There are many other &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;free Hugo themes&lt;/a&gt; you can choose from as well on the official Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One minor note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s not needed, I would recommend spending some money and buying a domain name. Usually, most people want a domain in the format of firstNameLastName[dot]com, but you can pick anything you like. For example, Sophie&amp;rsquo;s domain is &lt;a href=&#34;https://localghost.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;localghost.dev&lt;/a&gt;, a fun play on words for localhost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain name shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost too much and you can buy one from several domain name registrars. I bought my domain name, akashgoswami.com via &lt;a href=&#34;https://domains.google/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Google Domains&lt;/a&gt; and pay £10 a year for it (that&amp;rsquo;s less than £1 a month!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;What is Hugo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is a fast static site generator tool written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;. It uses templates and markdown files to generate webpages in seconds. The final result is a set of HTML files that you can deploy as a website using a hosting provider such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use an analogy. Let&amp;rsquo;s pretend that we&amp;rsquo;re making a sandwich, instead of building a website 🥪&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prepare our sandwich by laying out all the ingredients that we want to include in our sandwich. Once that&amp;rsquo;s done, you simply run the &amp;lsquo;make sandwich&amp;rsquo; command to create a sandwich within seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine we want to swap out some of those ingredients, add new ones or remove some we don&amp;rsquo;t like. We can run the &amp;lsquo;make sandwich&amp;rsquo; command again and have a new sandwich created with these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s how Hugo works, but instead of making a sandwich, it generates the files needed to make a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start building our website, there are a few things you&amp;rsquo;ll need beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-text-editor&#34;&gt;A text editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need something to edit your code in. I like using &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;.There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tools/editors/#visual-studio-code&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;handy Hugo extensions&lt;/a&gt; that you can install within Visual Studio Code as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;familiarity-with-using-a-command-line-app&#34;&gt;Familiarity with using a command line app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to navigate around files and run some Hugo commands using the command line interface. On macOS, the built-in command line tool is called &amp;lsquo;Terminal&amp;rsquo; (but I prefer using &lt;a href=&#34;https://iterm2.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;) and on Windows it&amp;rsquo;s Powershell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-package-manager&#34;&gt;A Package Manager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo can be installed as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;prebuilt binary&lt;/a&gt; but I prefer using a package manager. For macOS, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to use Homebrew. For Windows, it&amp;rsquo;s Chocolatey. The installation guides for both of these package managers is well documented so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the links to official installation instructions below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS - &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Installation instructions for Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows - &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/install&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Installation instructions for Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux - If you use a Linux-based OS then you can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/linux/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;correct installation steps for your Linux distro here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-and-git&#34;&gt;GitHub (and Git)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To host the website, we&amp;rsquo;re going to use GitHub Pages, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; account. Create an account (please also enable 2-factor authentication) and then install &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to install Git via your package manager if it&amp;rsquo;s not already on your machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install git.install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-our-website&#34;&gt;Setting up our website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, open the command line and navigate to where you want to create your website project file. I choose to create mine in Users/Akash (the default directory when you open Terminal on macOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run the following command (but replace username with your GitHub username):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site username.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This creates a new folder under the same name that contains some starter files for your Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then run the following two commands to navigate into this newly created folder and create a git repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd username.github.io
git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, we want to add our Hugo theme and set it as well by using the following two commands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog themes/hugo-bearblog
echo &amp;#34;theme = &amp;#39;hugo-bearblog&amp;#39;&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; hugo.toml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;modifying-the-site&#34;&gt;Modifying the site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the website is set up, you can add your own content to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to a theme&amp;rsquo;s recommended instructions. For &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;hugo-bearblog theme&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog/tree/master/exampleSite&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;exampleSite folder&lt;/a&gt; with the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;testing-and-building-the-site&#34;&gt;Testing and building the site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;rsquo;s done you can spin up the website by running &lt;code&gt;hugo server&lt;/code&gt; and then visiting http://localhost:1313/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stop the web server, just enter the command mentioned in your command line application (for macOS its Ctrl+C).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve made your changes, you can build your website by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. This will update the files within your public folder, which you can then deploy to a hosting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uploading-the-website-to-github&#34;&gt;Uploading the website to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;re happy with our website, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to upload it to GitHub. Open the GitHub Desktop application and then go to File &amp;gt; Open Local Repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you tick all the files and then enter a commit message. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be too fancy, &amp;lsquo;first commit&amp;rsquo; works well. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done that, click &amp;lsquo;Commit to main&amp;rsquo; and then the &amp;lsquo;Publish repository&amp;rsquo; button. A popup will appear asking you to name your new repository. Name it &amp;lsquo;username.github.io&amp;rsquo; and set it to be public before you click the &amp;lsquo;Publish Repository&amp;rsquo; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-actions&#34;&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deploy your website, open the new repository via GitHub on a web browser, and then head to Settings &amp;gt; Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here you can switch the source to &amp;lsquo;GitHub Actions&amp;rsquo; and the default Hugo action should be suggested. Click configure button and then commit the code to your main branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you now head back to the Actions tab you can see a workflow running to build your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;setting-your-domain-name-optional&#34;&gt;Setting your domain name (Optional)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a custom domain, you can set your website&amp;rsquo;s name from the Custom Domain section of the Pages settings page. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to set your DNS records from your domain registrar to point to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your website has been built, you can view it by entering either username.github.io or your custom domain name from your web browser!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! You&amp;rsquo;ve built your own website 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know the basics, feel free to edit anything you like; switch themes, write new posts, the choice is yours. You can now host your own website, and push new content to it by syncing your changes from your machine to GitHub via GitHub Desktop. Just remember to also run the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command to rebuild the website after making any changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you found this guide helpful at all or want to suggest an improvement, feel free to reach out to me and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>