<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Akash Goswami</title>
    <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Akash Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Skyth3r.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>In the last few months, there has been a flurry of activity around personal blogs and owning your own data, since Musk took the reins of Twitter.
With that, a lot of people have been wondering how they can start their own websites. Since re-launching my website, I&amp;rsquo;ve had people ask me how they can make their own website in the last few weeks. To avoid repeating myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a guide on how you can build a website using Hugo and GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a personal website</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>Time and time again, we are shown that we cannot rely on third-party platforms to host our content.
The internet is constantly changing and with that, the platforms that host our content are constantly in flux. Platforms can fall just as quickly as they can rise, either by just going completely offline or by making drastic changes to how people interact with content on their site/platform.
There are countless examples of this happening in the past and more recently the 2022 Twitter meltdown has led to some massive changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying Back Your Time</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/buying-back-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/buying-back-your-time/</guid>
      <description>A talk I presented at You Got This in Cyberspace about knowing when to prioritise saving time vs saving money and a simple framework for how we can buy back our time.
View the full talk here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akash &amp; Money Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/akash-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/akash-and-money/</guid>
      <description>A writing side project I started in 2020 that covers topics around personal finance. Currently the newsletter has 180+ subscribers.
View the Akash &amp;amp;amp; Money website here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual Receipt Generator</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/manual-receipt-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/manual-receipt-generator/</guid>
      <description>A simple python third party terminal client based on the reference receipts app that attaches receipts to Monzo transactions using the Monzo Receipts API and a json payload.
You can find the source code here on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TfL to Monzo</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/tfl-to-monzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/tfl-to-monzo/</guid>
      <description>TfL to Monzo was an severless application built as my project for my Cloud Computing module at university with a friend.
It was written in Python and made use of AWS Lambda to process TfL jounrey data into Monzo recipts.
The Lambda function would recieve incoming transcation webhook events from a linked Monzo account, check if they were TfL transcations and then run a web scraper script to extract the matching journey data from the TfL web portal before then submitting this data as a reciept to the Monzo receipt API endpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Workout</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/credit-card-workout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/credit-card-workout/</guid>
      <description>A website that takes a users credit card balance, interest rate and monthly amount they wish to pay to calculate how long it would take them to pay their debt off as well as showing them how much interest they have accumulated. This was made within 24 hours for the Porticode 2.0 Hackathon.
The source code is hosted here on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
