<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Akash Goswami</title>
    <link>https://akashgoswami.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Akash Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language></language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akashgoswami.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Got This Scraper</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/you-got-this-scraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/you-got-this-scraper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Python script to scrape the metadata from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://yougotthis.io/library&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;You Got This library&lt;/a&gt; and output the formatted data into a txt file that can be used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/You-Got-This-Scraper&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;View the code here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note from Sage</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/z/sage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/z/sage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hkjjjjkjn, c kasch a mnxç,mcmzzd. .mx
X&lt;br&gt;
X;x
Find us jkdxflckzs ;x \’d’;d
&lt;br&gt;
X
Du mlf mncv ;Leclerc ,c,d&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note from Nova</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/z/nova/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/z/nova/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ujhgmngnggnngggngn
kbnkn nl;l
;l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;;;;;;;
;l
&amp;rsquo;l
l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v nnnhouh bv a&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Tips</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/z/japan-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/z/japan-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: This is a work in progress page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips for visiting Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-tips&#34;&gt;General Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have an iPhone, add a Suica card to your Apple Wallet and then add it to Express Mode via the settings. This lets you tap in and out of most public transport extremely quickly. You can also use the for payments in a number of stores and topping it up is done within seconds from the Apple Wallet app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid missing the last train. Ubers are really expensive in Japan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note down the 7-11 locations near where you&amp;rsquo;re staying. They are open 24/7 and all have an ATM that accepts all international bank cards (great for when you need to make a cash withdrawal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to drive in Japan (yes this includes go karts!)? Remember to get your International Drivers Permit before you leave the UK. You can get it from The Post Office for about £5.50 and need to bring your drivers linsce and a passport photo of yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tokyo&#34;&gt;Tokyo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monkey Kart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teamLab Planets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Disneyland/Tokyo DisneySea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAUNA RESET Pint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensō-ji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asakusa Kagetsudō - Matcha ice cream melon pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matcha Sweets Kaminari-Issa - assortment of matcha items, including a matcha beer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soranoiro NIPPON - Tokyo Ramen Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tajimaya Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omoide Yokochō&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;locations&#34;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pokémon Center Shibuya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shibuya Scramble Crossing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsukiji Outer Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;osaka&#34;&gt;Osaka&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-1&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rikuro’s - Fluffy japanese cheesecake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;locations-1&#34;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dotombori - Ebisubashi Bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsūtenkaku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Osaka Castle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Studios Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Osaka Tenmangu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kyoto&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;activities-1&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-2&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kikyo Sushi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nishiki Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;locations-2&#34;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hōkan-ji Temple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiyomizu-dera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fushimi Inari Taisha (Thousand Tori Gates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kinkaku-ji (Golden Temple)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bamboo forest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kyoto Tower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An eSim database!</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/esimdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/esimdb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I came across a handly little app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airalo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Airalo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airalo lets you install data only eSims on your phone - perfect for a trip abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always been my go to since (most) mobile networks in the UK re-introuduced roaming fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://esimdb.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;esimbdb&lt;/a&gt;. A way of comparing eSim prices from various eSim providers for different countries!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably still going to use Airalo. It might cost a little more, but the app is super conveniance, accepts Apple Pay (or Google Pay on Android), gives you cashback credit on your purchases and simplifies the eSim installion process (it&amp;rsquo;s a one tap install on iOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to give Airalo a spin? Use my code &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;AKASH336&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for $3 off your first purchase (I also get $3 in credit as well).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A solar powered website</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/solar-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 21:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/solar-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I came across a quirky little website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Low Tech Magazine&lt;/a&gt; is a website that explores forgotten tech and energy sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Articles on the website are split into three main categories; &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/low-tech-solutions/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Low-tech solutions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/high-tech-problems/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;High-tech problems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/obsolete-technology/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Obsolete Technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite part. It&amp;rsquo;s a solar powered website ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally the website goes down when it&amp;rsquo;s not sunny enough in Barcelona (where the web server is based) and the backup battery has run dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do when you want to read articles from the website and the site is down? Well you can access the site&amp;rsquo;s content offline&amp;hellip;as &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/offline-reading/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;physical books&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s such a interesting take on websites that I really like the idea of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite article from the website so far - &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2023/02/can-we-make-bicycles-sustainable-again/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Can We Make Bicycles Sustainable Again?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Double Tap</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/apple-watch-double-tap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/apple-watch-double-tap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 12th September 2023, Apple announced the new Apple Watch Series 9 with a new double tap guesture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except&amp;hellip;this new guesture isn&amp;rsquo;t actually new. You can enable it on your Apple Watch (Series 4 and later, Apple Watch SE and later, and Apple Watch Ultra) already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Apple Watch app on your iPhone, head to Settings &amp;gt; Accessibility &amp;gt; AssistiveTouch and then toggle &amp;lsquo;Hand Gestures&amp;rsquo; on. You can now control your entire Apple Watch with one hand using the Pinch, Double Pinch, Clench and Double Clench gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works flawlessly on my Apple Watch Series 8 (gestures on older models might be less reliable). The difference between the new double tap guesture and the double pinch guesture seems to be minimal with the expection of the double tap guesture being enabled by default on the new Apple Watch and the hardware being slighlty better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade an Apple Watch for this one feature but battery life and other improvements would be my main reason for getting a newer Apple Watch. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sticking to my Series 8.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arc&#39;s secert reader mode</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/arc-reader-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/arc-reader-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the features I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked in Apple&amp;rsquo;s Safari web browser is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/safari/sfri32632/mac&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Safari Reader mode&lt;/a&gt;, which removes ads, navigation or other distracting elements from a web page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works perfectly for me on iOS but on my laptop, I mainly use Google Chrome and Arc for my web browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome has a reader type view hidden under &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt; and by then searching for &amp;lsquo;reading mode&amp;rsquo; but it&amp;rsquo;s still a bit complicated to enable and doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide the same view as Safari&amp;rsquo;s web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arc.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Arc for macOS&lt;/a&gt; has a hidden reader mode that can be enabled on a web page by pressing the &lt;code&gt;option + command + r&lt;/code&gt; keys together which is much more similar to Safari&amp;rsquo;s reader mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - Arc&amp;rsquo;s reader mode is still in beta but does a great job regardless&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houston, we have notes!</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/adding-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/adding-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to the articles, I’ve decided to add a notes section to the website now. There are times when I wanted to write a short piece about something but it didn’t feel right to put it in the articles section of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I just want to…note something down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hence the &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/notes&#34; &gt;notes section&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-notes-meant-to-be&#34;&gt;What are notes meant to be?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes will be short pieces of writing. Most likely a couple of lines long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’ll basically be my equivalent of a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a note ends up getting too long, I might decide to nudge it over to the articles section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-rss-feed&#34;&gt;Notes RSS feed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/articles/building-websites-with-hugo&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a new RSS feed is auto-magically generated for notes.
If you want to subscribe to it, here’s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/notes/index.xml&#34; &gt;notes RSS feed link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use an adblocker</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/adblocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/notes/adblocker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You should be using an adblocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not because ads are bad (although some are really annoying), but because even &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/22/fbi-ad-blocker/?guccounter=1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the FBI recommend using one for security&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://ublockorigin.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; and block those scam adverts that pop up at the top of search results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRM free books</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy reading books on my Kindle. I also buy most of my digital books via Amazon. I never thought about making DRM-free copies of my eBooks until I read about how &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bjax_/a-tale-of-unwanted-disruption-my-week-without-amazon-df1074e3818b&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;an engineer has his Amazon account suspended&lt;/a&gt; due to a delivery driver&amp;rsquo;s false claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That really got me thinking about how I would feel if I lost access to my Amazon account. I’ve purchased most of my ebooks from Amazon. Losing access would mean losing the majority of my digital library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid such a situation, I decided it was time to make a copy of the digital eBooks I purchased from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article covers how I removed the DRM from my Kindle ebooks so I can read my books on any device without needing to use a Kindle app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going further, I’ll answer some questions some folks might have 👇🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-frequently-asked-questions-faq&#34;&gt;Quick Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is DRM?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRM stands for Digital Rights Management. It’s a type of tech used to control and manage access to copyrighted content. Its main purpose is to prevent content from being shared with those that did not pay for it and to also prevent the content from being modified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What issues does it pose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While DRM is used to prevent piracy, it can cause issues for legitimate users as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, say you bought a video game that comes with some DRM that checks you own the game by contacting the game publisher’s server before you can play the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine if the game publisher went out of business and with that, the server used for the DRM check goes offline with it. Now you’re in a situation where you’ve paid for a video game but you can no longer access it due to the DRM server going offline (Also what if you just wanted to play the game offline/without an internet connection?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital books from Amazon, are only intended to be read on Kindle devices and via the Kindle app using your Amazon account. If you lost access to your Amazon account for any reason, you would essentially lose access to the books you bought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should you care about removing DRM from your eBooks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s simple. Not having DRM on your eBooks means you can read them on any device using any app you want without having to worry about losing access to your books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it illegal to remove DRM from your digital items?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Just don’t distribute the DRM-free books you have as that would be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There a several guides online that explain how to do this, I initially followed those methods but I got some errors when following these guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I’ve listed the steps that worked for me. You might find that this exact approach not working for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need a Kindle eReader or the Kindle app on your machine. I personally used my Kindle eReader for this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - I use MacOS so these steps will be MacOS specific but the steps are similar if you are using a different operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First download &lt;a href=&#34;https://calibre-ebook.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a free open source e-book manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have Calibre installed, you’ll need to download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noDRM/DeDRM_tools/releases&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;NoDRM plugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the settings/preferences menu within Calibre and then click plug-ins under ‘Advanced’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the ‘Load plug-in from file’ option and then select the noDRM zip file you downloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your Kindle’s serial number from your Kindle device. You can find it under Settings &amp;gt; Device options &amp;gt; Device info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back the plug-in menu in Calibre, select the NoDRM plug-in (under the file type sub-heading) and click ‘Customise plug-in’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select ‘Kindle eInk ebooks’, click the green plus icon and enter your Kindle serial number and then click ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to the plug-ins menu, click ‘Get new plug-ins’ and then install the ‘KFX Input’ plug-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the Amazon website and then select the ‘Manage Your Content and Devices’ under your account menu and then click ‘Books’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the eBook you want to download and then select more actions &amp;gt; download and transfer via USB to download the eBook (Note - the file extension should be ‘AZW3’. I wasn’t able to get the ‘AFX’ file extension decryption/DRM removal working)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag and drop the eBook into the Calibre and then select ‘Convert Book” and then convert the book into whatever format you like (I usually go with ePub) and your eBook should have the DRM removed from it now 🎉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re able to remove DRM from your Kindle books you can read them on any device you like! If you want a Kindle like e-reader without having to buy a Kindle, you might want to consider a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pocketbook.ch/en-ch&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Pocketbook&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-to-buy-ebooks-going-forward&#34;&gt;Where to buy eBooks going forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can of course still buy your eBooks from Amazon, but it might be worth exploring what other options exist that allow you to get DRM free books way more easily. One of my favourites is a website called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/eBooks&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hive&lt;/a&gt; which sells eBooks in ePub and PDF formats by default and most books are similarly priced to their Amazon counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s everything you should need to build a DRM-free digital library. All that’s left to do is to back up your eBooks somewhere (like a digital cloud provider) so you can alway keep a copy of the books you bought).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/community/file/1047875211730430527/Amazon-Kindle-Paperwhite-Mockup&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Article header image by Vyshnav Gangadharan under CC 4.0 license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Leave (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/sabbatical-leave-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/sabbatical-leave-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took 9 weeks off work. Of those 9 weeks, I spent 8 travelling. This is a summary of how I found my time off and what I did, things I learnt from my first long-term travel trip and my favourite highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-sabbatical-leave&#34;&gt;What is sabbatical leave?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick 101 - sabbatical leave is an extended period of time away from work. Common reasons for taking sabbatical leave are to pursue interests outside of work; such as travelling, studying, volunteering or even just to take a break to just rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-i-get-my-sabbatical-leave&#34;&gt;How did I get my sabbatical leave?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work at a bank called &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Monzo&lt;/a&gt; and about a year ago they introduced a new benefit. 3 months of paid sabbatical leave for those that had been at the company for 4 years. It just happens so that I was months away from hitting my 4 year work anniversary at the time of this announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I did the logical thing and started planning how I would spend these 3 months away from work right away. In the end, I’ve taken 9 weeks of sabbatical leave this year, with plans of using the remaining next year for another trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terms-and-conditions&#34;&gt;Terms and Conditions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the catch? It almost sounds too good to be true right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, there was nothing that was of any concern. There were only two conditions I had to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was that for the amount of time, I took as sabbatical leave, I needed to give double the length of that as my notice for taking the leave. Since I took 9 weeks off, I had to give 18 weeks of notice before taking the time off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other condition was that you’re required to keep working for the company for at least 6 months after taking sabbatical leave or I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay it back. Sounds pretty reasonable to me. I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on quitting anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-i-do-during-my-sabbatical&#34;&gt;What did I do during my sabbatical?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was really conflicted about what to do with my time off. Part of me really wanted to travel and another part of me wanted to stay at home and work on several projects I just never found the time for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I decided to prioritise travelling and also make use of the credit card points/air miles I’d been saving up for the last 6 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of planning, I ended up visiting 6 countries on my trip; The Netherlands, Germany, Japan, Vietnam, Indonesia and Singapore. I went slowly through these countries to take the time to explore without feeling like I didn’t have enough time to do everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally my plan was to use all 3 months of sabbatical leave to travel across all of south-east Asia, Japan, South Korea and also Australia but it felt like I was trying to do too much in one trip. Adding locations like South Korea and Australia would have also made the trip expensive 💸&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I think travelling for 2 months instead of 3 was the right call. I started to feel a bit overwhelmed towards the end of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel-tips&#34;&gt;Travel Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not an expert when it comes to solo travelling and I’ve never done a trip for this long before. The journey wasn’t always smooth and I managed to run into some problems along the way. Here’s what I think people should consider before travelling for long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get away from work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To truly immerse yourself while travelling, one of the first things I would consider doing is switching off from work (that is of course, if you didn’t quit your job to go and travel). No emails, no Slack or Microsoft Teams. Nothing. If you have a work laptop/phone, leave it at home. I personally just ended up logging out of my work email account and Slack and made sure I couldn’t log back in until after I got back from my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack less&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I had to learn the hard way. Avoid over-packing. Easier said than done. Learn how to pack efficiently, use some packing cubes and try and travel with a single bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do that…it was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, double-check where the nearest place to do laundry is before you need to do it. You’ll thank yourself later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus tip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - If you are going to check-in some luggage for the flight, have a day or two&amp;rsquo;s worth of clothes/essentials in your carry-on. A friend that joined me in Japan had his suitcase lost by the airline. He did get it back in the end, but had to go a few days without his stuff 😬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book flexible/refundable tickets, accommodation, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can cost a little extra to choose the fully refundable/flexible but there are times when you’ll be grateful you can just change your plans without any worries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up doing this myself, I changed my accommodation in Bali 2 nights before arriving and extended my stay in the areas I really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything needs to be fully flexible, however. Flights are usually fine to not book as fully refundable. Most accommodation options in south-east Asia are really cheap so I booked everything as fully refundable (I only had to pay for the first night upfront and usually paid the rest on arrival).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leads me to my next tip…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t plan everything in advance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s nice to have a plan and some things you definitely do need to book in advance. Not every day has to be planned down to the last minute, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s better to just embrace the randomness. That’s how I ended up doing some things I would never have considered, like trying out a sensory deprivation tank in Vietnam, climbing an active volcano at 4 am in the morning to watch the sunrise, or accidentally walking right into the Sanja Festival in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll find more exciting things to do and see walking down random streets and by talking to people you encounter along the way on your trip. I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spend less time on your phone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. Phones are the modern-day equivalent of a Swiss Army knife. They are incredibly useful but they can also be extremely distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s too easy to grab your phone and start scrolling through Instagram or TikTok when you’ve got a spare moment. I try not to look at my phone too much when I’m travelling (I make an exception for when I need to contact people).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay in hostels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re solo travelling, hostels are the best place to stay in my opinion. It’s cheap, sociable, and overall just really fun. Most hostels also offer private rooms if you’re not keen on sharing a room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most memorable moments from my trip from thanks to the friends I met along the way. Hostels are the perfect environment for meeting new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare for things to go wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t except so many things to go wrong on this trip. Train strikes, almost missing my flight (twice), almost paying over £200 for an Uber&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these setbacks, I still had an amazing time! Sure it was annoying/frustrating when things went wrong, but situations like that really put that Brain Tracy quote into perspective for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot control what happens to you, but you can control your attitude toward what happens to you, and in that, you will be mastering change rather than allowing it to master you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus the travel stories where things go wrong are always way more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-5-highlights&#34;&gt;Top 5 highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of exciting moments from my trip. Here’s what were my top five:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Driving a go-kart down the streets of Tokyo
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/img/sabbatical-leave/tokyo_go_karts.png&#34; alt=&#34;Me, sitting in a go-kart at an intersection of the Shibuya scramble crossing&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Climbing up Mt Batur at 4 am to watch the sunrise from the peak in Bali
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/img/sabbatical-leave/mt_batur.png&#34; alt=&#34;A view of the valley covered in clouds from the peak of Mt Batur at 6 am in the morning&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waking up at 4:30 am in the morning to an iconic photo of the Hōkan-ji Temple in Kyoto
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/img/sabbatical-leave/hokan_ji.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunrise photo of the Hōkan-ji Temple in Kyoto&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching the sunset on a boat at Ha Long Bay in Vietnam
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/img/sabbatical-leave/halong_bay.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset of the bay at Ha Long Bay in Vietnam&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking a photo with this adorable chihuahua at the Senso-ji temple festive (Sanja Matsuri) in Tokyo
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/img/sabbatical-leave/chihuahua.png&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of me holding a chihuahua wearing a costume with glasses for the Senso-ji temple festive (Sanja Matsuri)&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back at work now but I still have some sabbatical leave left to use. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on carrying it over to next year and using it for a trip to South Africa. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely also do a few smaller trips across Europe before that though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I really enjoy travelling, it&amp;rsquo;s always been the people that I&amp;rsquo;ve met that have made each trip ten times better. While a lot of these new friends might be scattered across the world, I plan on dropping in on a few of them from time to time as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to be back on another adventure soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shoutout&#34;&gt;Shoutout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, none of this would have been possible without my workplace. A massive thanks to Monzo for introducing the new sabbatical leave policy. While other companies do offer similar policies for long-term employees, Monzo&amp;rsquo;s policy is unmatched by any other company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising my Hugo Theme</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Hugo website uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Digital Garden Hugo theme&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes in addition to using the theme. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed these changes below both for myself to refer back to and for anyone else that might find these useful to include in their own Hugo website 👇🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating-lastmod-text&#34;&gt;Updating lastmod text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first changes I made was to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/ee9926c786e458476524ac571be01a7ea6a38285&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;change the lastmod front matter text&lt;/a&gt; that was displayed on the theme. Previously it would default to showing &lt;code&gt;Pruned January 2, 2023&lt;/code&gt; on articles with the &lt;code&gt;lastmod&lt;/code&gt; front matter. After my change to the article single layout it now instead shows &lt;code&gt;Last tended to on January 2, 2023&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ if .Date }}
    &amp;lt;p class=&amp;#34;text-sm text-slate-500 !mb-8&amp;#34;&amp;gt; Planted {{ $date }}
		{{ if ne $lastmod $date}}
			&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Last tended to on {{ .Lastmod.Format &amp;#34;January 2, 2006&amp;#34; }}
        {{ end }}
	&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
{{ end }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-analytics&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding Google Analytics to the site is pretty simple as it&amp;rsquo;s natively supported by the theme I&amp;rsquo;m using. Within the config.toml file, you just need to add the Google Analytics tracking ID in the format, &amp;ldquo;googleAnalytics = &amp;lsquo;TRAKCING_CODE_HERE&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue I noticed with this was the fact analytics data would be pinged back to Google Analytics while I worked on the website locally on my own machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix this, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/1bcb816700f2244d7a8337f61be5b410886f88bd#diff-5f948a63b2e0f5e8409b3a709cb74c89451854c6ded2959a6f110d5340001cc1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;replaced the config.toml file stored in the root of the repository with a config folder&lt;/a&gt; and then split the config.toml file into two files, a default file that contained all the config settings for the site, and a production config.toml file that contains only the Google Analytics tracking code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I work on new things for the website I run the command &lt;code&gt;hugo server --environment development -D&lt;/code&gt;, which loads only the default config file. When re-building the website, I use the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command takes both config files and merges them together to build the production website, thus resolving the issue of generating accidently analytics data during testing and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-article-front-matter&#34;&gt;Additional Article Front Matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up adding a few new improvements to the article front matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;article-read-time&#34;&gt;Article read time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/a3cea7373e46fd49c8ab0c0e1499497741153237&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Added a read time for articles&lt;/a&gt;. This is automatically generated and listed for each article item. This is based on the code found &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/readingtime-define/13036/4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ if gt .ReadingTime 1 }}
    {{ .Scratch.Set &amp;#34;readingTime&amp;#34; &amp;#34;minutes&amp;#34; }}
{{ else }}
    {{ .Scratch.Set &amp;#34;readingTime&amp;#34; &amp;#34;minute&amp;#34; }}
{{ end }}
Reading time: {{ .ReadingTime }} {{ .Scratch.Get &amp;#34;readingTime&amp;#34; }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tags&#34;&gt;Tags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be able to nagivate my site articles by tags, so I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/29ede00b08c2f0eabe217eee315ef9924498250d&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;added tags to each article&lt;/a&gt; and updated the autogenerated tags page (was previously blank) as well. The code from the tags page is currently just copied from the theme&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme/tree/main/layouts/portfolio&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;portfolio layout&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect but it works for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Tags:
{{ with .Param &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34; }}
    {{ range $index, $tag := (. | sort) }} 
        {{ with $.Site.GetPage (printf &amp;#34;/%s/%s&amp;#34; &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34; $tag) }}
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;{{ .Permalink }}&amp;#34;&amp;gt;#{{ $tag | urlize }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
        {{ end }}
    {{ end }}
{{ end }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rel-me-verifcation&#34;&gt;rel-me verifcation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modified the social icons sidebar code to &lt;a href=&#34;ttps://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/f7cf25f796ead76c1348da976cb980e899f1302a&#34; &gt;include rel=me&lt;/a&gt;. Used for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.joinmastodon.org/user/profile/#verification&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;verification on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;a class=&amp;#34;px-2 py-1.5 rounded-md text-sm block text-slate-800 dark:text-slate-50 {{ if eq (.URL|absURL) $permalink }} bg-slate-800 text-white dark: {{ else }} hover:bg-slate-200 dark:hover:bg-slate-700 {{ end }}&amp;#34;
    href=&amp;#34;{{ .URL }}&amp;#34; target=&amp;#34;_blank&amp;#34; rel=&amp;#34;noopener noreferrer me&amp;#34;&amp;gt;
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;404-page-copy&#34;&gt;404 page copy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/1dd845aa4b5894753755a2384eb4d1f784067337&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Added some copy to the 404 page&lt;/a&gt; as it was previously a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-me-a-coffee-widget&#34;&gt;Buy me a coffee widget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/698221f0451372bac9b85b90fcff1b9f92321597&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Added a buy me a coffee widget&lt;/a&gt; to each article page by creating a new partial shortcode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, there has been a flurry of activity around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23513418/bring-back-personal-blogging&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;personal blogs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brycewray.com/posts/2022/11/own-your-stuff/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;owning your own data&lt;/a&gt;, since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23551060/elon-musk-twitter-takeover-layoffs-workplace-salute-emoji&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Musk took the reins of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, a lot of people have been wondering how they can start their own websites. Since re-launching my website, I&amp;rsquo;ve had people ask me how they can make their own website in the last few weeks. To avoid repeating myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a guide on how you can build a website using Hugo and GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kinsta.com/blog/hugo-static-site/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Other guides exist&lt;/a&gt;, but this one covers how I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my website in a simple and easy-to-follow guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this demo, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo Bear Blog theme&lt;/a&gt; as it&amp;rsquo;s a nice minimalist theme to start with. My website uses a theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Digital Garden&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-garden-hugo-theme.vercel.app/articles/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;installation steps&lt;/a&gt; for this theme are slightly more complicated. This guide will focus on using a simpler theme to demonstrate the basics of building websites with Hugo. There are many other &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;free Hugo themes&lt;/a&gt; you can choose from as well on the official Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One minor note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s not needed, I would recommend spending some money and buying a domain name. Usually, most people want a domain in the format of firstNameLastName[dot]com, but you can pick anything you like. For example, Sophie&amp;rsquo;s domain is &lt;a href=&#34;https://localghost.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;localghost.dev&lt;/a&gt;, a fun play on words for localhost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain name shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost too much and you can buy one from several domain name registrars. I bought my domain name, akashgoswami.com via &lt;a href=&#34;https://domains.google/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Google Domains&lt;/a&gt; and pay £10 a year for it (that&amp;rsquo;s less than £1 a month!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;What is Hugo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is a fast static site generator tool written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;. It uses templates and markdown files to generate webpages in seconds. The final result is a set of HTML files that you can deploy as a website using a hosting provider such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use an analogy. Let&amp;rsquo;s pretend that we&amp;rsquo;re making a sandwich, instead of building a website 🥪&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prepare our sandwich by laying out all the ingredients that we want to include in our sandwich. Once that&amp;rsquo;s done, you simply run the &amp;lsquo;make sandwich&amp;rsquo; command to create a sandwich within seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine we want to swap out some of those ingredients, add new ones or remove some we don&amp;rsquo;t like. We can run the &amp;lsquo;make sandwich&amp;rsquo; command again and have a new sandwich created with these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s how Hugo works, but instead of making a sandwich, it generates the files needed to make a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start building our website, there are a few things you&amp;rsquo;ll need beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-text-editor&#34;&gt;A text editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need something to edit your code in. I like using &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;.There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tools/editors/#visual-studio-code&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;handy Hugo extensions&lt;/a&gt; that you can install within Visual Studio Code as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;familiarity-with-using-a-command-line-app&#34;&gt;Familiarity with using a command line app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to navigate around files and run some Hugo commands using the command line interface. On macOS, the built-in command line tool is called &amp;lsquo;Terminal&amp;rsquo; (but I prefer using &lt;a href=&#34;https://iterm2.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;) and on Windows it&amp;rsquo;s Powershell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-package-manager&#34;&gt;A Package Manager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo can be installed as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;prebuilt binary&lt;/a&gt; but I prefer using a package manager. For macOS, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to use Homebrew. For Windows, it&amp;rsquo;s Chocolatey. The installation guides for both of these package managers is well documented so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the links to official installation instructions below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS - &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Installation instructions for Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows - &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/install&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Installation instructions for Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux - If you use a Linux-based OS then you can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/linux/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;correct installation steps for your Linux distro here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-and-git&#34;&gt;GitHub (and Git)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To host the website, we&amp;rsquo;re going to use GitHub Pages, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; account. Create an account (please also enable 2-factor authentication) and then install &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to install Git via your package manager if it&amp;rsquo;s not already on your machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install git.install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-our-website&#34;&gt;Setting up our website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, open the command line and navigate to where you want to create your website project file. I choose to create mine in Users/Akash (the default directory when you open Terminal on macOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run the following command (but replace username with your GitHub username):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site username.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This creates a new folder under the same name that contains some starter files for your Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then run the following two commands to navigate into this newly created folder and create a git repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd username.github.io
git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, we want to add our Hugo theme and set it as well by using the following two commands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog themes/hugo-bearblog
echo &amp;#34;theme = &amp;#39;hugo-bearblog&amp;#39;&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; config.toml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;rsquo;s done you can spin up the website by running &lt;code&gt;hugo server&lt;/code&gt; and then visiting http://localhost:1313/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stop the web server, just enter the command mentioned in your command line application (for macOS its Ctrl+C).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modifying-the-site&#34;&gt;Modifying the site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the website is set up, you can add your own content to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to a theme&amp;rsquo;s recommended instructions. For &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;hugo-bearblog theme&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog/tree/master/exampleSite&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;exampleSite folder&lt;/a&gt; with the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve made your changes, you can build your website by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. This will update the files within your public folder, which you can then deploy to a hosting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uploading-the-website-to-github&#34;&gt;Uploading the website to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;re happy with our website, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to upload it to GitHub. Open the GitHub Desktop application and then go to File &amp;gt; Open Local Repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you tick all the files and then enter a commit message. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be too fancy, &amp;lsquo;first commit&amp;rsquo; works well. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done that, click &amp;lsquo;Commit to main&amp;rsquo; and then the &amp;lsquo;Publish repository&amp;rsquo; button. A popup will appear asking you to name your new repository. Name it &amp;lsquo;username.github.io&amp;rsquo; and set it to be public before you click the &amp;lsquo;Publish Repository&amp;rsquo; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-actions&#34;&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deploy your website, open the new repository via GitHub on a web browser, and then head to Settings &amp;gt; Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here you can switch the source to &amp;lsquo;GitHub Actions&amp;rsquo; and the default Hugo action should be suggested. Click configure button and then commit the code to your main branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you now head back to the Actions tab you can see a workflow running to build your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;setting-your-domain-name-optional&#34;&gt;Setting your domain name (Optional)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a custom domain, you can set your website&amp;rsquo;s name from the Custom Domain section of the Pages settings page. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to set your DNS records from your domain registrar to point to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your website has been built, you can view it by entering either username.github.io or your custom domain name from your web browser!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! You&amp;rsquo;ve built your own website 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know the basics, feel free to edit anything you like; switch themes, write new posts, the choice is yours. You can now host your own website, and push new content to it by syncing your changes from your machine to GitHub via GitHub Desktop. Just remember to also run the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command to rebuild the website after making any changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you found this guide helpful at all or want to suggest an improvement, feel free to reach out to me and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a personal website</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time and time again, we are shown that we cannot rely on third-party platforms to host our content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is constantly changing and with that, the platforms that host our content are constantly in flux. Platforms can fall just as quickly as they can rise, either by just going &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/site-deaths&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;completely offline&lt;/a&gt; or by making drastic changes to how people interact with content on their site/platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless examples of this happening in the past and more recently the 2022 Twitter meltdown has led to some massive changes. One of these changes is that the newsletter platform Twitter acquired just two years ago, Revue is now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/14/23509254/twitter-revue-shutdown-newsletter-data-deletion&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;shutting down&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;digital-platforms-are-fragile&#34;&gt;Digital platforms are fragile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s partly why I’m writing this. The shutdown of Revue has been particularly frustrating for me as someone who moved their &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashandmoney.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; from another newsletter service to Revue thinking it would be a better fit earlier this year. The announced shutdown left me scrambling to migrate my content and subscribers over the Christmas holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just goes to show you the kind of problems we face when we trust third-party platforms to host our content. Thankfully I managed to export my content &amp;amp; subscribers in time, but that got me wondering&amp;hellip;How do I avoid this happening again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;owning-your-content&#34;&gt;Owning your content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to start owning our digital content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning more about IndieWeb, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to follow their &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/principles&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;community principles&lt;/a&gt;. The one that stood out to me was the principle of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/own_your_data&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;owning your data&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So going forward I&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting more of my content here on this website where I don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about another platform dying out and losing my content. Hosting my content also gives me the ability to fully control how my website/content looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean I’m quitting on using other platforms entirely but instead I plan on using this website to complement my activity on other digital platforms. You&amp;rsquo;ll likely see my cross-posting most of my content from here to these other platforms for visibility (A practice coined as &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt; by IndieWeb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-having-a-personal-website&#34;&gt;The benefits of having a personal website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a great number of benefits as to why you should have your own website but here are the reasons that really matter to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform independent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest reason for me at the moment. All my content is owned by me and hosted on my website, overall reducing my dependence on third-party platforms for content hosting. I won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about my account being banned, I won&amp;rsquo;t have to migrate my data after another platform announces that it&amp;rsquo;s shutting down and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about a platform suddenly removing its free tier and demanding payment to continue using their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, this website is built using a static site generator and hosted via &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. In the future, if I wanted to change hosting platforms or the structure of this website, I have the full flexibility to do so all while maintaining access to my content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robust &amp;amp; compact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m using a static site generator for this website now, this has simplified a lot for me and has helped make the website a lot smaller and more compact. Due to its small size, I&amp;rsquo;m able to back up the entire site to several other code hosting/cloud storage platforms with ease. Currently, you can find this website on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, using a static site generator has also done a lot of the heavy lifting when it comes to SEO optimisation and has drastically improved the website&amp;rsquo;s load times as pointed out by this speed test 👇🏽
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/img/personal-website/pagespeed-insights-desktop-100.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pagespeed insights results desktop: 100% all pagespeed-insights-desktop-100-performace&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-expect-from-this-website&#34;&gt;What to expect from this website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can you expect from this website then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m someone that has several interests and hobbies so I don&amp;rsquo;t want to box myself in with a particular theme or topic. My interests are not set in stone, and I expect them to change over time but there will likely be many recurring themes &amp;amp; topics I write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I plan on writing things around programming, tech, travel, video games, projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on, things I&amp;rsquo;m learning, life updates and anything else I find interesting or useful that I think is worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-is-not-a-blog&#34;&gt;This is NOT a blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of against the idea of calling this a blog. I found that having a blog always felt really pressurising. It felt like every post had to be perfect and I would end up spending too much time polishing up each post before publishing them. I would end up publishing less and less over time, while fussing over each post, trying to chase that sense of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/posts/perfectionism&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;perfection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-to-my-digital-garden&#34;&gt;Welcome to my Digital Garden!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come to like the term &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;digital garden&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and I think it better suits what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to achieve with this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is my public digital garden. A place for me to cultivate, and grow my thoughts, ideas, and other bits of information freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote from Maggie Appleton explains it well while keeping it short and simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gardens present information in a richly linked landscape that grows slowly over time. Everything is arranged and connected in ways that allow you to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I&amp;rsquo;d like to build. An inter-connected garden of information around the things that interest me. I like to think of it more as being a content &lt;em&gt;curator&lt;/em&gt; rather than being a content creator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I think there is a lot of information out there in the world and there&amp;rsquo;s only so much the human brain can hold and retain. Having a secondary space (almost like a second brain) for collecting and organising meaningful notes, thoughts and ideas can help free cognitive capacity, a bit like backing up your computer&amp;rsquo;s hard drive to cloud storage to free up memory on the local disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have multiple digital gardens, scattered across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instapaper.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/i/akash56&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt;, etc, but this is the first one I&amp;rsquo;ll be publishing publicly as a centralised home to share what I find important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as this is for other people to read, this is also for me to reflect on myself and build upon existing ideas and thoughts of mine that would otherwise usually get lost among the various note-taking apps I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about rebuilding my website for some time, but never got around to doing it. It was thanks to a handful of people that I found the motivation to start working on this site again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to give a little shoutout to them for how they helped me find the direction I wanted to go with this website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shoutouts&#34;&gt;Shoutouts:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localghost.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Sophie Koonin&lt;/a&gt; - For having an awesome personal website that inspired me to redesign mine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bradleyjkemp.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Bradley J Kemp&lt;/a&gt; - For suggesting the static site generator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; to me which has now become my favourite web framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maggieappleton.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Maggie Appleton&lt;/a&gt; - For her brilliant essay on the history of digital gardens leading me to rethink what I wanted my personal website to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apvarun.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;AP Varun&lt;/a&gt; - For the minimal &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;digital garden Hugo theme&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m using for this website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Yusuf Bouzekri&lt;/a&gt; - For his posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/posts/perfectionism&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;perfectionism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/posts/the-content-creation-dilemma&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the content creation dilemma&lt;/a&gt;, which helped me actually publish this post after reading them both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What you need to know about...Bitcoin</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey friends 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last year or so, everyone has either been talking about Bitcoin or has at least heard of it by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is Bitcoin? Should I buy Bitcoin? Is Bitcoin a scam?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all questions that have been asked (and more) by a lot of people when they first heard of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve had many conversations with people about Bitcoin; people who saw it as an amazing opportunity, people who thought it was a massive scam and those who just didn’t really understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, Bitcoin (and cryptocurrencies in general) has always been an interesting topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I wanted to use this newsletter issue to share with you what I think of Bitcoin and what I think more people need to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; - I won’t be covering the technical details of Bitcoin here and the following issue is one of my longer pieces. If you wanted a quick summary of what you need to know about Bitcoin, check out this thread I wrote on Twitter last year 👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;🥇 BITCOIN 101 THREAD 🥇&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This year El Salvador made &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; legal tender 🇸🇻&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Tesla and Microstrategy have bought billions of dollars worth of bitcoins 💸&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But what actually is Bitcoin?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a guide to everything you NEED to know about Bitcoin ($BTC)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THREAD BELOW 👇 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/W0QadFHJnb&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/W0QadFHJnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Akash Goswami 👨🏽‍💻 (@akashgoswami_) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_/status/1442799252665606145?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should make this clear before going further…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing discussed here is financial advice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is for educational and entertainment purposes only. Please don’t make financial decisions based on this newsletter issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a financial advisor. I’m just a guy that is interested in personal finance (and by extension, cryptocurrencies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bias&#34;&gt;Bias&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I should mention is that my option will be slightly biased. I own a small amount of Bitcoin, so I’ll be trying to show a balanced view here but I thought it was worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-makes-bitcoin-different&#34;&gt;What makes Bitcoin different?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/tech/were-there-cryptocurrencies-bitcoin/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Bitcoin was not the world’s first attempt at a cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; but rather it was the first successful decentralised cryptocurrency to have taken off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is an open-source decentralised peer to peer currency that had no central authority that controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always like comparing it to the likes of email, because who owns email?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is no one because it’s an open standard that other companies have built things on top of, but they don’t ‘own’ email because of this. The same can be said for Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, there are a number of factors to Bitcoin’s success since its invention but there are five main factors that make Bitcoin valuable or desirable as a currency to people. Let’s have a look at each one in a bit more detail below…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scarcity&#34;&gt;Scarcity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fixed-supply&#34;&gt;Fixed Supply&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scarcity is the first factor that makes Bitcoin different from other currencies. Scarcity simply means that there is a limited supply or shortage of a certain thing. A lot of things have a limited supply if you think about it, oil, computer chips, gold, limited edition trainers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin’s case, there are a maximum number of Bitcoins that can ever exist. Bitcoin was hardcoded with a fixed supply of 21 million bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might sound like a lot but roughly 2.8 to 3.8 million bitcoins are said to already be lost and there are bitcoin wallets with hundreds if not thousands of bitcoins already in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a limited supply of bitcoins in circulation right now and once all 21 million bitcoins have been mined, there will never be any new bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional currencies like the US dollar or the British pound sterling, don’t have a limited supply as more can be printed when needed. This is partly why traditional currencies lose value over time due to inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin on the other hand is not subject to inflation but rather deflation as creating new bitcoins becomes increasingly more difficult over time due to…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;halving-events&#34;&gt;Halving Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a &lt;em&gt;“Halving Event”&lt;/em&gt; you say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The halving is something that currently happens roughly every 4 years. Currently, when a block is successful ‘mined’, the person (or machine) that mined this block is given a reward in bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, this reward was initially set at 50 bitcoins. 4 years later it dropped to 25 bitcoins and in 2016 it dropped to 12.5 bitcoins per block. The last halving event was in 2020 and the reward now sits at 6.25 bitcoins per successfully mined block. The next halving event is expected to happen around 2024 when the block reward will drop to just 3.125 bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty (or energy required) of mining these blocks does not decrease, so obtaining new bitcoins becomes harder due to the decreasing block reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;halving-events.png&#34; alt=&#34;image showing bitcoin halving events from 2009, 2013, 2016 and 2020 where the reward has havled starting at 50 BTC in 2009 to 6.25BTC in 2020&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reward of mining a block halves roughly every 4 years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These halvings help ensure a steady and predictable supply of new bitcoins, where the last bitcoin is expected to be mined around the year 2140.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to Bitcoin’s fixed supply along with these periodic halving events, the overall supply of new bitcoins decreases over time. Therefore a lot of people believe that the overall value of a bitcoin will increase due to this contrasted supply of new bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;durability&#34;&gt;Durability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durability is the ability to be able to withstand damage. Since bitcoins are not physical or digital objects, they can’t be destroyed and they don’t ‘wear down’ over time. Instead, the ownership of bitcoins is recorded in a public ledger called the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is a decentralised ledger with a copy of every single transaction that has taken place on the Bitcoin network. As long as you retain access to the bitcoin wallet (or more specifically the private keys), then you’ll always have access to your bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is often compared to gold when discussing durability as, like gold, it can’t be destroyed and it also can’t be physically ‘lost’ because it’s not a physical object like gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durability is a favourable quality in a currency, which is something Bitcoin provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;portability&#34;&gt;Portability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoins (and cryptocurrencies in general) are probably some of the most portable currencies we have today. Since they have no physical form, there’s no storage risk that comes with traditional currencies or gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Bitcoin is very portable, it’s relatively easy to send a large amount of money (or value) using the Bitcoin network without a middleman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were to attempt the same with say a million dollars you would either have to use a trusted third party like a bank which could take a lot longer at sending such a large amount of money or you could move this money in cash which would be incredibly costly and risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Bitcoin, on the other hand, you could ‘technically’ carry large amounts of bitcoins with you on your phone via a mobile wallet app or a USB stick and it wouldn’t ‘weigh’ you down the same way carrying a lot of coins or banknotes would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin nails portability thanks to the fact it’s fully digital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;divisibility&#34;&gt;Divisibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is extremely divisible, meaning you can send or receive tiny factions of a bitcoin very easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smallest unit of bitcoin is a ‘sat’ or satoshi, which is one hundred millionth of a bitcoin, or 0.00000001 bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bitcoin-pizza.png&#34; alt=&#34;image showing how bitcoin is divisible like a pizza&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoins are divisible, like a pizza and a single unit of a bitcoin is called a satoshi or &amp;lsquo;sat&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows bitcoins to be used for smaller transactions and even micro-transactions, such as tips, buying small things like coffees and so on. Most of these micro-transactions are made using a layer 2 solution called &lt;a href=&#34;https://lightning.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Lightning Network&lt;/a&gt; for faster and cheaper payments ⚡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fungibility&#34;&gt;Fungibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s final factor is fungible, meaning each and every bitcoin is identical. Each of the 21 million bitcoins is exactly the same. Fungibility is a desirable trait within any currency, including cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-bitcoin&#34;&gt;The Future of Bitcoin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now that we’ve explored the five factors that make Bitcoin different, let’s talk about what this means for Bitcoin going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popularity of Bitcoin is &lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; going to grow in the future. This doesn’t mean the price of Bitcoin itself is going to increase but rather we will likely see other companies and countries holding onto Bitcoin as a reserve of some kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are actually &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitcointreasuries.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;a few companies that now own and hold Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;; MicroStrategy, Tesla, Block (formally Square), Coinbase and even one of the ‘big four’ accounting organisations, KPMG!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;We have just completed an allocation of cryptoassets to our corporate treasury, our firm’s first of its kind investment in the asset class. This includes Bitcoin and Ethereum tokens, and carbon offsets to maintain a net-zero carbon transaction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/32hsKbnGuC&#34;&gt;https://t.co/32hsKbnGuC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; KPMG Canada (@KPMG_Canada) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KPMG_Canada/status/1490728332345987078?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 7, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Country-wise, only one country has made Bitcoin legal tender and that’s El Salvador but some folks are speculating that other countries might look to do the same over the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that begs the question…&lt;em&gt;should you buy Bitcoin?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer (bearing in mind this isn’t financial advice) is maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally think it depends on your individual circumstances…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you currently have little to no savings, I don’t think it’s a good idea to buy Bitcoin or any cryptocurrency and instead, you should focus on &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds&#34; &gt;building up an emergency fund&lt;/a&gt;, first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re someone that already has some savings/an emergency fund, then I think it makes more sense to &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/investing-101&#34; &gt;look into more traditional investments&lt;/a&gt; that are less risky and &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/interesting-isas&#34; &gt;explore tax-efficient savings accounts&lt;/a&gt; such as a Stocks and Shares ISA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already nailed the emergency fund, have a decent tax-efficient investment portfolio, have looked into &lt;a href=&#34;https://yougotthis.io/talks/buying-back-your-time&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;buying back your time&lt;/a&gt; (optional - but I highly recommend it), only then would I really say it would be worth looking into Bitcoin as an investment (once again, &lt;em&gt;not. financial. advice.&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at this point, I would say it’s probably best to only invest a small amount of your net worth/investment portfolio into Bitcoin. Bitcoin is still a relatively high risk as an asset class and extremely volatile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to also discuss the risks and concerns that come with Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies because Bitcoin is not a perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bitcoin-woes--risks&#34;&gt;Bitcoin Woes &amp;amp; Risks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volatility&#34;&gt;Volatility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about Bitcoin’s volatility first. As you might be aware, Bitcoin is highly volatile. Its price has fluctuated and more recently it’s lost 40% of its value since its last all-time high of $68,990 (around £51,780) in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A store of value (often what Bitcoin is often referred to) does not lose 40% of its value in less than a year. If you had bought Bitcoin at this all-time high, it would be devastating to see that you’ve lost 40% of your money in less than 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said…volatility does bring opportunities. Looking at the longer term, Bitcoin has slowly been increasing in value over the last 12 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bitcoin-price-history.png&#34; alt=&#34;Price chart for Bitcoin from 2009 to 2022. Source: CoinMarketCap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s price history (source - coinmarketcap.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing these types of gains or profit require being able to stomach large drops without panic selling and &lt;strong&gt;there isn’t a guarantee that Bitcoin will continue to increase in value&lt;/strong&gt; over the next decade and beyond as it has done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I would recommend focusing on savings/emergency funds first, and then traditional investments before looking into volatile cryptocurrencies. There’s just still a lot we don’t know when it comes to what will happen to cryptocurrencies in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leads me to my next point now…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fighting-fomo-fear-of-missing-out&#34;&gt;Fighting FOMO (Fear Of Missing Out)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve seen increase along with Bitcoin’s coverage in the media is the fear people have of feeling like they’re missing out. Which in turn causes them to panic buy Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies without really understanding it and then panic selling when they see massive price swings, losing their money in the process. The news coverage around Bitcoin’s all-time high price tends to have this effect the most, and the people who buy Bitcoin at this all-time high and usually the first to get stung when Bitcoin tumbles down in price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this issue can be summarised to just this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People get too emotional when it comes to any form of investments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to other things, we’re generally a lot more level headed and reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, you wouldn’t panic-buy a new car because everyone else is buying that exact same car? Or what about a new phone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’d probably want to do your research first, understand why these items are sought after and what they offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s another example. Over 2021, the &lt;em&gt;S&amp;amp;P 500 hit an all high 70 times throughout the year&lt;/em&gt;…how many times did you panic buy the S&amp;amp;P 500 during 2021?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most people reading this, they likely didn’t. Instead, they might have been fixated on what the media was saying about Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way I fight FOMO is by spending a lot of time researching and learning about what I want to invest in, all while ignoring the price of the asset while I do so. Depending on what I’m looking into, this process can take a few months and in the end, I might just decide not to invest in something because of something I found during my research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;replacing-traditional-currencies&#34;&gt;Replacing traditional currencies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some folks that support Bitcoin see it as something that might replace traditional fiat currencies like the dollar and the pound sterling in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest… I don’t think this will ever happen. No government would want to rely on a currency they are not in control of as their main currency. Fiat currencies in western nations also come with some level of protection on your money such as the FSCS protection scheme in the UK or the FDIC deposit insurance in the US. Bitcoin (and cryptocurrencies as a whole) do not come with such protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason I don’t think we’ll see cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin replace traditional currencies is that cryptocurrencies exclude people who are not technologically literate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandparents struggle using a smartphone, let alone mobile banking. I can’t see them ever getting crypto wallets and fully understanding the risks that come with it. I’m sure there are large groups of people who will likely struggle with cryptocurrencies due to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do however think Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies that offer ‘DeFi’ (Decentralised Finance) will offer an alternative to traditional markets, and there is likely a future for that, but it won’t be replacing any traditional markets any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;energy-concerns&#34;&gt;Energy concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest outcries you’ll see around Bitcoin is its high energy usage. I won’t go into too much detail here but I will say that Bitcoin does use a lot of energy and that energy usage is only going to increase. That being said, however, I think people get Bitcoin’s energy consumption confused with its carbon emission output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s estimated that Bitcoin currently uses around 0.55% of global electricity production (roughly the equivalent amount of energy a small country uses). The exact percentage varies but it is suggested that a large amount of the energy used by Bitcoin miners is generated using renewable energy sources, hydropower being one of the largest sources of energy for Bitcoin. Using a renewable energy source will mean that there is minimal carbon output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other cryptocurrencies have found more energy-efficient ways of running their networks, one of such is &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethereum.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; which plans to move away from Proof of Work (what Bitcoin uses) to Proof of Stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin will likely not change how it works. It is designed to sacrifice electrical energy to generate/mine new bitcoins. This is its ‘cost’ of creating new bitcoins. Removing this ‘cost’ would also remove/reduce the value of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s not really much I can add to this. I just wanted to point it out and make sure you were aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security plays a major part in cryptocurrencies. Specifically speaking, cryptography is critical in what makes or breaks a &lt;em&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/em&gt;. In fact, it’s even mentioned in the name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crypto&lt;/strong&gt;currency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people get really excited for the ‘&lt;em&gt;currency&lt;/em&gt;’ part of cryptocurrency but bear little attention to the ‘cryptography’ part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies are all about decentralisation and ‘Being your own bank’ and I have some thoughts around this.
Banks exist for a reason. They help the average person keep their money secure and outsource the need for having to think about how you keep your money safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m being brutely honest. I don’t think the majority of people understand the difficulty that comes with being your own bank. The security of your money is ultimately your responsibility. If you haven’t done a good job of securing your crypto wallet, that falls on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not your keys, not your wallet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a famous phrase you’ll hear among the crypto community. Holding your cryptocurrency on an exchange can be risky due to exchange hacks. It’s happened in the past and &lt;a href=&#34;https://crystalblockchain.com/articles/the-10-biggest-crypto-exchange-hacks-in-history/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;I doubt we’ve seen the last of exchange hacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, being your own bank is not easy. There are countless stories of people who have lost fortunes where they did own their own keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s one famous story of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-55658942&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;a man in the UK who accidentally threw away a hard drive that contained the private keys to around 7,500 bitcoins&lt;/a&gt; 😱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the fact that transactions made using cryptocurrencies are irreversible. If you happen to get scammed out of your cryptocurrency, there’s no way of getting it back. There are no chargebacks, no refunds, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scammers have plagued cryptocurrencies for a long time and if you fall for one, there’s not much that can be done. I would advise being aware of how these scams work and how you can protect yourself against such scams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went and found two great resources for getting a basic understanding of crypto security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is a thread by Bobby Ong (the co-founder &amp;amp; COO of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coingecko.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;CoinGecko&lt;/a&gt;) which covers some basics at a very high-level overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Crypto is a very dangerous and adversarial place. If you are not careful, you risk having your valuable cryptocurrencies stolen from you.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I&amp;#39;ve compiled a thread on some security best practices that you can follow to stay safe. Read on below 👇👇&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bobby Ong (@bobbyong) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bobbyong/status/1403881080902471680?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The second is &lt;a href=&#34;https://skerritt.blog/wallet-security/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; covering crypto wallet security, put together by a friend of mine! I’ve personally gone through this post and found it really easy to follow along, all while explaining complicated wallet security topics. There’s a great little summary at the end that summaries everything pretty well but I would highly recommend giving &lt;a href=&#34;https://skerritt.blog/wallet-security/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the full post a read&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will add however, it would be a good idea to consider getting a hardware wallet if you are storing large amounts of bitcoins - There are other great guides and resources around this topic online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m a fan of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ledger.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Ledger hardware wallet devices&lt;/a&gt;. If you wanted to test out an app-based software wallet in the meantime, the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluewallet.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;BlueWallet&lt;/a&gt; is a great simple first wallet with some advanced features built-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before I wrap up this post, I thought I’d share four resources you might want to look into if you wanted to read up more on Bitcoin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spiral.xyz/bitcoin.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Bitcoin Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; (The original Bitcoin whitepaper)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Bitcoin-Standard-Decentralized-Alternative-Central/dp/1119473861/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Bitcoin Standard&lt;/a&gt; (Highly recommended book)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://michaelmcguiness.com/essays/why-bitcoin-makes-sense&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Why Bitcoin Makes Sense&lt;/a&gt; (An essay on the pros of Bitcoin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ByO8ym-iF8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Bitcoin: The Future, or a World’s Greatest Scam&lt;/a&gt; (A great explanation from James Jani in video format)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are a lot more resources that I haven’t been able to list here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far, great! Thanks for sticking around 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my summary - Regardless of if you love or hate Bitcoin and what is it. Just like marmite, Bitcoin is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of countries with inadequate payments infrastructure and currency stability issues (such as hyperinflation) where Bitcoin could provide some stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of us are very fortunate and privileged to live in parts of the world where we have these types of infrastructure in place and don’t have to worry about currency stability issues that other places deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there will likely be a lot of interesting and exciting projects being developed around Bitcoin now that large companies (and even countries) have taken such an interest in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Price predictions - Easy, don’t bother. Almost everyone that has made a production of what price Bitcoin will be has been wrong. No one knows what will happen, but I’m certain Bitcoin will continue being the rollercoaster that it’s so commonly known for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, of course, so much more that I wanted to write about when it comes to Bitcoin, but I’m going to have to leave it like this, for now, to avoid this becoming a dissertation on Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all from me for today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m planning on writing up something on Ethereum next and will drop a thread on Twitter as well, so follow me on Twitter if you haven’t already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll see you next time 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying Back Your Time</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/buying-back-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/buying-back-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A talk I presented at &lt;a href=&#34;https://yougotthis.io/collections/cyberspace/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;You Got This in Cyberspace&lt;/a&gt; about knowing when to prioritise saving time vs saving money and a simple framework for how we can buy back our time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yougotthis.io/library/buying-back-time&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;View the full talk here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Text Message Scams with Kia</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/text-message-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/text-message-scams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Akash&lt;/a&gt; here 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I’ve got something a bit different - This week’s newsletter comes in audio format 🗣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently recorded a podcast episode with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ikeeyah_/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Kia&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PenniesToPound&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Pennies to Pounds Podcast&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having worked in the disputes team at a bank, I shared what I knew about text message scams, how they work and how you can avoid &amp;amp; report them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the full episode here 👇&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; class=&#34;spotify spotify-episode&#34; id=&#34;h-sc-spotify-0&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/4K59galnBg7gUiOGFpCmGG?theme=1&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: 232px; border: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldl-too-long-didnt-listen&#34;&gt;TL;DL (Too Long, Didn’t Listen)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No problem! Here’s a quick summary of what we discussed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scammers get your phone numbers from past data breaches and use them to send you scam text messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt; to see if your data has been breached before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scam text messages will contain links to webforms that ask for your personal details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/blog/behind-the-scenes-of-a-phishing-scam&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Learn how to spot phishing websites scams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scammers use the information from the webform to call you and convince you they are calling from your bank (or another organisation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scammers try to convince you to move your money to a ‘safe account’ or another account - This is just their own account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your bank will never ask you to move your money to another account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’ve been a victim of this scam, report it to your bank and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.actionfraud.police.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Action Fraud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report scam text messages by forwarding them to 7726&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign up for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://campaigns.which.co.uk/scam-alert-service/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;scam alerts newsletter&lt;/a&gt; from the Which? Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wheres-the-cryptocurrency-write-up-akash&#34;&gt;Where’s the cryptocurrency write up Akash?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cat-working.gif&#34; alt=&#34;cat working gif&#34;&gt;
^ A visual representation of me at the moment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on the cryptocurrencies mini-series, and I’ll be covering Bitcoin in the first of those newsletter issues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also working on putting together some threads on Twitter, so if you want to see those, consider &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;following me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; 👀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing 101</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/investing-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/investing-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while but good news, I’m back! 😎&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;im-back.gif&#34; alt=&#34;joey friends im back baby gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all - apologies for not sending this out sooner. I got caught up in some other stuff but to make up for it I’m (finally) covering investing and everything you need to know as a beginner (or as I like to call it - “What I wish someone told me before I started”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, disclaimer time - &lt;strong&gt;This isn’t financial advice and everything discussed here is for educational and entertainment purposes only. If you are looking for financial advice, you should find a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citizensadvice.org.uk/debt-and-money/getting-financial-advice/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;qualified and registered financial adviser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last 12-18 months in the stock market have been a series of ups and downs and new investors have been pouring in thanks to low-cost investment platforms like Freetrade and Trading 212 in the UK and Robinhood, Fidelity and TD Ameritrade in the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should also make this clear now before you read further - I’m not going to recommend a certain stock, share or anything for you to invest in. Instead, I want to share the benefits that come with investing, some easy ways to get started and some of the risks that are not talked about enough in my opinion (I’m looking at you, sponsored/promoted TikTok videos 👀).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-should-invest-&#34;&gt;Why you should invest 💭&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first and foremost - Investing lets you grow your money, and usually at a faster rate than what a savings account can offer you. Compound interest plays a large part in this and it can be hard to understand so let’s use a hypothetical example here to demonstrate this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say Tom has £10,000 and wants to grow this money over time. After a quick search online, Tom finds that the highest rate on an easy access savings account is 0.41%. If he left his money in this account for ten years and received the same interest rate over this time then Tom would have roughly £10,417.65 after these ten years - He made a total of £417.65 in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s see what would happen if Tom invested this money instead. According to Goldman Sachs “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.com/personal-finance/average-stock-market-return&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the average stock market return for 10 years is 9.2%, for the past 140 years.&lt;/a&gt;.” So we’ll be using 9.2% as our yearly interest rate here (note - historical data is not an indicator of future performance) and imagine this is the rate Tom gets on his money over the next 10 years. At the end of these ten years, Tom would roughly have £24,111.62! That’s a gain of £14,111.62 and more than double what he started with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dollar-duck.gif&#34; alt=&#34;donald duck dollar eyes gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNBC Make It recently also put together a great video that demonstrates how powerful compound interest is. It’s just over 6 minutes long but I think it’s worth a watch 👇&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I1_wcYe6LGg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, now the second key reason why you should consider investing, is because of &lt;strong&gt;inflation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve mentioned this briefly before in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/interesting-isas&#34; &gt;past newsletter issue&lt;/a&gt; and essentially what it means is that the value of your money will go down and you’ll find that the price of things like food, houses and wages will increase over time. Typically countries want the rate of inflation to be around 2% a year, to encourage spending, ensure stability and help plan for the future. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/monetary-policy/inflation&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Bank of England has a handy page&lt;/a&gt; that explains inflation and the downsides to both a higher rate of inflation and a lower rate of inflation. They also have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/monetary-policy/inflation/inflation-calculator&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;inflation calculator&lt;/a&gt; you can use to see how the value of money has changed over time due to inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, investing can you retain the value of your money by allowing it to grow at a faster rate than the rate of inflation (this will ultimately depend on what you invest in exactly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want another reason to invest? Those gains you make can be &lt;strong&gt;100% tax-free&lt;/strong&gt; - thanks to stocks and shares ISAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to the example with Tom before. If he invested his £10,000 using a stocks and shares ISA and ended up with £24,111.62, he could withdraw all of that from his ISA account (minus any fees) and not need to pay a penny in tax on that. If he had used a general investment account (GIA) then he’d need to pay some tax, specifically &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/capital-gains-tax&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s say he also earns £38,600 a year (the UK average salary). Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://taxscouts.com/calculator/capital-gains-tax/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;this capital gains tax calculator&lt;/a&gt; (a handy free tool) he&amp;rsquo;d need to pay roughly £181 if he withdrew all his money today. Now that isn’t a lot in this example but it can be a lot more the longer you leave your money invested to grow. Let’s say Tom invested his money for 25 years instead of 10 years then he’d have made a gain of £80,274.68 and would need to pay around &lt;strong&gt;£12,428 in capital gains tax&lt;/strong&gt; - a tax bill he could avoid entirely if he invested using a stocks and shares ISA instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this sounds great, right? Well, there are a few things you should know before you start investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-you-invest-&#34;&gt;Before you invest ✋&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;emergency-fund-&#34;&gt;Emergency fund 🚨&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this is talked about enough, but &lt;strong&gt;please have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds&#34; &gt;emergency fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; before you look into investing your money. The value of your investments can go down as well as up so it’s highly recommended that you do not invest money that you need in the short term. It’s a good idea to have a few months worth of expenses at hand in an emergency fund so you don’t need to dip into the money you’ve already invested and possibly get back less than what you started with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;risks-&#34;&gt;Risks ⚠️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While investing can boost the amount of money you have, it isn’t all smooth sailing. There are risks when it comes to investing your money - You’ve likely heard the phrase “the value of your investments can go down as well as up”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, for the majority of new investors, picking individual stocks to invest in isn’t recommended due to their volatility (how often the price moves up or down) and it might be better to consider Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) to help manage and diversify risk for new investors (more on this further down).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volatility is a major factor to consider when it comes to investing. Investing over longer periods of time can mitigate some of this volatility. Investing for short term gains can be a lot harder due to constant volatility and the chance of ending up with less money than you originally invested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;regulations--fscs-protection-&#34;&gt;Regulations &amp;amp; FSCS Protection 🛡&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking into investment platforms and brokers to invest with, make sure that they are authorised to provide financial services by the Financial Conduct Authority and are registered on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://register.fca.org.uk/s/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Financial Services Register&lt;/a&gt;. The page on the register about a company should have the companies official details (address, phone number, email address and website).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://register.fca.org.uk/s/firm?id=001b000003rtZg9AAE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Freetrade’s page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;freetrade-fca-register.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Freetrade&amp;rsquo;s entry in the FCA register&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the ‘Registered company number’ on the register and find this at the bottom of Freetrade’s website as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;freetrade-website-footer.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the footer section of Freetrade&amp;rsquo;s website with a red arrow pointing at FCA register number&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure the investment firm you open an account with is covered by the Financial Services Compensation Scheme so if the firm fails, you’ll be able to recover up to £85,000 of your money from the firm. &lt;em&gt;The scheme doesn’t protect your money in the event that your investments go down in  value&lt;/em&gt; due to volatility in the market but rather only if the company you use for investments fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-should-you-invest-with-&#34;&gt;Who should you invest with 🤔&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;batman-thinking.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Batman thinking gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; going to recommend a certain platform or broker that you should invest with, but I’m just going to explain the difference between two possible approaches you can take - What works best for you will depend on your individual circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-it-for-me-platforms--brokers-&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do it for me&amp;rdquo; platforms &amp;amp; brokers 🤖&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment firms that offer a ‘do it for me’ approach make it extremely simple for an individual to invest. The idea is very simple - You give them your money and they do all the investing work for you. It’s basically automated investing. There are groups of people that might have a limited amount of free time, so this would be great as it gives them a chance to invest without spending large amounts of their time trying to learn how to invest. It’s also great for people who might be inexperienced with investing but still want to get started without knowing too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So why might someone not want to invest in this way?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some downsides to this way of investing. If you’re someone that specifically wants to choose what you invest in, then this method likely won’t be for you. Additionally, having to manage the investments for thousands (if not millions) of people is not easy. Investment firms will charge a fee for these services. The fees are relatively small but over time they can compound to thousands of pounds as your portfolio grows in size - Just something to bear in mind 🐻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the more hands-on approach to investing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-it-yourself-platforms--brokers-&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do it yourself&amp;rdquo; platforms &amp;amp; brokers 🏋️‍♂️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, if you open your account with a do it yourself investment firm you’ll need to pick what to invest in by yourself. You get full control over your investment portfolio but you’ll need to know what you’re doing to, spend time doing your own research and understand what stocks are worth investing in. Fees can be cheaper than the ‘do it for me’ investment firms but this will largely depend on the fees set by the investment firm you decided to open an account with (some firms charge a fee per trade 😱).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this certainly can be a cheaper way of investing, you won’t have a team of experienced people working on making sure your investment portfolio grows over time as you would with a ‘do it for me’ investment firm. If you’re planning on holding investments like ETFs in the long term (like I am) then this approach can be a lot cheaper - A ‘do it for me’ firm might charge around 0.75% for managing your money for you, but some ETFs can have even lower charges (e.g. some ETFs have an ongoing charge of 0.07% or even less - That’s just over ten times less than the ‘do it for me’ ongoing charge I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exchange-traded-funds-etfs-&#34;&gt;Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) 🥧&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to know exactly what to invest in and that’s why I think ETFs are great for the majority of everyday retail investors. One of the world’s best investors Warren Buffet says the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most investors, both institutional and individual, will find that the best way to own common stocks is through an index fund that charges minimal fees. Those following this path are sure to beat the net results (after fees and expenses) delivered by the great majority of investment professionals” - Warren Buffet, source - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/robertberger/2020/11/24/how-to-invest-money-based-on-advice-from-warren-buffett/?sh=7a7cc0a4526c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s this ETF thing now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, so ETFs are ‘funds that track the performance of something’. That ‘something’ can be anything from an index, a sector, a group of assets (e.g. green enegry companies) or some other type of asset. An ETF can be made up of many assets and by buying an ETF you’re essentially buying a small piece of all the assets it is made up of. Some of the biggest ETF providers include &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vanguardinvestor.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Vanguard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ishares.com/uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;iShares&lt;/a&gt; by Blackrock and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.invesco.co.uk/uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Invesco&lt;/a&gt;, but there are many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a simpler way of thinking about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have five different bags of sweets. Now you want each type of sweet but you don’t want to buy all five bags - maybe it&amp;rsquo;s too expensive or you don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy that many sweets. We can imagine these bags of sweets as shares of different companies. You then come across a variety bag of sweets, that contains a mix of sweets from each of those five bags. Buying this one bag of sweets gets you a bit of each of the sweets from those five bags without needing to buy all five bags of sweets. We can think of the variety bag of sweets as an ETF - an easier and cheaper way of buying all the different types of sweets in smaller amounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, when most people talk about ETFs, they are usually talking about passive ETFs that have lower fees and are not managed by an asset manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actively managed funds/ETFs on the other hand usually charge higher fees than passive ETF funds to hire a manager that picks stocks they believe will achieve a higher return however this isn’t guaranteed and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebalance.com/why-index-funds-beat-actively-managed-funds-2466411&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;historically passive funds have a strong history of beating actively managed funds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to being low cost, ETFs have another great advantage to them - automatic risk diversification. If one company within an ETF loses a lot of value or even goes bust, it’s a lot less risky for you as your money is spread out across several other companies/assets within the ETF instead of being all in that one company that went bust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about different types of ETFs &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrade.io/learn/what-is-an-etf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Freetrade does a great job explaining them further).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-&#34;&gt;Summary 📝&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite a lengthy read, so let me summarise the above into some bullet points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investing is a great way of growing your money and beating the rate of inflation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stocks are Shares ISAs help you pay less or no Capital Gains Tax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have an emergency fund before investing any money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick your approach to investing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ride out market volatility with low-cost passive ETFs and invest with the long term in mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investing can be easy&lt;/strong&gt;, and believe it or not, if you’re of working age and are currently employed, you likely already have an investment account without realising it - your workplace pension!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend looking into investing or just learning more about it, because the best time to invest was yesterday, the second-best time is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-coming-next-&#34;&gt;What’s coming next ➡️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lockdown is coming to an end soon and with that, a lot of people’s schedules are changing, including mine. I’m hoping to spend a bit more of my free time catching up with friends, spending more time outside and working on some other things as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be scaling back to sending out one newsletter per month to reflect this change. I might not stick to that, and send out a few emails a month from time to time, like for the cryptocurrency mini-series I’m working on, but I though I&amp;rsquo;d give you all a heads up ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway that&amp;rsquo;s all for day, I’ll see you next time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;doctor-who-see-ya.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Doctor Who see ya gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting ISAs</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/interesting-isas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/interesting-isas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, around this time of year, you’ll start seeing more reminders, adverts, emails and more all saying the same or similar thing - “&lt;em&gt;Remember to use your ISA limit before the end of the tax year&lt;/em&gt;”, and honestly, I don’t think it’s a big issue for the majority of people with ISAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISAs can be confusing so here’s my personal take on ISA’s (Individual Savings Accounts) and which ones I think are worth looking into for yourself (based on your goals).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - Spend some time looking into different types of ISAs and how they can help you reach your financial goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going any further if you’re not familiar with ISAs here’s a great guide to understanding them better ➡️ &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/blog/2018/11/14/isas-explained&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The big guide to ISAs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-isas-are-great-&#34;&gt;Why ISAs are great 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think ISA&amp;rsquo;s are one of the best savings/investment accounts on the planet. From what I’ve found, no other savings/investment account is as generous as a UK ISA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the US, IRA and Roth IRA and the closest thing to an ISA. Any money that goes into either one of these accounts (you can only have one or the other) can’t be accessed until after the age of 59 and a half. With a UK ISA, you have the freedom to withdraw your money at any time you like. With an IRA you also have to pay income tax on any withdrawals you make as well as some penalties if you make a withdrawal before the age of 59 and a half and this is really where the UK ISA shines in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a UK ISA, you can make a withdrawal at any time (for the cash ISA and stocks and shares ISA) within a penalty - Perfect for if you’re planning on using the money for a large purchase (e.g. a home) or if you’re looking to retire before the state age of retirement. Other countries offer similar accounts to what the US offers and from what I could find online which only highlights the uniqueness of UK ISAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something to bear in mind is the limit on how much you can invest into ISAs each tax year and currently, that’s £20,000. This is why I think ‘remembering to use your ISA limit’ isn’t beneficial to most people unless you can put away the full £20,000 each tax year (£1667 each month) into your ISA. If you are in a position where you’re able to put away £20,000 then it might be worth considering using up your allowance as it’s not possible to rollover any unused allowance from a previous tax year into the current or future tax years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This limit can be split across several different types of ISA’s and it’s important to remember that &lt;strong&gt;you can only contribute money to one type of ISA in each tax year&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. you can contribute £5,000 into a cash ISA and £15,000 into a stocks and shares ISA in one tax year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how many ISAs are there and do you need all of them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-isas-and-my-thoughts-around-them-&#34;&gt;Types of ISAs (and my thoughts around them) ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are five ISA types currently - cash ISAs, stocks and shares ISAs, the lifetime ISAs, innovative finance ISAs and Junior ISAs.The three most common ones for people over the age of 18 are the cash ISA, the stocks and shares ISA and the lifetime ISA, so let’s cover those three first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind, the following comments on each type are just my thoughts and opinions of each of these ISAs and this isn’t financial advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cash-isas-&#34;&gt;Cash ISAs 💷&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash ISA’s are the simplest and most risk-free type of ISA - You can think of it like a normal savings account. The difference is that with a saving account, you’ll have to pay tax on any interest you earn that is over your personal saving allowance (£1,000 in interest for basic rate taxpayers, £500 for higher-rate taxpayers). With a cash ISA, you pay no tax on any interest regardless of your personal saving allowance. In my personal opinion, this isn’t as great as it sounds. Let me explain why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this newsletter issue, the highest interest rate for a fixed term ISA was around 1% and can only be obtained if you lock up your money in this ISA for several years. The rates for flexible or easy access cash ISAs are a lot lower and range around 0.4% to 0.5%. If we consider these rates then you would need to have saved between £100,000 to £250,000 to earn enough interest to go over your personal saving allowance (assuming you are a basic rate taxpayer) with these ISAs and reaching these amounts will take years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, you’ll also need to consider the price of inflation - Any interest rate lower than the rate of inflation means that in the long term, your money is losing value rather than gaining any. You can find the current rate of inflation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/inflationandpriceindices&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Office for National Statistics website&lt;/a&gt; and as of January 2021, it stands at 0.9%. A majority of the time, you’ll find that almost all (especially for instant/easy access cash ISAs) that the rates offered by cash ISA providers are below this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this makes the cash ISA a terrible way of growing your money in the long term and it makes more sense to use a normal saving account for short term savings or an emergency fund instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lifetime-isas-&#34;&gt;Lifetime ISAs 🏡&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lifetime ISA’s are slightly different to other ISAs - The maximum amount of money you can put in a lifetime ISA is capped at £4,000 per tax year but the benefit is that for every £4 you put into the account, you get a £1 bonus from the government up to a maximum of £1,000 per tax year. This ISA was introduced in 2017 to replace the Help to Buy ISA and can be opened by anyone between the ages of 18 to 39. It has two purposes - to help savers save enough to buy their first home or it can be withdrawn as cash for your retirement (at retirement age that is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you open a Lifetime ISA at the age of 18 and made the maximum contribution until you were 50 then you would receive a maximum bonus of £33,000. A lot of home buyer will likely want to purchase a home before the age of 50, so the bonus received will depend on how much is saved in this ISA as well as how many years you decide to save for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great ISA if you are planning on buying a home soon (or for retirement in the long term) and it comes in two flavours - cash lifetime ISAs and stocks and shares lifetime ISAs. Additionally, you can contribute to this ISA and another cash or lifetime ISA regardless of the type of lifetime ISA you pick. Just know that with stocks and shares lifetime ISAs there are usually some additional fees such as platform charges and charges per trade (if you decided to pick your own stocks and shares for your lifetime ISA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning on buying a home in the short term and you plan on saving more than £4,000 a year, you could use a lifetime ISA in combination with another type of ISA to save up more tax-free (but as mentioned, I personally wouldn’t choose a cash ISA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to buy a home in the more long term (e.g. five-plus years), then you could save using your lifetime ISA (either cash or stocks or shares) with a stocks and shares ISA to grow your money over time. Just be aware that stocks and shares ISAs come with the risk of the value of your investments going down as well as up so it’s generally advised not to use them if you are not comfortable taking risks or if you need access to the money in the short term. This brings me to the next type of ISA&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stocks-and-shares-isas-&#34;&gt;Stocks and Shares ISAs 📈&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name implies, you’ll be able to use the money you put into a stocks and shares ISA to buy….stocks and shares. There are two variations of this ISA - the automated option (or “do it for me”) or the “do it yourself” option. The automated option is great if you don’t want to spend a lot of time research funds and stocks that you want to invest in. It’s all taken care of for you, but it comes at a cost&amp;hellip;literally. From what I’ve seen, the fees on accounts that take care of investing your money for you generally are a bit higher than do it yourself options. That however doesn’t make “do it yourself” options better - They can have their own fees as well depending on who provides them. Some platforms have low fees (e.g. Freetrade and Trading212) and other platforms charge per trade you make (on average around £9.99 per trade) so that’s something else you’ll also need to take into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my favourite type of ISA because it’s possible to beat the rate of inflation while also growing your savings further. Regardless of which type of stocks and shares ISA you get, you’ll want to avoid high fees as much as possible. Fees like this will eat into any gains you make and in the long term it can stack up quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ISA is better suited for long term savings/investing due to the risk that comes with it as stocks and shares can go up or down in value in a short period of time. I’ve gone with a “do it yourself” stocks and shares ISA myself and plan on investing in low-cost ETFs and a small handful of growth stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And before someone asks, no &lt;strong&gt;you cannot buy cryptocurrencies within an ISA&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;innovative-finance-isas-&#34;&gt;Innovative Finance ISAs 💥&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest&amp;hellip;this is the ISA I know the &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; about. This ISA is mainly offered by Peer to Peer (P2P) lender, and what I can tell you is that if you use an innovative finance ISA, your money will be used for peer to peer loans, making you a private lender rather than an investor like you would be with a stocks and shares ISA. The risks are also quite different; borrowers can default on their loans and your money isn’t even protected by the Financial Services Compensation Scheme (FSCS) like it is with the other types of ISAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, no FSCS protection makes this a major no for me and there’s not much else I have to say about this ISA 😬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;junior-isas-&#34;&gt;Junior ISAs 👶&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re over the age of 18 then unfortunately you won’t be able to open a Junior ISA. However, if you are a parent and wanted to put some money aside for your child/children for later on in life, then a Junior ISA could be great. Compound interest will work in their favour and depending on how soon you open an account for them, they can stand to benefit from up to 18 years of compounding interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior ISAs come in two flavours - cash ISAs and stocks and shares ISAs. Generally speaking, the interest rates on a cash Junior ISA are higher than what you can find with a normal savings account or a cash ISA. The stocks and shares ISAs variant can also be great as you’ll have up to 18 years to allow that money to compound over time and investing can outperform cash when it comes to long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the downsides then? Well, the first is you can’t withdraw any money put into a junior ISA, only your child can and they can only do that once they turn 18. Additionally, the amount of money you can put into a junior ISA is capped at £9,000 per tax year at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s all my thoughts around these types of ISAs summarised as best as I can. I could probably still go on quite a bit about all this but I hope this gives you a general idea of why ISAs could be beneficial for you if you don’t already have one. If you wanted to go further down the rabbit hole of the world of ISA’s then there are many resources you can check out but my first stop and recommendation would be to check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Money Saving Expert&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See ya next time! 🦀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mr-krabs.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Mr Krabs money shower gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming outages</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/overcoming-outages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/overcoming-outages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you do if your main bank had an outage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is, what if you held all your money in one bank account and that bank had an outage&amp;hellip;how would you access your money? Answer - &lt;strong&gt;You can’t&lt;/strong&gt;….at least not until their systems are back online. So what do you do to prevent an outage from interrupting your life (and your access to money)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - Spread your money across a few bank accounts (and card networks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multiple-bank-accounts&#34;&gt;Multiple bank accounts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s rare for a bank to have an outage but if and when they do and you need access to your money, you’ll want a backup account for such a situation. The majority of current accounts are free and a few banks let you open an online current account within less than an hour. I think it’s a great idea to open up a second bank account and hold a few days worth of spending money in it or at least enough to cover any recurring bills you might have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing you might want to do instead would be to split your &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds/&#34; &gt;emergency fund&lt;/a&gt;  across two or three bank accounts, to ensure you always have access to some money regardless of if your main bank has an outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of outages that have happened in the past:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TSB, 2018 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/jun/06/timeline-of-trouble-how-the-tsb-it-meltdown-unfolded&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;outage for multiple weeks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natwest &amp;amp; RBS, 2019 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.finextra.com/newsarticle/34871/natwest-and-rbs-down-infuriating-black-friday-online-shoppers&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;outage on Black Friday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revolut, 2019 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20220928011612/https://blog.revolut.com/revolut-app-issues-30th-october-what-happened-and-what-we-did-to-fix-it/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;outage for two and a half hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monzo, 2019 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/blog/2019/09/08/why-monzo-wasnt-working-on-july-29th&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;outage for two hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how long an outage is for, not having access to your money is a horrible feeling. While it’s impossible to know when a bank could have an outage, by being prepared with a backup account, you can be reassured that you’ll have access to some of your money until the outage with your main bank has been resolved.
There’s just one other thing to consider as well when looking into secondary accounts, because…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;card-networks-have-outages-as-well-&#34;&gt;Card networks have outages as well 🙃&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;spongebob-fire.gif&#34; alt=&#34;spongebob fire gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup. This is something else you’ll also need to consider. If you look at any bank card, you’ll likely see either a Mastercard, Visa or an American Express logo somewhere on it. These are all card networks that work independently of each other and several banks will be using one or the other for their debit and credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 Visa has an outage that caused &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.finextra.com/newsarticle/32277/visa-says-52m-payments-failed-during-10-hour-outage&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;5.2 million payments to fail during a 10-hour outage&lt;/a&gt; and 2.4 million of those payments were in the UK 😬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day, Mastercard and American Express cardholders were able to continue using their cards without any major issues. So having a bank card on another card network to your main bank account might just help you out in a tricky situation like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again - This type of outage isn&amp;rsquo;t even that common, but making sure you are ready for it just means you have one less thing to worry about in the future in the chance that an outage does occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the important thing to remember is not to panic when an outage happens and fall back on your other bank account (hopefully also on another card network).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, we’re likely going to progress into an increasingly more digital financial world. In 2019 alone, more than half of the payments made in the UK were made via a card and in 2020 this trend only accelerated due to the pandemic and increased contactless spending limit in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a last resort, you could also just have a little bit of cash on hand in such situations (as long as you’re not tempted to spend it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having access to your main account (or any money) can be annoying. At least you can sleep easy at night knowing you didn&amp;rsquo;t spend over &lt;a href=&#34;https://foundation.app/@NyanCat/foundation/219&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;half a million dollars on a Nyan cat gif&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Till next time!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;nyan-cat.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Nyan cat gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone plans</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/phone-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/phone-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our phones have become an essential tool in our everyday lives. Everything is just a tap away, whether it’s online banking, shopping or ordering a takeaway. For what is an essential tool, you’re likely paying more for your phone or sim plan than you need to. I thought I’d share some of the things I’ve learnt to help keep costs low 📉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - Check if changing your phone contract/sim plan can save you money at least once a year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-success-story-&#34;&gt;A success story! 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going further, I wanted to share a success story from a reader that made some changes to her finances after reading my last newsletter issue! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulienuh/status/1358325455447879684&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Pauline shared how she spent a weekend reading more about personal finance&lt;/a&gt; and as a result, has now negotiated her phone bill down and cut out some subscriptions she no longer needs. She’s told me that due to these changes she now &lt;strong&gt;saves an extra £538 a year!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pauline-saving-money-tweet.png&#34; alt=&#34;tweet from @paulienuh about how she saves money&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done Pauline 👏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contracts-are-spendy-&#34;&gt;Contracts are spendy 💸&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we don’t pay as much as folks in America (who pay around an average of $101.50 a month!) we’re still spending a considerable amount on phones. In 2018, Money Saving Expert found that &lt;em&gt;four million mobile phone users are paying up to £38 extra for their phones/contracts&lt;/em&gt; without realising it and it’s partly to do it with how fixed contact deals work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of a contact, most network providers will roll you onto a 30-day plan where everything stays the same including the price. This isn’t great because fixed-term contracts include the price of the phone in the plan. At the end of the term, you’d have paid the phone off but by not changing your plan you could still end up paying for a phone you’ve already paid off 😱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, a handful of network providers have committed to moving customers to lower-priced plans at the end of a contract term automatically to save them some money however, some network providers (&lt;em&gt;cough cough&lt;/em&gt;, Three, EE and Vodafone 🙄) have declined to offer this, leaving it up to customers to remember switching to a cheaper deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the tips I’ve previously discussed on how to &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/busting-broadband-bills&#34; &gt;haggle with your broadband provider&lt;/a&gt; with network providers as well if you want to stay with the same one at the end of your contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I buy my phone outright while sticking to sim only plans and hang onto my phone for three to four years before replacing it. There are also a few other things I did over the years to help keep costs low&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;switch-to-a-virtual-network-operatorssim-only-plan-&#34;&gt;Switch to a virtual network operators/sim only plan 🔄&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual network operators are companies that lease network usage from the main network providers and usually have sim plans that are a lot cheaper than those offered by the main network providers. You’ve likely heard of a few of them already such as GiffGaff, Lyca Mobile and Virgin Mobile just to name a few and there are some newer (and interesting) ones popping up like Voxi and Zevvle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.voxi.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Voxi&lt;/a&gt; has been a favourite of mine in the past due to it’s unique ‘Endless Social Media’ perk that comes with all its sim plans. Another great benefit of virtual networks is that a lot of the sim only plans offer flexibility. They are mostly 30-day sim plans which give you the freedom to switch to a better deal later on if you wanted. Most virtual network providers tend to also offer the standard fixed-price phone contracts (again, usually for less) if you aren’t ready to switch over to a sim only deal yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun Fact&lt;/strong&gt; - Virtual networks are getting more popular in the US and one virtual network provider ‘Mint Mobile’ is partly owned by Ryan Reynolds&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mint-mobile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of unlimited $30 offer from mint mobile&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cashback-sim-only-plans-&#34;&gt;Cashback sim only plans 🤑&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve found this one only recently but I’m surprised by how simple and cost-effective it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some websites offer cashback on their sim only contract plans so you can end up with an amazing deal that can cost less than a tenner a month. My current sim plan is from a website called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fonehouse.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Fonehouse&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a sim only contract with unlimited minutes and texts with 60GBs of data for just &lt;strong&gt;£7.50 a month!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ok, but what’s the catch?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catch is that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;you have to claim this cashback manually&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in certain months after getting your sim plan and a majority of people will likely forget to do this. Fonehouse has a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fonehouse.co.uk/blog/how-does-redemption-cashback-work/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; explaining how their cashback redemption works, and if you do it correctly the money is paid directly into your bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sceptical at first, but I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten two out of my three cashback payments so far. In the meantime, while you wait for your cashback you do pay the full price of the contact each month (mine is £20 a month) so remember to submit those cashback claims. If you set up some reminders for yourself ahead of time you should have no issues with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fonehouse offers a few different ‘extras’ on sim only plans. You can select ‘Auto Cashback’ plans if you don’t want to deal with submitting your monthly bills to receive your cashback but the amount of cashback on these plans are lower than the standard cashback plans. Additionally, all the sim plans come with free delivery so the offer of &amp;lsquo;free delivery&amp;rsquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t really an &amp;rsquo;extra&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple diagram that summaries what you want to look for in addition to the monthly price👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fonehouse.png&#34; alt=&#34;fonehouse meme&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of dedicated cashback websites, I’ve only seen one other website that offers cashback on sim only contracts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.affordablemobiles.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Affordable Mobiles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘Guaranteed Cashback’ is paid to you automatically and the manual cashback offers are labelled as ‘Cashback by Redemption’. I haven’t used their website myself so I’m not too familiar with their cashback process but according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.affordablemobiles.co.uk/help/cashback&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;their help article&lt;/a&gt;, the process looks to be similar to claim your cashback. While they don’t have as many cashback offers they have some surprisingly cheap sim only plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;affordable-mobiles.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of a sim plan from the afforable mobiles website&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👆This offer ends up being just &lt;em&gt;£3 a month&lt;/em&gt; when the cashback is taken into consideration!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-readingwatching-&#34;&gt;Further Reading/Watching 📽&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/news/2018/09/millions-overpay-for-mobiles/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Millions pay up to £38/mth for a phone they already own&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.which.co.uk/news/article/three-ee-and-vodafone-will-continue-to-overcharge-customers-for-mobile-contracts-heres-how-to-save-aB4uN7k9sA0l&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Three, EE and Vodafone will continue to overcharge customers for mobile contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6CU3g0X4yF0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Why Do Cell Phone Bills Cost So Much In The U.S.?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this information above I’ve managed to cut my phone bill down from £15 a month to just £7.50 (after cashback). I&amp;rsquo;m also working on a way to drop that down further to £0 a month, but that&amp;rsquo;s a story for another time. Why not see how much you can save as well using these tips and tricks 😃&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swimming in Subscriptions</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/swimming-in-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/swimming-in-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey folks 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about subscriptions because &lt;strong&gt;everything is becoming a subscription&lt;/strong&gt;, from streaming services to software and even physical goods. Subscriptions are becoming a normal way of life and while a lot of them can provide a lot of value, they run up to hundreds (and sometimes thousands) of pounds a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - Have a look through all your subscriptions and cut out what you don’t use or need&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-we-subscribing-to-more-subscriptions&#34;&gt;What are we subscribing to more subscriptions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barclays Payments claims that we’re becoming a ‘Subscription Society’ and that’s not far from the truth. &lt;a href=&#34;https://home.barclaycard/press-releases/2020/8/Lockdown-fuels-Subscription-Society/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Research found&lt;/a&gt; that on average we’re shelling out about &lt;em&gt;£46 a month (£552 a year)&lt;/em&gt; on subscription services and in April 2020, spending on digital subscription services increased by over 50% year on year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockdowns accelerated the growth of subscription services - A lot of us took up a streaming service to get through the long periods at home and with shops closed, 22% of UK retailers launched a subscription service at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also been another type of subscription that has been creeping up on us, and that is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-subscriptions&#34;&gt;Software subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The era of one-time payment software is starting to crumble, and in its place are subscription software services. Traditional computer software, apps on our phones and even video games (to some degree) are all turning into monthly subscription services. Subscriptions are great for companies that build software. It creates a recurring and predictable source of revenue that can be reinvested to build better products and services, however it might leave you with less money and a sense of obligation to use these services to &lt;em&gt;get your money’s worth&lt;/em&gt; from them since you’ve already paid for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can make sense to pay a subscription for great software but as a rule of thumb, I try to stick to only those that I’m able to get a lot of value out of or ones that help save me time such as my &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;password manager&lt;/a&gt;, my music streaming service, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotify.com/uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and most recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/i/akash56&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; for tracking and syncing various notes and highlight across several sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most software subscriptions can be considered as ‘&lt;em&gt;optional&lt;/em&gt;’ subscriptions. They are ones that you could probably cut out for a few months and be fine without. As an example, most fitness apps will have some type of subscription tied to &lt;em&gt;premium&lt;/em&gt; content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See if you can try and find one of these types of subscriptions that you have and try canceling it or downgrading to the free plan instead to start saving some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-subscriptions&#34;&gt;Service subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re starting to see more and more subscriptions that offer a service for a fixed monthly cost including but not limited to razor blades, recipe boxes, video games, newspapers and content streaming. As with software subscriptions, the same rule applies - Only keep the ones that prove to provide you value but also try not to be subscribed to different versions of the same type of service - You probably don’t need a subscription to two or more streaming services for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classic-subscriptions&#34;&gt;Classic subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed monthly costs can be thought of being subscriptions as well - You pay monthly for a service or product. So energy, internet, phone and rent/mortgage bills are what I would consider ‘classic subscriptions’. Instead of cutting these ones out, there are usually ways you could cut down on some of them which can end up saving you money. It could be as simple as checking if you are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.which.co.uk/news/2020/08/third-of-mobile-network-customers-still-being-hit-by-overpayments-rip-off/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;overpaying for your phone plan&lt;/a&gt;, switching to a cheaper energy supplier, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/busting-broadband-bills&#34; &gt;haggling with your broadband provider for a cheaper deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keeping-a-track-on-subscriptions&#34;&gt;Keeping a track on subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can easily fall for the trap of needing every subscription service thrown at us and also losing track of what we are subscribed to. I found it useful to track each of these subscriptions and how much they are costing me each month/year. I use an app on Android that’s simply called &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.simolation.subscriptionmanager&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Subscriptions&lt;/a&gt; to do this. For iOS users, you can get something similar from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bobby-track-subscriptions/id1059152023&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Bobby&lt;/a&gt; app. Thankfully neither of these apps have their own subscription service but there are some in-app purchases if you want to get some extra functionality from either app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;subscriptions-app-screenshot.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Subscriptions Android app showing a few listed subscriptions&#34;&gt;
^ &lt;em&gt;An example of what my &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.simolation.subscriptionmanager&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;subscription tracking app&lt;/a&gt; looks like&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20180930115117/https://blog.unicornhunt.io/your-life-is-about-to-be-dominated-by-subscriptions-580c2ef410f9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Why everything is turning into a subscription&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2019/08/12/whats-behind-the-rise-of-the-subscription-model/?sh=692fe14b35c3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;What’s Behind The Rise Of The Subscription Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscriptions are not going to go away anytime soon and inevitably if you don’t have one now, you’ll likely get one (or more) in the future. Subscriptions aren’t the end of the world but it’s just something to remain aware about and stay on top of, because while &lt;strong&gt;we might be swimming in subscriptions today, tomorrow we could end up drowning in them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four finance books for 2021</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/four-finance-books-for-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/four-finance-books-for-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey folks 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy belated New Year! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 2020 behind us and the start of a what we can only hope will be a better year to look forward too, I thought now would be the perfect time to share four personal finance books that I&amp;rsquo;ve read that helped me get better with my finances and that might help you as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - Here are four personal finance books that I think are useful 👇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-richest-man-in-babylon&#34;&gt;The Richest Man in Babylon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book was originally written by George S. Clason and published in 1926. Almost 100 years later it still stands the test of time! Out of all the personal finance books that I have read, I think this one that I found the most interesting, because despite the different time period, a lot of the things covered in the story of this book about the ancient and forgotten city are still relevant and the personal finance concepts explained can still be applied to how we treat our finances today. The best part is that you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Richest-Man-Babylon-George-Clason-ebook/dp/B07H7HN6DN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;grab a digital copy of this for less than a pound from the Amazon Kindle store!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Product/George-S-Clason/The-Richest-Man-In-Babylon/1042026&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;You can also buy it from Hive instead here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-little-book-of-common-sense-investing&#34;&gt;The Little Book of Common Sense Investing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written by John C Bogle, the founder of the Vanguard Group and the creator of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/i/indexfund.asp&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;index funds&lt;/a&gt;. In this book, John explains the benefits of low-cost index funds as opposed to actively managed funds that underperform the market, the fees that can eat into any profits you make and why you should consider investing for the long term instead of looking for short term gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall this book is great! It&amp;rsquo;s easy to read compared to some of the other books around investing. Some of the technical details might not be clear at first but with some further research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could say it that investing in this book is&amp;hellip;.&lt;em&gt;common sense&lt;/em&gt; 😏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Little-Book-Common-Sense-Investing/dp/1119404509&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Buy it from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Product/John-C-Bogle/The-Little-Book-of-Common-Sense-Investing--The-Only-Way-t/20756527&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Buy it from Hive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-investing-guide-for-beginners&#34;&gt;The Investing Guide For Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of personal finance books are written from the perspective of someone living in the US or are targeted towards a US audience. This ebook is written by Curtis Davies (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/financepapi_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;@financepapi_ to those that follow him on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;) and is targeted towards a more UK centric audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It covers ISA&amp;rsquo;s in-depth, ETF&amp;rsquo;s, index funds, investing terminology, fees and a lot more, in less than 100 pages and is sprinkled with a dash of humour throughout it. I was personally surprised at how useful and insightful this ebook is and even wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_/status/1300380591901282305&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;small thread of my thoughts&lt;/a&gt; about it shortly after it was released (Yes I speed read it in a day to write that). I think it is a great modern day resource for those that want to get started with investing but aren&amp;rsquo;t too sure where to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being priced a bit more compared to the other books suggested here, it does provide a lot of information that is quite easy to digest and is a bit more tailored to a UK audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/a/151712883&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;You can buy a copy using my affiliate link here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-intelligent-investor&#34;&gt;The Intelligent Investor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book that I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading because it was recommended by many others that have taken an interest in personal finance and investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, written by Benjamin Graham in 1949, this book covers the concepts around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/v/valueinvesting.asp&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;value investing&lt;/a&gt;, not getting emotional with your investments and my favourite topic, &lt;em&gt;dollar-cost averaging&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more on the technical side and you&amp;rsquo;ll likely need to re-read it a few times to fully understand it. The other three books are a lot more beginner-friendly in my opinion so I&amp;rsquo;d treat this as an &lt;em&gt;additional&lt;/em&gt; book to go over if you have already read over the three above or any other personal finance books first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Intelligent-Investor-Definitive-Investing-Practical/dp/0060555661&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Buy it from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Product/Benjamin-Graham/The-Intelligent-Investor/62779&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Buy it from Hive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m planning on reading more books this year so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting this list to be different in a year&amp;rsquo;s time and I might consider making an updated version in the future to reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These four books are a great starting point but reading these alone will not change the future of your financial life. As well as reading you need to take action as well. It could be as small as saving a little bit more each month or cutting back on a subscription you no longer use. These small actions will help you make progress to where you want to be financially and you don&amp;rsquo;t need any of these books to make those changes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on picking up one or more of these books, then I hope you learn a lot from them like I did and take action to make progress to improve your personal financial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adiós for now amigos 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binge Buying</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/binge-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/binge-buying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry this issue is a few days late - I just wanted to spend a bit more time to polish the last few touches on this email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - Consider only buying things you need or things that significantly improves your life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With less than a month left of the year, I thought now would be the perfect time to write about minimalism and its polar opposite, excessive consumption. There&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot of confusion about what minimalism is as well as how excessive consumption can take over your life without you realising it. In this issue, I wanted to explore these two dynamics and how you can navigate between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve put a &amp;rsquo;too long, didn&amp;rsquo;t read&amp;rsquo; (TL;DR) line above for those that might not have time to read this whole newsletter issue (and that&amp;rsquo;s ok!). I might consider having one of these in each issue of this newsletter going forward&lt;/em&gt; 😃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-see-minimalism-through-consumption&#34;&gt;How I see minimalism (through consumption)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a lot of people, minimalism is about &amp;rsquo;things&amp;rsquo; you own and owning a few things as possible. To some degree, this is right, however, from a financial perspective I see it more as trying to control and limit how much I buy (consume) and only buying things that are of high quality for a fair price and that are things that I need and use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important thing to point out is that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to throw out everything or most of your things to adopt a more minimalist lifestyle. You can make changes to your life over time instead of all at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minimalism to me is buying only the things I need or things that will significantly improve my life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;favouring-quality-over-quantity&#34;&gt;Favouring quality over quantity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going further, I should mention that this doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply to absolutely &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;. This can be a bit subjective and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to evaluate what items in your life are worth paying a bit more for. I ended up discovering this when buying a pair of jeans&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to buy a pair of jeans for £30, but after six months of use, they constantly needed to be replaced or repaired due to wear and tear. This cycle and frustration with the lack of quality led me to do a bit more research and I ended up buying a pricer £90 pair of jeans instead about two years ago. While I paid three times more for these jeans, they lasted well and I still wear them frequently to this day. Paying a bit more upfront here ended up being more cost-effective in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word of warning - &lt;em&gt;A higher price does not always mean an item is of a higher quality.&lt;/em&gt; You might have to experiment a bit more with what you buy or do some further research so please bear that in mind when making such purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-you-need-it&#34;&gt;Do you need it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is a bit of a trick question because often we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to self justify to ourselves why we need the newest phone, tablet, pair of shoes or some other trinket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you are not allowed to treat yourself or enjoy nice things, but rather what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say is that you can do this but in &lt;em&gt;moderation&lt;/em&gt; instead of excessively spending without really thinking about if these things bring value to your life. Whether you need to buy something, is going to come down to your own personal circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can help you is understanding why you are buying something.
Here are some questions I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself when considering buying something:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this something I can live without?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any cheaper alternatives?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I already own something like this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this replacing something I already have?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will it last a long time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I buying this on an impulse?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall - The only person that can answer all of these questions honestly&amp;hellip;is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;binge-buying-things-we-dont-need&#34;&gt;Binge buying (things we don&amp;rsquo;t need)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binge buying. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been guilty of it at one point or another. Another term for it is &amp;lsquo;Retail therapy&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s the act of buying yourself things to improve your mood. When we buy things, we usually get a burst of &lt;a href=&#34;https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dopamine&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;dopamine&lt;/a&gt; which makes us &amp;lsquo;feel happy&amp;rsquo;. This alone isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad thing but it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20161123-shopping-a-sale-gives-you-the-same-feeling-as-getting-high&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;usually fades after a period of time&lt;/a&gt;, which can create a loop of buying more things to maintain this feeling of happiness. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.experian.com/blogs/news/about/retail-therapy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Experian has a great article&lt;/a&gt; describing this in more detail as well as things you can do to try and curb the need to spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done it myself before (more than once) and it&amp;rsquo;s totally normal. I have however learnt to limit buying things that leave both me and my bank balance happy - It&amp;rsquo;s all about finding that perfect balance. This all ties back to what I discussed above about minimalism. While I&amp;rsquo;m not committing to a fully minimalist lifestyle, by thinking more about what I spend my money on I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to cut down overspending and learnt to value quality over quantity when it comes to possessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-video-that-inspired-this-issue&#34;&gt;The video that inspired this issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t lie, this issue is heavily inspired by a recent video I came across on YouTube. I found it to be really engaging, easy to understand and well put together. It made my stop and think about my relationship with things and money. Parts two and three feel the most relevant to this newsletter issue, but I think the whole thing is worth watching (and also subscribing James&amp;rsquo; channel) 👇&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9RJpIqD8MGg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s enough from me today! Thanks for sticking through this issue. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be taking a break from the newsletter over the holiday season to rest and recharge, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be back with a new issue of the newsletter around the start of the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I hope you all have a wonderful holiday season and a happy New Year ✨&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Connoisseur</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/credit-card-connoisseur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/credit-card-connoisseur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everybody 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you&amp;rsquo;ve all been well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this week&amp;rsquo;s issue of Akash &amp;amp; Money, I wanted to share how I&amp;rsquo;ve used credit cards to my advantage to earn points and why I spend my money via a credit card and not a debit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before going any further I would just like to remind you all that this isn&amp;rsquo;t financial advice and that all information, opinions and suggestions are for educational and entertainment purposes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should add that this issue won&amp;rsquo;t cover the basics around credit cards and rather I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on the &amp;ldquo;reward credit cards&amp;rdquo; rather than standard credit cards, 0% credit cards or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/reclaim/section75-protect-your-purchases/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;section 75&lt;/a&gt;. If you happen to be someone that carries a credit card balance month to month, then earning points should be a low priority and instead, you should focus on paying down this debt or any other short term debt you may have - **The points earned do not outweigh the interest rate of any debit so please bear that in mind. **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, but what’s the point of points? (see what I did there 😏)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credit-card-rewardspoints&#34;&gt;Credit card rewards/points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, let&amp;rsquo;s kick-off!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you make a transaction using either cash or a card, most cards do not offer you anything at all for making those transactions. Reward credit cards offer a reward for using them instead of your other payment options where you usually earn a point per £1 you spend on the card. If you look back at how much you spent month to month, you can roughly work out the number of points you could be earning on your purchases and these points can stack up over several years and be used on things like flights, cash back or credit statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to collect just over 70,000 points across American Express Membership Reward Points, British Airways Avios and Virgin Points. Most credit cards also offer a signup bonus with a few thousand points to start with either if you hit a spending goal or by making a single transaction on the card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-responsible-with-credit-cards&#34;&gt;Being responsible with credit cards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now earning rewards is great but you&amp;rsquo;ll tend to find that credit cards like this tend to have a higher interest rate than other credit cards. If you end up carrying a balance because you&amp;rsquo;re unable to pay off a credit card in full each month, then the points end up costing you more than what they are worth. It can be really easy to justify a frivolous purchase because &amp;ldquo;I can pay it off after I get paid&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s this type of mentality can make it a lot harder to budget and can lead to overspending money you might not have. This is why I use a feature from my main bank and carefully plan my spending to overcome this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-bonuses&#34;&gt;Welcome bonuses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before signing up for any of these credit cards, the first thing I did was see if I had any planned large purchases coming up. Reward credit cards often tend to have a &lt;strong&gt;welcome bonus&lt;/strong&gt; but the catch is that you only get the bonus once you spend a certain amount on the credit card. For one of my cards, the bonus was an extra 5,000 points when you spent £2,000 within the first three months. Around the time of getting my first rewards card, I was looking to purchase a new phone for my mum and book a return trip flight for my family. Together these purchases were over £2,000 and they were all going to be made in the next three months so I signed up for a credit card and managed to hit the spending goal for the bonus without spending more than I was already planning to spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first mistakes you can make when signing up for these credit cards is &lt;em&gt;thinking you need to hit the spending goal for the bonus&lt;/em&gt;, which again, leads to overspending. By strategically planning your spending you can avoid this entirely and just spend the amount you were already planning on spending. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have any large purchases coming up just yet then it might be a good idea to hold off from signing up for a rewards credit card if you want the welcome bonus (hint - you should want the bonus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can sometimes get a slightly bigger signup bonus by using a referral link to sign up for one of these credit cards. The extra bonus points vary per card but for example, the referral bonus for the Amex rewards credit card is 6,000 Membership Reward points (1,000 extra) and 22,000 Membership Reward points for the Amex gold card (2,000 extra). The referrer also gets some extra points as an incentive. I’d recommend asking any of your friends and family first to see if they have a referral link and if not you can always email myself for one as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;amex-rewards-card-welcome-bonus.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the American Express website showing the welcome bonus offer on The American Express Rewards Credit Card&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;^ An example of a referral welcome bonus on the American Express Rewards Credit Card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paying-off-credit-cards&#34;&gt;Paying off credit cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I do is treat my credit cards like debit cards. If I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough in my current account to pay for something then I can&amp;rsquo;t buy it via a credit card. The other thing I do is pay my credit cards off in full each month. I do this by setting up a direct debit for each card linked to my bank account. Monzo has a unique feature where you can pay your direct debits from pots which I use to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this feature I set up a pot for each credit card and link the direct debit to them. Now, when I do pay for things on my credit card I&amp;rsquo;ve got into a habit of moving the exact amount of money from my main account over to my credit card pot. Then, when the direct debit is due, the money is withdrawn from the pot and used to pay the direct debit automatically. Using this, I can stick to my budget and also reap the benefits from credit cards without overspending since the money needs to be in my account first to be moved over to the pot to pay off the credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;monzo-amex-pot.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of a Monzo pot name &amp;lsquo;Amex - Rewards Card&amp;rsquo; with an American Express direct debit linked to it&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;^ The pot I set up to pay my American Express Rewards Credit Card direct debit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fees&#34;&gt;Fees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first fee you want to avoid is the interest rate. You can avoid this by simply paying your balance in full every money. The method I use above is my preferred way and I highly recommend setting up a direct debit to have the balance paid off in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are often other fees as well for making transactions using reward cards abroad and for making withdrawals at ATMs. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest avoiding using credit cards for these types of transactions and instead, use a fee-free debit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-credit-cards&#34;&gt;My credit cards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of credit cards. At the moment I currently have three point-earning cards that I use for my day to day spending. Between these three cards, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to rack up over 70,000 points across them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;american-express-rewards-credit-card&#34;&gt;American Express Rewards Credit Card&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first, and the main credit card that I use is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanexpress.com/uk/credit-cards/rewards-credit-card/?linknav=uk-amex-cardshop-allcards-learn-RewardsCreditCard-carousel&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;American Express Rewards Credit Card&lt;/a&gt;. It has no annual fee and earns 1 Membership Rewards point per £1 spent on the card. These points are the most versatile out of the three types I collect. There are a lot of different ways you can spend them such as a credit statement on your credit card bill, gift vouchers (e.g. Amazon) or (and my favourite) airline air miles across a number of airlines. These points never expire as long as you keep a Membership Rewards point earning card open. To date, I hold just over 40,000 Membership Rewards points on my card and I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on using them just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;british-airways-american-express-credit-card&#34;&gt;British Airways American Express Credit Card&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Amex rewards credit card was available in the UK I actually used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanexpress.com/uk/credit-cards/ba-credit-card/?linknav=uk-amex-cardshop-allcards-learn-BritAirwaysAmexCC-carousel&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;British Airways Credit Card&lt;/a&gt; for most of my day to day spending. This card also has no annual fee and at the time of when I got my BA (British Airways) Amex card I just used to collect Avios air miles (1 point per £1 spent) in the hopes of using these air miles for business class flights. Head for Points is a great website that explains &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.headforpoints.com/the-beginners-guide-to-collecting-avios-points/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;how to earn Avios&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.headforpoints.com/2020/04/06/how-do-you-book-flights-using-avios-points/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;what you can spend them on&lt;/a&gt;.
There is one issue with collecting just Avios points and it&amp;rsquo;s that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britishairways.com/en-gb/executive-club/collecting-avios/avios-expiry-rules&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;they expire if you do not collect, spend, purchase or share at least one Avios point&lt;/a&gt; every 36 months. This isn&amp;rsquo;t too terrible, however, it can be easy to forget and you could end up losing all your Avios air miles.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I have one monthly card subscription paid from my BA credit card and this keeps my 25,000 plus Avios air miles valid indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;virgin-atlantic-credit-card&#34;&gt;Virgin Atlantic Credit Card&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final main credit card is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uk.virginmoney.com/cards/products/vaa-cards/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Virgin Atlantic Credit Card&lt;/a&gt;. This Mastercard credit card has no annual fee but earns a slightly lower rate of 0.75 points per £1 spent and 1.5 points for every £1 spent via Virgin Atlantic or Virgin Holidays. I treat this card more as a backup card for places that don&amp;rsquo;t accept American Express. This is one of my most recent cards and a card I do not use that often, so I only have just over 5,000 points on this card - 5,000 of those points coming from the signup bonus before that was removed earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-would-do-differently&#34;&gt;What I would do differently&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could start all over again the main change I would make is signing up for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanexpress.com/uk/credit-cards/gold-credit-card/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Amex Preferred Rewards Gold Credit Card&lt;/a&gt; first via a referral link to get a welcome bonus of 22,000 points instead of the Amex rewards credit card. You pay no annual fee for the first year you have an Amex gold card, so towards the end of that year, if I didn&amp;rsquo;t find myself utilising the other benefits that came with the gold card I would downgrade to the rewards card to retain all the points I earned and to keep earning more points while still paying no annual fee. &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.co.uk/guide/beginners-guide-tpg-uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Points Guy&amp;amp;rsquo;s Beginner Guide&lt;/a&gt; is also a great resource for learning how to maximise the most out of reward credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for this issue, I hope it was informative and insightful around how reward credit cards work! If you would like a referral for one of American Express cards I mentioned and you aren&amp;rsquo;t able to use anyone else&amp;rsquo;s referral first, you can email me and I can share mine with you 😊&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crunching Credit Scores</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/crunching-credit-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/crunching-credit-scores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there lockdown crew 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I went over some of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/social-scammers&#34; &gt;types of scams you might come across on social media&lt;/a&gt;. Given we&amp;rsquo;re in a second lockdown now, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance you might start seeing some of these scams re-emerging so if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already I would recommend giving the last issue a look over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this issue I’m covering credit scores and why you should think about yours. I want to avoid sharing what you &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ikeeyah_/status/1179145024602329088&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;might have already come across online&lt;/a&gt; but rather expand share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt from my own experience trying to understanding my credit score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go 🏃‍♂️💨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credit-scores-101&#34;&gt;Credit Scores 101&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do a quick 101 on what credit scores are. Credit scores are used by lenders as a way to measure your &amp;ldquo;reliability&amp;rdquo; when they decide if you can qualify for certain lending products (e.g. credit cards, loans, mortgages, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenders want to avoid lending money to people that they think are unlikely to pay it back. If your credit score is on the low side, they could flat out reject your application or they might consider you for their products but with a higher interest rate, which means you end up needing to pay back more than those with a higher credit score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all credit scores are the same, and lenders do not use the same one. You have three different credit scores in the UK due to the three credit agencies in the UK; &lt;strong&gt;Experian&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Equifax&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;TransUnion&lt;/strong&gt;. These three agencies provide your credit report to lenders to help them make accurate decisions regarding their lending products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-three-agencies&#34;&gt;The three agencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of misunderstanding around how credit scores work and several &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.experian.com/blogs/ask-experian/credit-education/faqs/credit-myths/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;rumours and myths&lt;/a&gt; as well which have scared people into not checking their credit score. Checking your credit score does not affect your credit score and you can check it as often as you want (it might not update daily). I use the following apps and websites to help me keep a track of my mine👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experian--money-saving-experts-credit-club&#34;&gt;Experian / Money Saving Expert’s Credit Club&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;credit-club.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Money Saving Expert Credit Club landing page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check my &lt;em&gt;Experian credit score&lt;/em&gt;, I used to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.experian.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Experian&amp;#39;s credit score checking service&lt;/a&gt; but I found that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to view my whole credit report without paying for something called &amp;ldquo;CreditExpert&amp;rdquo; which costs a staggering £15 a month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up finding a tool by MoneySavingExpert called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/creditclub/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Credit Club&lt;/a&gt;, which shows you the same Experian credit score and full credit report for free and have been using this since without any issues ✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;creditkarma&#34;&gt;CreditKarma&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;creditkarma.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Credit Karma landing page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next app/website is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.creditkarma.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Credit Karma&lt;/a&gt; and this one allows you to view your &lt;em&gt;TransUnion credit score&lt;/em&gt; and file. Unlike Experian however, this score only goes up to 710 instead of 999. This isn&amp;rsquo;t something to worry about as this is just how TransUnion calculates your score. Out of the three apps I use, this one is my favourite, the app and web UI has a clean and simple look to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clearscore&#34;&gt;ClearScore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;clearscore.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the ClearScore landing page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clearscore.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;ClearScore&lt;/a&gt; is the one out of the three that allows you to view your Equifax credit score and file. It also has a handy feature called &amp;ldquo;Protect&amp;rdquo; which checks if your linked email account has been involved in any data breaches and warns you if any of your passwords have been leaked online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-did&#34;&gt;What I did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly when I first checked my credit scores across these services I found that it was pretty high. There were three main things I did from when I was younger that positively impacted my credit score without even realising it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paying-my-phone-bill-&#34;&gt;Paying my phone bill ☎️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the age of 19, I started paying for my phone bill via direct debit. This shows lenders that I was able to pay a bill on time and with no issues for the length of time that I had this bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;registering-on-the-electoral-roll-&#34;&gt;Registering on the electoral roll 🗳&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also registered to vote a few years before this. Something you might not know is that you can register to vote at the age of 16! If you haven&amp;rsquo;t you can do this on the government website via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/register-to-vote&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; which takes roughly 5 minutes and provides another positive impact on your credit score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-a-credit-card-&#34;&gt;Getting a credit card 💳&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, this option isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone - Some people might just want to avoid credit cards but if you end up taking one up, using it a bit, and pay it off in full on time every month then again this shows lenders that you are reliable. I got offered a student credit card with a £500 limit along with my student bank account and honestly, for most of the first year, I forgot I even had it. I started using it a bit more after that, putting roughly £50 a month of my spending on it and paying that off in full each month. By doing this I also maintained a &lt;em&gt;low utilisation&lt;/em&gt; of my credit limit by keeping my credit usage at around 30% or less of my limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three of these things when combined gave lenders a good understanding of how I managed my money and brought up my score without really doing much. These led to being accepted for other lending products like my American Express credit cards and an overdraft (the latter being something I don&amp;rsquo;t use and only really have for an emergency), which further builds a clearer picture of my credit history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a good credit score and credit history can help you secure a better interest rate (remember where we talked about measuring reliability) for large loans such as a mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking your score also helps you spot anything fishy on your account, such as a credit card you never took out - Using these same services you can usually report something like this and they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to investigate things like that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for this email and I hope that this is a great introduction to credit scores for you. In the next issue, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/credit-card-connoisseur&#34; &gt;credit cards&lt;/a&gt; and how I use mine to get a ton of points, air miles and cashback without paying anything extra fees or costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Scammers</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/social-scammers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/social-scammers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long time no see! First of all apologies for this reaching you a week later than it should have, I was a bit busy settling into &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_/status/1316723658455478273&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;my new role at work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this issue, I wanted to cover social media and how scammers have been using it to their advantage. Social media is great, it has allowed us to connect to friends and family globally through a trying year. Unfortunately, it has also made it a lot easier for fraudsters to find people to deceive and steal their money via these same platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a topic strictly related to personal finance, but I’ve always believed that knowing how to protect your money from these common scams is something that should be more widely known. By working for a bank, I’ve come across a number of these scams before. I wanted to break down the three most common ones you’ll find on social media at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advance-fee-scams-&#34;&gt;Advance Fee Scams 💸&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember at the start of the lockdown how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/02/nintendo-switch-animal-crossing-and-coronavirus-led-to-record-sales.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;everyone wanted to get their hands on a Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people were told to stay at home and finding something to do to pass the time led to many exploring what video games had to offer. Combined with a supply issue for new consoles such as the Nintendo Switch, scammers used this shortage of consoles to their advantage. There was a flood of people looking to sell their games consoles, bikes, shoes and more through several different ways using the lockdown. eBay, Depop, Shpock, Instagram, Snapchat, Facebook Marketplace are just a handful of the platforms used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scammers will list items up for sale among legitimate items regardless of if they have the item or not - It is easy to find someone else’s photos and use those instead as a part of their scams! All they need to do is wait for someone to contact them about the item they have for ‘sale’ after posting the listing. Once someone falls for the bait, the social engineering begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with the term social engineering I’ll provide a brief explanation. &lt;strong&gt;Social engineering&lt;/strong&gt; is the act of manipulating someone into doing a task or action, such as sending a bank transfer or sharing their login details for certain websites. This is a crucial part of the scam as most of relying heavily on the use of social engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scam, a buyer will usually be convinced to send a bank transfer and have the goods (e.g. a Nintendo Switch sent to them). What will happen is as soon as the scammer has received the money, they’ll simply move this to another account or withdraw it as cash at an ATM and then block the person they were speaking to. Worse, they might string the buyer along for a few days buying they more time to move the money while telling the buyer that they have &amp;lsquo;sent the item&amp;rsquo;, before later again blocking them. Ok, but where’s the social engineering element?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the payment is made, this will be the point where the scammer will try everything to convince someone to send them a payment. This can be in the form of showing additional photos of the item, telling them they live too far away from the buyer to meet face to face to sell the item or just telling the buyer to &amp;rsquo;trust them because they are not a scammer&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;
It is also the point where if asked if the payment can be sent via a more secure method (such as the PayPal Goods &amp;amp; Services option) that the scammer will either say to the buyer to either send the payment via the ‘Friends and Family’ option, via bank transfer or simply say that they do not have a PayPal account. This again is preying on the fact that a lot of people do not understand the difference between the two options on PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s Goods &amp;amp; Service option will offer a form of buyer/fraud protection and they charge a small amount of commission on the final sale value to provide this service. The friends and family option offers no such protection and thus does not charge a fee. If you end up buying an item via this way and it later turns out to be a scam, PayPal is unlikely to help you with this as they&amp;rsquo;ll state that the friends and family option is not meant to be used for buying goods and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to avoid getting scammed over items like this over the internet is to either see the item first face to face with the seller before making the payment or using a platform (such as eBay, Depop, Shpock, etc.) that offers the ability to make your purchase via their payment platform (or via your bank details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a seller on these platforms tell you that their account is ‘not working’ or is ‘unable to receive’ payments (commonly seen on Depop for example) it’s best to see this as a red flag to not continue with the purchase as they will try to redirect you to make the payment via a method that will give you no buyer/fraud protection and ultimately a higher chance that you will be scammed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;depop_chat_reddit.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot from a Depop chat which is highly likely to be a scam via that I found on Reddit&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from a Depop chat which is highly likely to be a scam via that I found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Depop/comments/dxa4rh/is_this_a_scam_if_i_pay_through_paypal_can_i/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t look to buy via such methods and always look to make a payment using my card details via a payment portal/checkout provided by the app/platform for better protection. There’s a higher risk of purchases made via bank transfers (or PayPal friends and family) being a scam and if you end up sending money via these ways, it can be very difficult to recover any of the money sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-scams-&#34;&gt;Investment Scams 📈&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scam is also a common one but comes in many forms. The concept largely remains the same - Send the scammer some money and they promise to send you more money back. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.actionfraud.police.uk/alert/164-instagram-users-report-losing-over-350000-to-investment-scams&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Action Fraud found that 164 Instagram users reported that they had collectively lost over £350,000&lt;/a&gt; and that’s just from reported cases. The real amount lost is a lot higher as most of these types of scams go unreported due to victims not really being sure who to report these to or simply out of embarrassment of being scammed in the first place. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.finextra.com/newsarticle/36432/barclays-reports-66-spike-in-scams&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Barclays has seen a 66% spike in scams&lt;/a&gt; in the first six months of the year with July seeing a 49% increase in the volume of investment scams. So how does this scam work and who is it that falls for them?
Let’s first discuss how the scam works. Similar to Advance Fee scams, scammers will create social media profiles and then will post many photos and attempt to gain as many followers as possible to ‘build their brand’. The photos posted will be a glimpse of their &amp;rsquo;luxury lifestyle&amp;rsquo; - big houses, swimming pools, fancy cars, travel snaps, parties and often stacks of money to entice people into wanting a similar lifestyle. They’ll also usually hide their face or could go a step further and impersonate someone else by using photos from someone else&amp;rsquo;s public accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;scammer_instagram_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of an instagram profile that is likely to be a scammer&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An example of what a scammers Instagram account might look like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’ll either then reach out to their victims or simply wait for their victims to contact them. When questioned how it all works, most of these scammers have a script filled with confusing jargon (talking without really saying anything as I like to call it) to make what they do sound more legitimate while claiming to be an expert, having screenshots of trading as proof (again, can be faked easily) and having ‘good reviews’. These reviews they provide are fairly easy to fake - It just requires making a handful of additional social media accounts to send direct messages back and forth with and then taking screenshots of those conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common words used in these types of messages include &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/b1dpmdtw19x3n0/Mark-Yusko-Has-an-Imposter-We-Talked-to-Them&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;forex, bitcoin, trading&lt;/a&gt;, signals, and options along with the promise of a high or guaranteed return. Something to note about the last point is that investments of any type never guarantee any form of returns. The world&amp;rsquo;s best investor, Warren Buffet is unable to guarantee a return from their investments, it&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely someone you found on Instagram can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These lengthy descriptions are used to confuse people who might not be as aware as to how investing, trading or cryptocurrency work. The main part that will lure them in is the high return of what they could make. Once the scammer has said enough to convince the victim, they’ll ask them to make a bank transfer for as much as they can convince the victim to sent and as fast as they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first payment is sent, they have the victim fully hooked and will demand further payments for activation fees, management fees, transfer fees and so on until the victim realises that they fell for a scam. At this point, the victim will feel stuck and see the only way to get their money back is to send these further payments to &amp;lsquo;unlock&amp;rsquo; their profits or to start a refund. After these payments are made, the scammer simply blocks the victim and transfers the money away as fast as they can to avoid getting caught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question now is who even falls for a scam like this? I like to visualise it as two groups of people; the first are those that are lured in by greed and the second are those that desperately need money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former is self-explanatory. They are individuals hoping to make money quickly and do not understand or check how these returns are made or simply do not care. There is likely an element of naivety at play as well so they are just willing to trust someone they meet over social media. These individuals tend to learn the hard way that not everyone on the internet is their friend and wants to help them after unfortunately being scammed themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter group make up the majority of those that end up getting scammed. Those in need of money tend to be on a lower income or are vulnerable in one form or another that which in turn can lead to financial vulnerability. The appeal of these scams to this group of people is the possibility that the opportunity presented to them could be legitimate and how the additional money can be of a great benefit with them. Hope is what the fraudsters will prey on with these types of victims and they won’t hesitate to take advantage of it. Scammers will frequently apply pressure to both groups of people to force their hand into sending them payments without really understanding the consequences of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment scams are normally advertised via social media platforms such as Instagram, Twitter, Snapchat, Facebook. TikTok and so on. Real investment firms and traders do not offer their services via direct messages on such platforms or on shady-looking websites. It&amp;rsquo;s best to always check if the firm or individual that you are speaking to is registered under the Financial Conduct Authority’s (FCA) register to check if the firm is regulated by the FCA and if there are any signs of such opportunities being a scam and if the investment opportunity is too good to be true then it often is. At the time of writing this post, I found that there is someone that recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://metro.co.uk/2020/10/26/gareth-gates-reveals-he-lost-250000-after-getting-burnt-with-investment-13483603/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;lost £250,000 via one of these forex scammers&lt;/a&gt; 😬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I like to think of it is if someone could turn, for example, £500 into £5000, why do they need you? Surely if it was legitimate would this person not just put their own £500 get £5000 back out and then just repeat the process but this time with 10 lots of £500 to make £50,000 and so on? Why would they need your money or show you how to achieve this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;money-mules-&#34;&gt;Money Mules 🐴&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third type of scam you’ll come across are the ones where scammers promise a sum of money in exchange for using your bank account to send/receive some money. This is called money laundering - Fraudsters will want to move their money through these accounts to then send on to other accounts to conceal the money they obtained. This money can be associated with some severe crimes such as illegal fraud, human trafficking, corruption, kidnapping and even extortion. By helping they mule this money, you&amp;rsquo;re committing a crime.
Again, a similar approach is taken on social media to recruit people for this scam - Get in touch with victims, convince them to hand over their bank details, and then use them to launder the money or by telling the victim to withdraw the money as cash and then handing it over to the scammer while keeping a cut of the money themself. A key indication of people involved in money muling and looking to recruit others is the language they will use, often stating that the opportunity is a limited time offer and how the payout is fast, instant or risk-free. A money mule can lose access to financial services (such as bank accounts) and a convinced money mule could also serve up to 14 years in prison. This type of scam/fraud is targeted heavily at young people and university students. Surprising &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v_NkfOQANDo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the number of 14-18 year-olds involved in this type of fraud has risen by 73%&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=money&amp;#43;mules&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;A quick search on youtube&lt;/a&gt; shows a number of videos warning others not to fall a victim to this scam and how it can affect the rest of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fintrail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fintrail cover image&#34;&gt;
I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fintrail.co.uk/news/2020/4/16/how-social-media-is-used-to-further-financial-crime-part-2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Fintrail’s blog posts&lt;/a&gt; on how social media is used to further financial crime on money mules an interesting read - I recommend giving this a look over when you have the time to learn more about money mules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same principles from spotting the other two scams also apply here. It’s also important to never share your banking details such as your card details, online banking login information or card PIN with anyone or to make transactions or transfers when instructed by someone else in such situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for this issue. I hope I’ve highlighted the importance of what to be aware of in these common scams and how you can avoid them. Scams of these nature can affect anyone including people you know. If you want to protect yourself and others from scams I recommend reading up more on the matter (you won&amp;rsquo;t have trouble finding articles online) and if you want to help your friends and family as well, consider forwarding this email to them as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll see you all again, two weeks from now with another issue of Akash &amp;amp; Money 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busting broadband bills</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/busting-broadband-bills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/busting-broadband-bills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi again 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today in the third issue of Akash &amp;amp; Money, I’m covering something almost all of us will be familiar with - Internet Service Providers (ISPs), broadband and your monthly bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s often easy to avoid price hikes and get discounts with little effort and any money you save can end up being put towards other things (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds&#34; &gt;an emergency fund&lt;/a&gt;. I also wanted to share my own experience where just last Friday, I managed to talk my own bill down to save an extra 25% in just a 20-minute phone call. I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover how I did this and how you can also haggle your own broadband bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently in the UK when you sign up with a broadband provider you&amp;rsquo;ll often come across two plans - pay monthly and a fixed-term contract. The monthly plan allows you to easily switch between providers when and where it suits you however this isn&amp;rsquo;t something a provider will want, so the monthly price for such plans are a lot higher than those on a fixed-term contract. Providers love long term customers and are willing to reduce the monthly cost if they can keep you for longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most contracts will have a minimum term of 12 months, however, longer contracts of 18 months and 24 months are also available for packaged bundles that include broadband, a landline line rental and a TV package as well. These contracts will often have a lower monthly fee for the duration of the contract and after the contract ends the price usually increases quite a bit. Knowing when your contract is coming to an end allows you to avoid getting stung with a higher bill by simply switching or asking your provider for a discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also all comes down to the most important fact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The cost of acquiring a new customer is often more than that the cost of keeping an existing customer happy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invespcro found that it can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.invespcro.com/blog/customer-acquisition-retention/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;cost up to five times more to attract a new customer than to keep a new one&lt;/a&gt;. In other words - It&amp;rsquo;s easier and cheaper for a service provider to give existing customers discounts and promotions to keep they a customer for longer, which is great news for you and gives you a chance to haggle with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;haggling-with-your-provider&#34;&gt;Haggling with your provider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haggling might not be something you&amp;rsquo;re used to doing and can seem really un-British - After all, you&amp;rsquo;d never try to negotiate your weekly shopping bill at a supermarket. With internet providers, haggling can often net you a massive discount and it’s always worth giving it a try. The worst thing that can happen is that they say no. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great advice online already that explains how you can do this. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/broadband-and-tv/haggle-your-broadband-existing-customer-tips/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Money Saving Expert offers 14 tricks&lt;/a&gt; you can use to slash your monthly bill and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hjb7CZWHOF8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Which UK has a YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; that shows some handy tips to consider before calling your provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research--other-things-to-know&#34;&gt;Research &amp;amp; other things to know&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you contact your internet provider you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to have a battle plan ready. Here are some things you should arm yourself with before picking up the phone (or opening a web chat):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a note of what you are already getting from your current provider and see if you can find the same or similar package with another provider. Have these quotes at hand when contacting your existing provider as this will be your main bargaining chip. You can check directly with internet service providers and also using price comparison websites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comparethemarket.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Compare the Market&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uswitch.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;uSwitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gocompare.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Go Compare&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moneysupermarket.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;MoneySuperMarket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out when your existing contract ends - You&amp;rsquo;re going to have the most bargaining power towards the end of your contract as you have the freedom to switch away if you are not happy with your current provider. An internet provider will not want you to leave so they are more willing to offer discounts and price reductions at the end of your contact term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note down how long you have been with your provider. You can often leverage your long term loyalty for a further discount. Phrases like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a customer for X years and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that as a loyal customer you would be able to give me a better deal&amp;rdquo; can go a long way in swaying the provider to give you a discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take the first deal that you are given. When you first contact your provider, the first team you will likely speak to is the customer service team. They are usually able to offer you an discount however this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the best deal they can provide you. The cancellations/retention team can offer you some of the better deals but you can&amp;rsquo;t really speak to them directly. Instead, you need to use a special phrase - &amp;ldquo;Thanks for the offer but I would still like to cancel my current service as I have found a better deal elsewhere&amp;rdquo;. This often leads to being put on hold and being transferred to another team. They&amp;rsquo;ll be aware of why you have been transferred to them and this will usually be the last chance they have to retain you as a customer and thus are more willing to offer a higher discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a track of any service issues or outages you have experienced - You can mention how you were disappointed with these issues and how these effected you - Again, the aim of mentioning this is to try and get a further discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hear other people&amp;rsquo;s stories of how they haggled with their service providers. You can find these stories online to get a better understanding of what they did. Morgan M Woods explains how she &lt;a href=&#34;https://morganmwoods.com/save-money/haggle-with-sky/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;cut her own bill down with Sky and managed to save £180&lt;/a&gt; and one blogger even &lt;a href=&#34;https://emmadrew.info/haggled-with-sky/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;managed to save almost £500 in just an hour&lt;/a&gt; on a web chat with Sky!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be prepared to leave! After all, if your provider is not willing to give you a discount, vote with your money and leave for the cheaper service with another provider. Sometimes your provider will call back with a better deal however if not, switching is not that much of a hassle as it was in the past and is always an option to consider to reduce your broadband bill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this knowledge you&amp;rsquo;ll find that navigating these types of conversations a lot easier. It&amp;rsquo;s important to remain polite but also firm when dealing with agents from your IPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-own-recent-experience--haggling-with-my-provider&#34;&gt;My own recent experience  haggling with my provider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called my IPS last week as my contact has just come to an end. My £35 a month bill was going to increase to £65 a month the next month and I personally just thought this was a lot higher than what I was able to get elsewhere. When I called my provider, the first thing I said was that I wanted to cancel my current subscription with them. This led to the agent immediately asking why and if it was because of the price which I confirmed. In the next minute, I was offered a reduced rate of £42 a month. This price was still a lot more than what I was paying before so I persisted and said I still wanted to cancel as the price was just too high. I was then transferred to an agent in another department (likely the retention team) who mentioned they had been informed that I was looking to cancel and asked if there was any particular reason at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the moment I could mention everything I had researched. I mentioned the other deals from other providers that would be able to provide the same service for less than what I was currently paying and wanted to know if that could be matched or beaten as I would likely switch to the cheaper provider otherwise. A minute later I was offered a deal of £34 a month - A saving of just £12 a year compared to my just expiring contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point the agent also tried to scare me by saying switching would be a lot of hassle and that I might receive a lower speed with the new provider. I was aware that the other provider worked with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openreach.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Openreach&lt;/a&gt; and while on the phone I quickly searched my postcode on the Openreach website and found this not to be true and that I was able to get a much higher (but not required) speed if I choose to go with the other provider. I mentioned this and again stated that the quoted price was still more than what the new customer deal was from other providers for the same package (£30 a month). I decided to mention my recent issues and network outages that I had experienced with my current provider as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just 2 and a half weeks ago, my service suffered from a full day outage which prevented me from being able to work from home that day. I had previously called about this and asked what they could do about it and was told that I would be compensated but had still not heard back from them about this or seen this reflected in my monthly bill yet. The agent looked into this further for me and saw that a ticket had been raised but had not been looked into or approved by a manager yet. I asked how long it usually takes to look into such tickets and I was told that it usually took one week. It had been two weeks and a half since that ticket was raised and remained unresolved. I used this new information to my advantage as well and the agent then offered to have this ticket escalated but this would take an additional seven days to look into further - An extra two and a half weeks to the standard resolution timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that taken into consideration, the agent was then able to offer a further reduced price of £28.50 a month (on a 18-month contract) due to the inconveniences I had faced. This price was less than what I was able to find elsewhere for the same deal so I ended up accepting this new lower price. Compared to my last fixed price of £35 a month, over the next 18 months at £28.50, I&amp;rsquo;ll be saving an additional £117!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had I not called and mentioned wanting to cancel or switched, I would have been stuck with a higher bill of £65 a month which would have cost me an extra £540 over the next year and a half (from the contract price of £35 a month). Instead, now I get to keep the same contract but for a lot less!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;till-next-time&#34;&gt;Till next time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully these tips and tricks should help you a bit more on your own broadband bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to do your research to have a strong case ready to present to your internet provider and be prepared to switch if they are not willing to offer you a discount!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you again in two weeks 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank accounts - Chequing out current accounts</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/bank-accounts-chequing-out-current-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/bank-accounts-chequing-out-current-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey folks 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second issue of Akash &amp;amp; Money, fresh out the oven and delivered right to your inboxes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I covered &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds&#34; &gt;emergency funds&lt;/a&gt; and why you should probably have one. In this issue, I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the basics of current accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-accounts&#34;&gt;Current Accounts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the UK your main bank account is your Current Account. This account is mainly used as a place you can store and withdraw money from and use the account to pay for things. You&amp;rsquo;ll find that it comes with a linked bank card called a debit card that lets you spend money from your account. This simply means that your account will have the money taken from the account either on the same day as a transaction or a few days after. Usually, you&amp;rsquo;ll have just the one card linked to each of your accounts but certain accounts can have more than one debit card linked to them at a time such as joint accounts and business accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On your debit card, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely also see a Visa or Mastercard logo on it that tells you which payment network your debit card runs on. Either is fine and there aren&amp;rsquo;t any major differences between the two in the UK. Using your card overseas is a slightly different story - I&amp;rsquo;d recommend that you have at least one Visa card and one Mastercard at hand as you might have payment issues using only one type of debit card in certain countries. While this is uncommon, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to have a few extra cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using your card in the UK, there are no fees for making card transactions however international payments can cost you more based on the fees your bank charges - I&amp;rsquo;d recommend looking for an account/card that does not charge you any fees for using your card abroad like Monzo or Starling Bank. Just remember while spending on your card could be fee-free internationally, this might not be the case for international cash withdrawals. It&amp;rsquo;s always best to double-check with your card provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at the accounts side of things, all current accounts also come with an account number that is 8 digits long and a 6 digits sort code. When paired together these give you a unique way of identifying your account at your bank. The first two digits of the sort code identify which bank the account number is linked to and the last 4 digits refer to a specific bank branch. For example, 23-05-80 is one of Metro Bank&amp;rsquo;s London based branches and can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://newseventsinsights.wearepay.uk/sort-code-checker/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;checked here&lt;/a&gt;. For a branchless bank such as Starling Bank, as there are no branches all accounts share one sort code (60-83-71) instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charges--fees&#34;&gt;Charges &amp;amp; Fees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be quite complex and could even be its own newsletter issue. I&amp;rsquo;ll try and keep this section as simple as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most standard current accounts and basic current accounts are free and there are no fees for opening and maintaining these accounts. Standard current accounts are suitable for most people, however, a bank may not offer if you do not qualify for one. This is where the basic account comes into play. It has most the same features but might have some restrictions on the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third type of current account is called a package account and usually has a monthly fee. The main difference here is that these types of accounts come &amp;lsquo;packaged&amp;rsquo; with other benefits that can include travel insurance, mobile phone insurance, cashback/rewards and other benefits. I won&amp;rsquo;t explore the exact benefits you can get from these types of current accounts as there are several comparison websites that exist that allow you to compare between these types of accounts if you wanted to see which one suits you best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of these three, the standard account will likely be the account suitable for most people. I would only really recommend a packaged account for those that need all/most of the packaged benefits and if getting all those perks via the packaged account is cheaper than getting each of them separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of this, there are often many other fees that exist with current accounts that you could be charged - Alway remember to check over the terms and conditions for any additional or hidden fees for certain transactions. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.barclays.co.uk/content/dam/documents/personal/current-accounts/barclays-tariff-for-personal-customers.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Barclays charges a fixed 2.75% fee&lt;/a&gt; for each card payment made abroad and also add this fee on refunds (meaning you could be hit by the fee twice)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The another fee you might come across is the overdraft fee or unauthorised overdraft fee. An overdraft is where you borrow money from the bank when you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough in your account to cover the cost of a transaction. Some banks even charge fees for declined transactions on your account such as failed direct debit payments! Again, the fees will depend on the bank so it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to check with your bank as you&amp;rsquo;ll want to make sure you aren&amp;rsquo;t paying any of these fees unnecessarily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;direct-debits&#34;&gt;Direct Debits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A direct debit is essentially an instruction from you to your bank to inform them that you are allowing a company to collect an amount of money from your account. You might already have a direct debit set up on your account for things like your monthly gym membership fee, your phone bill or a utility bill. Direct debits are set up using your account number and sort code and are not linked to your bank card (something I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some people get confused about). If you end up having to replace your bank card your direct debits remain unaffected as they do not use your card details at all and can still be collected from your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct debits will usually be for a fixed amount but can vary from time to time (e.g. using extra energy in the winter but using a lot less in the summer), and you&amp;rsquo;ll usually be told about these additional charges or payments before the payment is taken from your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great thing (and important fact) about direct debits is that it comes with something called the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.directdebit.co.uk/DirectDebitExplained/Pages/DirectDebitGuarantee.aspx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Direct Debit Guarantee&lt;/a&gt;. This guarantee allows a payment to be reversed for a full and immediate refund if there is an error with the payment such as the payment being taken on the wrong date or if it&amp;rsquo;s for the wrong amount. Just remember, if you recall a payment that is not meant to be recalled, the organisation will look to recollect that payment - It&amp;rsquo;s best to always confirm with them what the payment is for before recalling it with your bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct Debit payments are made via a system called Bacs (Bankers&amp;rsquo; Automated Clearing System). Founded in 1986, this is the system that clears payments on a three-day working cycle and is not only used for direct debit bills but also credits! You might not realise it but most salaries are paid via this system as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fscs&#34;&gt;FSCS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FSCS (Financial Services Compensation Scheme) exists to help protect customers against financial services firms (like banks and credit card companies) that have failed/gone bust. It is important to check if your current account is protected by the FSCS. Almost all current accounts offer this protection in case the bank that you hold your money with goes out of business and this protection covers up to £85,000 per provider you hold money with rather than per account. So if you have several accounts with a bank (such as savings and investment accounts), then only the first £85,000 across all these accounts are covered. High street banks and digital banks should offer this protection as standard but remember to check. Revolut does not offer full FSCS as an example but still has something similar in place to keep their customer’s money safe in the chance that the business fails. You’ll want to keep an eye out for a &amp;lsquo;fscs protected&amp;rsquo; symbol on their website and/or in their branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have more than £85,000 then you might want to consider spreading your money across a few banks to make sure all your money is covered within that £85,000 limit per provider. Just be aware that some banks might have a shared limit across other banks in their network (The £85,000 FSCS protection from HSBC is shared with First Direct as First Direct is a division of HSBC UK).
For more information regarding the FSCS, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend going through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fscs.org.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; as you can find a range of different financial products that they offer protection on (such as pensions, mortgages and insurance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bank-transfers-faster-payments&#34;&gt;Bank Transfers (Faster Payments)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current accounts will allow you to make bank transfers from your account to another account. This is usually via a system called a ‘Faster Payment’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wearepay.uk/what-we-do/payment-systems/faster-payment-system/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Faster Payments&lt;/a&gt; were officially launched 12 years ago! It&amp;rsquo;s this system that allows you to make bank transfers to your friends within seconds and the maximum that you can send at once is £250,000. For anything more than that you&amp;rsquo;ll have to use a system called CHAPS (Clearing House Automated Payment System) and you&amp;rsquo;ll have to speak to your bank to often make a CHAPS payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a bank transfer all you need is the other parties account number and sort code as well as their name. Most banks are now enrolled in a system called Confirmation of Payee that checks if the account you are sending money to matches the name you typed in for the transfer so you can check you are paying the right person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we have the benefits of this fast and easy to use system, it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that these types of transfers are instant and do not offer any type of protection - If you are buying something it&amp;rsquo;s better to pay via your bank card. Fraudsters will often try to convince you to make payments via Faster Payments for this very reason. Once you send a bank transfer, it&amp;rsquo;s often impossible to get back as fraudsters will often move the money right away, making it hard to get back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to only make a bank transfer to someone you trust as it&amp;rsquo;s essentially the same as handing someone cash. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering certain types of scams and how to avoid them in a later issue of this newsletter in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standing-orders&#34;&gt;Standing Orders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing Orders (or &amp;lsquo;Scheduled Payments&amp;rsquo;) is a way of setting up a fixed regular payment from your bank account to another account. You might set this up to move money from your current account to a savings account or to another current account. Standing orders are bank transfers, so they are also made via the Faster Payments system. The only difference is that they are automated transfers that you&amp;rsquo;ll have to set up ahead of time to be completed on a set date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of parts to a current account but the above serves as a basic need to know and this knowledge should be handy regardless of the number of current accounts you have or even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a current account yet. I haven&amp;rsquo;t recommended any accounts here because I believe the best account will largely depend on the type of person you are and how you manage your money. There are a few websites that compare these types of accounts and a search online can often point out some benefits that some banks might be able to provide you. As always, remember to do your own research to find what works best for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to forward this email to any of your friends and family that you think might be interested in knowing this, and remember to subscribe to the newsletter if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done that already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Funds - Why do you need one?</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney/emergency-funds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey friends 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the first email from the Akash &amp;amp; Money newsletter!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to share a lot of useful information about personal finance in the future so I&amp;rsquo;m glad you are here. Today&amp;rsquo;s topic is emergency funds and is inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ikeeyah_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Kae&lt;/a&gt; and one of her tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kae-emergency-funds-tweet.png&#34; alt=&#34;tweet from kae about emergency funds&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to cover this as my first topic because 2020 has been pretty wild so far. Coronavirus has caused unemployment rates to skyrocket and with that the need for emergency funds as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yourmoney.com/saving-banking/a-fifth-of-uk-workers-had-no-rainy-day-fund-before-covid-19-crisis/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Research found that one in five workers in the UK had no emergency funds before the coronavirus lockdown&lt;/a&gt;. Before the furlough scheme came into effect, this would have left a lot of people worrying about how they would pay for their essentials. For people already living paycheck to paycheck, the 80% paycheck offered simply was not enough and for others, they found themselves &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-53936926&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;locked out from the furlough scheme completely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are perfect examples of why everyone needs an emergency fund!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-emergency-fund&#34;&gt;What is an emergency fund?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An emergency fund is a separate stash of money for unexpected emergencies that may happen in life. Generally, it&amp;rsquo;s a few months of expenses which include rent/mortgage payments, petrol/car payments, food and utility bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of things that can be classed as an emergency; the loss of a job, an unexpected bill or even a boiler repair in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergency fund doesn’t only have one name. In other places, it has also been called the &amp;lsquo;F**k off&amp;rsquo; fund. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebillfold.com/2016/01/a-story-of-a-fuck-off-fund/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Paulette Perhach wrote a post&lt;/a&gt; which explores two different situations, one without an emergency fund and another with one at hand. I think it is an article that is worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R0PdO9CY5Ew&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;I also managed to find this video that summarises emergency funds in just a minute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-you-need-one&#34;&gt;Why do you need one?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an emergency fund can be helpful in several ways. A lot of the time without an emergency fund, people tend to look into credit cards, overdrafts and loans to help them in difficult situations. It’s great having access to such options. However, they can end up costing more in the long term due to the fees associated with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Losing your only source of income can affect your financial life quite severely and sadly this was something that happened to a lot of people this year due to the ongoing pandemic. As mentioned above, a lot of people were able to get 80% of their salary via the furlough scheme in the UK with the remaining 20% being optionally provided by their employer. An emergency fund here could have been used to make up the difference instead if an employer did not provide this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself in a fortunate position where both my job and income were unaffected during the lockdown. At the moment I have about 6 months worth of expenses stored away for emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to dip into my emergency fund three times and I&amp;rsquo;ve listed what I used the money for each time below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vet bill - £800
My dog ended up needing to visit the vet and receive emergency treatment. This is one of the largest bills I&amp;rsquo;ve had to pay out of pocket as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have pet insurance at the time. My emergency fund was at hand to cover the costs of this bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24/7 locksmith - £150
Somehow I managed to lock myself (and my family) out the house with the keys still on the other side of the door late one night! After an hour of trying to unlock the door, I had to call a locksmith to drill a hole through the lock to get the door open and also have a new lock installed on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight change fee - £100
Two years ago I woke up one morning to catch my flight to Tokyo. Unfortunately, I managed to forget my passport at home with less than an hour before the flight. I ended up needing to rebook my flight for the next day. As I’d booked through a travel agent, I only needed to pay £100 for a flight change and narrowly missed having to pay for a completely new ticket. At this point of my life, I didn’t have much of an emergency fund, but I&amp;rsquo;d often set money aside and end up dipping into this fund I had, which later became the foundation of my emergency fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of these situations, my emergency fund was available to cover these unexpected costs. Without this emergency fund, I would have likely turned to using my overdraft or a credit card for these purchases, with both of these options likely costing me more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-start-an-emergency-fund&#34;&gt;How to start an emergency fund&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t got one already, starting to save for an emergency fund can be daunting at first. There are a few things you can do that make the process a bit easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-start-small--figure-out-how-much-you-need-per-month&#34;&gt;1. Start small &amp;amp; figure out how much you need per month&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to look back and work out how much you spend each month to get a rough idea of how much you need per month. To start with it&amp;rsquo;s best to aim for £1,000 as the starting point of your fund. Once you hit that goal, continue adding to your fund until you have several months of expenses put away. I&amp;rsquo;ve found having 6-9 months worth of expenses is generally a good amount to have in an emergency fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-put-money-aside-right-after-you-get-paid&#34;&gt;2. Put money aside right after you get paid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I treat saving for my emergency fund like a bill. I always have to pay into it first after getting paid. By putting this money away first, I’m less tempted to spend it and adopted an &amp;lsquo;Out of sight, out of mind&amp;rsquo; mentality with it, which leads me to the next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-put-your-emergency-fund-in-a-separate-account&#34;&gt;3. Put your emergency fund in a separate account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that keeping this money in a separate place from my main savings has helped remind me not to dip into this fund apart from when I needed it. You can do this as well by using a separate savings account or using a bank that offers the ability to split your money into several pots/spaces without the use of multiple bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-using-savings-apps--round-ups&#34;&gt;4. Using savings apps &amp;amp; round-ups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savings apps like &lt;a href=&#34;https://withplum.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Plum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetcleo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Cleo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandem.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Tandem&lt;/a&gt; all make it a little easier to save money by putting away small amounts of money throughout the month. Some banks like &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Monzo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.starlingbank.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Starling Bank&lt;/a&gt; also offer the ability to round up your transactions and save the spare change from your card purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-have-a-look-at-other-resources&#34;&gt;5. Have a look at other resources!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great information out there on the internet! For example, on Twitter, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ikeeyah_/status/1177362024810143744&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Kae (@ikeeyah_) has a great thread on how to save money&lt;/a&gt;. YouTube channel, Two Cents have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vftjBTjFlzI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;an amazing video on emergency funds&lt;/a&gt;, covering some scenarios of when an emergency fund was/would have been useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The finish line 🏁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far, well done! There&amp;rsquo;s just over 1,200 words here in total, so thanks for sticking around. If you haven’t already, you can follow Akash &amp;amp; Money on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashandmoney/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/akashandmoney/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll see you soon with the next issue of Akash &amp;amp; Money two weeks from now 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akash &amp; Money Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/akash-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/akash-and-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A writing side project I worked on from 2020 to 2022 that covers topics on personal finance. The newsletter had 185 subscribers, with an average open rate of 67% across all posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney&#34; &gt;View the past Akash and Money issues here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual Receipt Generator</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/manual-receipt-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/manual-receipt-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple python third party terminal client based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monzo/reference-receipts-app&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;reference receipts app&lt;/a&gt; that attaches receipts to Monzo transactions using the Monzo Receipts API and a json payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Manual-Receipt-Generator&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;source code here on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity 3D Platformer</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/unity-3d-platformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/unity-3d-platformer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 3d platformer game with randomised powerup mechanics I made for my final year universirty dissertation project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game focus on giving players a different playthrough experience on each playthrough based on the powerups they acquired throughout each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These powerups affected player stats such as movement speed, jump height, and base attack damage. By manipulating these game elements, each playthrough of the game would be unique due to the randomness of the powerups that were presented in each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this 3d platformer also featured a number of classic platformer game mechanics such as pick-up items (coins), moving platforms, enemies, obstacles and portals to teleport the player around different parts of each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this project recieved a 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TfL to Monzo</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/tfl-to-monzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/tfl-to-monzo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TfL to Monzo was an severless application built as my project for my Cloud Computing module at university with a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was written in Python and made use of AWS Lambda to process TfL jounrey data into Monzo recipts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lambda function would recieve incoming transcation webhook events from a linked Monzo account, check if they were TfL transcations and then run a web scraper script to extract the matching journey data from the TfL web portal before then submitting this data as a reciept to the Monzo receipt API endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of my favourite projects at university and overall we recieved a final mark of 98/100. I also posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_/status/1112685400336855040&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; of this project and it was highly received.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Workout</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/credit-card-workout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/portfolio/credit-card-workout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A website that takes a users credit card balance, interest rate and monthly amount they wish to pay to calculate how long it would take them to pay their debt off as well as showing them how much interest they have accumulated. This was made within 24 hours for the Porticode 2.0 Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Credit-Card-Workout&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;source code is hosted here on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://akashgoswami.com/archive/akashandmoney&#34; &gt;View Akash and Money archives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my &lt;a href=&#34;https://nownownow.com/about&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;now page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-what-im-up-to&#34;&gt;⭐ What I&amp;rsquo;m up to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in London and currently work at &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Monzo Bank&lt;/a&gt; as a Cybersecurity Backend Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-learning&#34;&gt;🤓 Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m working on improving my programming skills. I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also learning German 🇩🇪.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-fitness&#34;&gt;🤸🏽‍♂️ Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently getting back into going to the gym regularly 🏋🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cycle regularly (paused for the winter) 🚴🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still trying to get into running 🏃🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got into hiking in 2023. Last summer, I hiked up Ben Nevis in Scotland 🏴󠁧󠁢󠁳󠁣󠁴󠁿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-travel&#34;&gt;🌏 Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔜&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I travelled to the following countries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇳🇱 The Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇩🇪 Germany x2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇯🇵 Japan x2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇻🇳 Vietnam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇮🇩 Indonesia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇸🇬 Singapore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏴󠁧󠁢󠁳󠁣󠁴󠁿 Scotland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-books&#34;&gt;📚 Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently reading through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Product/Charlie-Higson/The-End-The-Enemy-Book-7/17521697&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The End&lt;/a&gt;, book 7 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Search/Search?Series=The%20Enemy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Enemy series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly getting through &lt;a href=&#34;https://shop.peregrinecoast.press/products/filmmakers-without-cameras-the-trilogy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Filmmakers without Cameras: Issue 3&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-films--tv-shows&#34;&gt;🎬 Films &amp;amp; TV Shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recently-watched-films&#34;&gt;Recently watched films&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RDE6Uz73A7g&amp;amp;list=PLJ7A97yl9oXpfq64XZCN9CEQVKMCsHAXh&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Hunger Games: The Ballad of Songbirds &amp;amp;amp; Snakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dlnmQbPGuls&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Trueman Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qEVUtrk8_B4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;John Wick: Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recently-watched-tv-shows&#34;&gt;Recently watched TV shows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/iplayer/episode/m001tfnl/doctor-who-2023-christmas-special-the-church-on-ruby-road&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Doctor Who - Christmas Special: The Church on Ruby Road&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tyqiQWxPz0c&amp;amp;t=3s&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Invincible, season 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-video-games&#34;&gt;🎮 Video Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recently started &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/the-outer-worlds-spacers-choice-edition&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Outer Worlds&lt;/a&gt; on PC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XvQNlGKNC6o&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Super Mario Bros. Wonder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91t0ha9x0AE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hades&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pKJ-NuSjNE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Spiritfarer&lt;/a&gt; on my Nintendo Switch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/wolfenstein-the-new-order&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Wolfenstein: The New Order&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 1st January 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses</title>
      <link>https://akashgoswami.com/uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akashgoswami.com/uses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The things I use on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;laptop&#34;&gt;Laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14&amp;quot; M1 Pro Macbook Pro 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anne Pro 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Magic Trackpad 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Razer Viper Ultimate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phone&#34;&gt;Phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 14 Pro Max&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Watch Series 8 45mm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Airpods Pro 2nd Gen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quadlock iPhone 14 Pro Max MAG case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quadlock MAG wallet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;desktop-pc&#34;&gt;Desktop PC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU: Intel Core i5-8600K 3.6 GHz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPU: NVIDIA FE GeForce RTX 3080&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RAM: Kingston HyperX Fury 16 GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSD: Sabrent M.2 NVMe SSD 2TB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-things-i-like&#34;&gt;Other things I like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.namecheap.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://porkbun.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Porkbun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fonts&#34;&gt;Fonts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/githubnext/monaspace&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Monaspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.myfonts.com/collections/knicknack-font-great-scott&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Knicknack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fontspace.com/public-pixel-font-f72305&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Public Pixel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://simplebits.shop/collections/fonts/products/cartridge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Cartridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brailleinstitute.org/freefont&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Atkinson Hyperlegible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adobe-fonts/source-code-pro&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Source Code Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;icons&#34;&gt;Icons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tabler-icons.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Tabler Icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robbiepearce.com/softies&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Softies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feathericons.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Feather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>