<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Akash Goswami</title>
    <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Akash Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language></language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Skyth3r.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Japan Tips</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/z/japan-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/z/japan-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: This is a work in progress page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips for visiting Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-tips&#34;&gt;General Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have an iPhone, add a Suica card to your Apple Wallet and then add it to Express Mode via the settings. This lets you tap in and out of most public transport extremely quickly. You can also use the for payments in a number of stores and topping it up is done within seconds from the Apple Wallet app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid missing the last train. Ubers are really expensive in Japan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note down the 7-11 locations near where you&amp;rsquo;re staying. They are open 24/7 and all have an ATM that accepts all international bank cards (great for when you need to make a cash withdrawal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to drive in Japan (yes this includes go karts!)? Remember to get your International Drivers Permit before you leave the UK. You can get it from The Post Office for about £5.50 and need to bring your drivers linsce and a passport photo of yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tokyo&#34;&gt;Tokyo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monkey Kart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teamLab Planets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Disneyland/Tokyo DisneySea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAUNA RESET Pint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensō-ji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asakusa Kagetsudō - Matcha ice cream melon pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matcha Sweets Kaminari-Issa - assortment of matcha items, including a matcha beer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soranoiro NIPPON - Tokyo Ramen Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tajimaya Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omoide Yokochō&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;locations&#34;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pokémon Center Shibuya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shibuya Scramble Crossing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsukiji Outer Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;osaka&#34;&gt;Osaka&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-1&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rikuro’s - Fluffy japanese cheesecake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;locations-1&#34;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dotombori - Ebisubashi Bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsūtenkaku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Osaka Castle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Studios Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Osaka Tenmangu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kyoto&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;activities-1&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-2&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kikyo Sushi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nishiki Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;locations-2&#34;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hōkan-ji Temple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiyomizu-dera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fushimi Inari Taisha (Thousand Tori Gates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kinkaku-ji (Golden Temple)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bamboo forest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kyoto Tower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An eSim database!</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/esimdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/esimdb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I came across a handly little app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airalo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Airalo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airalo lets you install data only eSims on your phone - perfect for a trip abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always been my go to since (most) mobile networks in the UK re-introuduced roaming fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://esimdb.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;esimbdb&lt;/a&gt;. A way of comparing eSim prices from various eSim providers for different countries!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably still going to use Airalo. It might cost a little more, but the app is super conveniance, accepts Apple Pay (or Google Pay on Android), gives you cashback credit on your purchases and simplifies the eSim installion process (it&amp;rsquo;s a one tap install on iOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to give Airalo a spin? Use my code &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;AKASH336&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; for $3 off your first purchase (I also get $3 in credit as well).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A solar powered website</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/solar-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 21:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/solar-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I came across a quirky little website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Low Tech Magazine&lt;/a&gt; is a website that explores forgotten tech and energy sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Articles on the website are split into three main categories; &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/low-tech-solutions/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Low-tech solutions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/high-tech-problems/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;High-tech problems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/obsolete-technology/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Obsolete Technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite part. It&amp;rsquo;s a solar powered website ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally the website goes down when it&amp;rsquo;s not sunny enough in Barcelona (where the web server is based) and the backup battery has run dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do when you want to read articles from the website and the site is down? Well you can access the site&amp;rsquo;s content offline&amp;hellip;as &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/offline-reading/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;physical books&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s such a interesting take on websites that I really like the idea of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite article from the website so far - &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2023/02/can-we-make-bicycles-sustainable-again/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Can We Make Bicycles Sustainable Again?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Double Tap</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/apple-watch-double-tap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/apple-watch-double-tap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 12th September 2023, Apple announced the new Apple Watch Series 9 with a new double tap guesture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except&amp;hellip;this new guesture isn&amp;rsquo;t actually new. You can enable it on your Apple Watch (Series 4 and later, Apple Watch SE and later, and Apple Watch Ultra) already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Apple Watch app on your iPhone, head to Settings &amp;gt; Accessibility &amp;gt; AssistiveTouch and then toggle &amp;lsquo;Hand Gestures&amp;rsquo; on. You can now control your entire Apple Watch with one hand using the Pinch, Double Pinch, Clench and Double Clench gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works flawlessly on my Apple Watch Series 8 (gestures on older models might be less reliable). The difference between the new double tap guesture and the double pinch guesture seems to be minimal with the expection of the double tap guesture being enabled by default on the new Apple Watch and the hardware being slighlty better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade an Apple Watch for this one feature but battery life and other improvements would be my main reason for getting a newer Apple Watch. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sticking to my Series 8.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arc&#39;s secert reader mode</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/arc-reader-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/arc-reader-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the features I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked in Apple&amp;rsquo;s Safari web browser is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/safari/sfri32632/mac&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Safari Reader mode&lt;/a&gt;, which removes ads, navigation or other distracting elements from a web page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works perfectly for me on iOS but on my laptop, I mainly use Google Chrome and Arc for my web browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome has a reader type view hidden under &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt; and by then searching for &amp;lsquo;reading mode&amp;rsquo; but it&amp;rsquo;s still a bit complicated to enable and doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide the same view as Safari&amp;rsquo;s web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arc.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Arc for macOS&lt;/a&gt; has a hidden reader mode that can be enabled on a web page by pressing the &lt;code&gt;option + command + r&lt;/code&gt; keys together which is much more similar to Safari&amp;rsquo;s reader mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - Arc&amp;rsquo;s reader mode is still in beta but does a great job regardless&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houston, we have notes!</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/adding-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/adding-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to the articles, I’ve decided to add a notes section to the website now. There are times when I wanted to write a short piece about something but it didn’t feel right to put it in the articles section of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I just want to…note something down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hence the &lt;a href=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes&#34; &gt;notes section&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-notes-meant-to-be&#34;&gt;What are notes meant to be?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes will be short pieces of writing. Most likely a couple of lines long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’ll basically be my equivalent of a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a note ends up getting too long, I might decide to nudge it over to the articles section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-rss-feed&#34;&gt;Notes RSS feed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a new RSS feed is auto-magically generated for notes.
If you want to subscribe to it, here’s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/index.xml&#34; &gt;notes RSS feed link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use an adblocker</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/adblocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/notes/adblocker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You should be using an adblocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not because ads are bad (although some are really annoying), but because even &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/22/fbi-ad-blocker/?guccounter=1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the FBI recommend using one for security&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://ublockorigin.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; and block those scam adverts that pop up at the top of search results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRM free books</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy reading books on my Kindle. I also buy most of my digital books via Amazon. I never thought about making DRM-free copies of my eBooks until I read about how &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bjax_/a-tale-of-unwanted-disruption-my-week-without-amazon-df1074e3818b&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;an engineer has his Amazon account suspended&lt;/a&gt; due to a delivery driver&amp;rsquo;s false claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That really got me thinking about how I would feel if I lost access to my Amazon account. I’ve purchased most of my ebooks from Amazon. Losing access would mean losing the majority of my digital library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid such a situation, I decided it was time to make a copy of the digital eBooks I purchased from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article covers how I removed the DRM from my Kindle ebooks so I can read my books on any device without needing to use a Kindle app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going further, I’ll answer some questions some folks might have 👇🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-frequently-asked-questions-faq&#34;&gt;Quick Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is DRM?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRM stands for Digital Rights Management. It’s a type of tech used to control and manage access to copyrighted content. Its main purpose is to prevent content from being shared with those that did not pay for it and to also prevent the content from being modified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What issues does it pose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While DRM is used to prevent piracy, it can cause issues for legitimate users as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, say you bought a video game that comes with some DRM that checks you own the game by contacting the game publisher’s server before you can play the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine if the game publisher went out of business and with that, the server used for the DRM check goes offline with it. Now you’re in a situation where you’ve paid for a video game but you can no longer access it due to the DRM server going offline (Also what if you just wanted to play the game offline/without an internet connection?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital books from Amazon, are only intended to be read on Kindle devices and via the Kindle app using your Amazon account. If you lost access to your Amazon account for any reason, you would essentially lose access to the books you bought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should you care about removing DRM from your eBooks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s simple. Not having DRM on your eBooks means you can read them on any device using any app you want without having to worry about losing access to your books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it illegal to remove DRM from your digital items?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Just don’t distribute the DRM-free books you have as that would be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There a several guides online that explain how to do this, I initially followed those methods but I got some errors when following these guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I’ve listed the steps that worked for me. You might find that this exact approach not working for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need a Kindle eReader or the Kindle app on your machine. I personally used my Kindle eReader for this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - I use MacOS so these steps will be MacOS specific but the steps are similar if you are using a different operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First download &lt;a href=&#34;https://calibre-ebook.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a free open source e-book manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have Calibre installed, you’ll need to download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noDRM/DeDRM_tools/releases&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;NoDRM plugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the settings/preferences menu within Calibre and then click plug-ins under ‘Advanced’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the ‘Load plug-in from file’ option and then select the noDRM zip file you downloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your Kindle’s serial number from your Kindle device. You can find it under Settings &amp;gt; Device options &amp;gt; Device info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back the plug-in menu in Calibre, select the NoDRM plug-in (under the file type sub-heading) and click ‘Customise plug-in’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select ‘Kindle eInk ebooks’, click the green plus icon and enter your Kindle serial number and then click ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to the plug-ins menu, click ‘Get new plug-ins’ and then install the ‘KFX Input’ plug-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the Amazon website and then select the ‘Manage Your Content and Devices’ under your account menu and then click ‘Books’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the eBook you want to download and then select more actions &amp;gt; download and transfer via USB to download the eBook (Note - the file extension should be ‘AZW3’. I wasn’t able to get the ‘AFX’ file extension decryption/DRM removal working)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag and drop the eBook into the Calibre and then select ‘Convert Book” and then convert the book into whatever format you like (I usually go with ePub) and your eBook should have the DRM removed from it now 🎉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re able to remove DRM from your Kindle books you can read them on any device you like! If you want a Kindle like e-reader without having to buy a Kindle, you might want to consider a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pocketbook.ch/en-ch&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Pocketbook&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-to-buy-ebooks-going-forward&#34;&gt;Where to buy eBooks going forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can of course still buy your eBooks from Amazon, but it might be worth exploring what other options exist that allow you to get DRM free books way more easily. One of my favourites is a website called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/eBooks&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hive&lt;/a&gt; which sells eBooks in ePub and PDF formats by default and most books are similarly priced to their Amazon counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s everything you should need to build a DRM-free digital library. All that’s left to do is to back up your eBooks somewhere (like a digital cloud provider) so you can alway keep a copy of the books you bought).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/community/file/1047875211730430527/Amazon-Kindle-Paperwhite-Mockup&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Article header image by Vyshnav Gangadharan under CC 4.0 license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Leave (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/sabbatical-leave-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/sabbatical-leave-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took 9 weeks off work. Of those 9 weeks, I spent 8 travelling. This is a summary of how I found my time off and what I did, things I learnt from my first long-term travel trip and my favourite highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-sabbatical-leave&#34;&gt;What is sabbatical leave?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick 101 - sabbatical leave is an extended period of time away from work. Common reasons for taking sabbatical leave are to pursue interests outside of work; such as travelling, studying, volunteering or even just to take a break to just rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-i-get-my-sabbatical-leave&#34;&gt;How did I get my sabbatical leave?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work at a bank called &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Monzo&lt;/a&gt; and about a year ago they introduced a new benefit. 3 months of paid sabbatical leave for those that had been at the company for 4 years. It just happens so that I was months away from hitting my 4 year work anniversary at the time of this announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I did the logical thing and started planning how I would spend these 3 months away from work right away. In the end, I’ve taken 9 weeks of sabbatical leave this year, with plans of using the remaining next year for another trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terms-and-conditions&#34;&gt;Terms and Conditions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the catch? It almost sounds too good to be true right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, there was nothing that was of any concern. There were only two conditions I had to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was that for the amount of time, I took as sabbatical leave, I needed to give double the length of that as my notice for taking the leave. Since I took 9 weeks off, I had to give 18 weeks of notice before taking the time off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other condition was that you’re required to keep working for the company for at least 6 months after taking sabbatical leave or I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay it back. Sounds pretty reasonable to me. I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on quitting anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-i-do-during-my-sabbatical&#34;&gt;What did I do during my sabbatical?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was really conflicted about what to do with my time off. Part of me really wanted to travel and another part of me wanted to stay at home and work on several projects I just never found the time for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I decided to prioritise travelling and also make use of the credit card points/air miles I’d been saving up for the last 6 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of planning, I ended up visiting 6 countries on my trip; The Netherlands, Germany, Japan, Vietnam, Indonesia and Singapore. I went slowly through these countries to take the time to explore without feeling like I didn’t have enough time to do everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally my plan was to use all 3 months of sabbatical leave to travel across all of south-east Asia, Japan, South Korea and also Australia but it felt like I was trying to do too much in one trip. Adding locations like South Korea and Australia would have also made the trip expensive 💸&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I think travelling for 2 months instead of 3 was the right call. I started to feel a bit overwhelmed towards the end of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel-tips&#34;&gt;Travel Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not an expert when it comes to solo travelling and I’ve never done a trip for this long before. The journey wasn’t always smooth and I managed to run into some problems along the way. Here’s what I think people should consider before travelling for long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get away from work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To truly immerse yourself while travelling, one of the first things I would consider doing is switching off from work (that is of course, if you didn’t quit your job to go and travel). No emails, no Slack or Microsoft Teams. Nothing. If you have a work laptop/phone, leave it at home. I personally just ended up logging out of my work email account and Slack and made sure I couldn’t log back in until after I got back from my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack less&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I had to learn the hard way. Avoid over-packing. Easier said than done. Learn how to pack efficiently, use some packing cubes and try and travel with a single bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do that…it was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, double-check where the nearest place to do laundry is before you need to do it. You’ll thank yourself later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus tip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - If you are going to check-in some luggage for the flight, have a day or two&amp;rsquo;s worth of clothes/essentials in your carry-on. A friend that joined me in Japan had his suitcase lost by the airline. He did get it back in the end, but had to go a few days without his stuff 😬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book flexible/refundable tickets, accommodation, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can cost a little extra to choose the fully refundable/flexible but there are times when you’ll be grateful you can just change your plans without any worries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up doing this myself, I changed my accommodation in Bali 2 nights before arriving and extended my stay in the areas I really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything needs to be fully flexible, however. Flights are usually fine to not book as fully refundable. Most accommodation options in south-east Asia are really cheap so I booked everything as fully refundable (I only had to pay for the first night upfront and usually paid the rest on arrival).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leads me to my next tip…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t plan everything in advance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s nice to have a plan and some things you definitely do need to book in advance. Not every day has to be planned down to the last minute, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s better to just embrace the randomness. That’s how I ended up doing some things I would never have considered, like trying out a sensory deprivation tank in Vietnam, climbing an active volcano at 4 am in the morning to watch the sunrise, or accidentally walking right into the Sanja Festival in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll find more exciting things to do and see walking down random streets and by talking to people you encounter along the way on your trip. I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spend less time on your phone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. Phones are the modern-day equivalent of a Swiss Army knife. They are incredibly useful but they can also be extremely distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s too easy to grab your phone and start scrolling through Instagram or TikTok when you’ve got a spare moment. I try not to look at my phone too much when I’m travelling (I make an exception for when I need to contact people).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay in hostels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re solo travelling, hostels are the best place to stay in my opinion. It’s cheap, sociable, and overall just really fun. Most hostels also offer private rooms if you’re not keen on sharing a room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most memorable moments from my trip from thanks to the friends I met along the way. Hostels are the perfect environment for meeting new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare for things to go wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t except so many things to go wrong on this trip. Train strikes, almost missing my flight (twice), almost paying over £200 for an Uber&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these setbacks, I still had an amazing time! Sure it was annoying/frustrating when things went wrong, but situations like that really put that Brain Tracy quote into perspective for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot control what happens to you, but you can control your attitude toward what happens to you, and in that, you will be mastering change rather than allowing it to master you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus the travel stories where things go wrong are always way more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-5-highlights&#34;&gt;Top 5 highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of exciting moments from my trip. Here’s what were my top five:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Driving a go-kart down the streets of Tokyo
&lt;img src=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/img/sabbatical-leave/tokyo_go_karts.png&#34; alt=&#34;Me, sitting in a go-kart at an intersection of the Shibuya scramble crossing&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Climbing up Mt Batur at 4 am to watch the sunrise from the peak in Bali
&lt;img src=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/img/sabbatical-leave/mt_batur.png&#34; alt=&#34;A view of the valley covered in clouds from the peak of Mt Batur at 6 am in the morning&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waking up at 4:30 am in the morning to an iconic photo of the Hōkan-ji Temple in Kyoto
&lt;img src=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/img/sabbatical-leave/hokan_ji.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunrise photo of the Hōkan-ji Temple in Kyoto&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching the sunset on a boat at Ha Long Bay in Vietnam
&lt;img src=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/img/sabbatical-leave/halong_bay.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset of the bay at Ha Long Bay in Vietnam&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking a photo with this adorable chihuahua at the Senso-ji temple festive (Sanja Matsuri) in Tokyo
&lt;img src=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/img/sabbatical-leave/chihuahua.png&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of me holding a chihuahua wearing a costume with glasses for the Senso-ji temple festive (Sanja Matsuri)&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back at work now but I still have some sabbatical leave left to use. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on carrying it over to next year and using it for a trip to South Africa. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely also do a few smaller trips across Europe before that though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I really enjoy travelling, it&amp;rsquo;s always been the people that I&amp;rsquo;ve met that have made each trip ten times better. While a lot of these new friends might be scattered across the world, I plan on dropping in on a few of them from time to time as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to be back on another adventure soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shoutout&#34;&gt;Shoutout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, none of this would have been possible without my workplace. A massive thanks to Monzo for introducing the new sabbatical leave policy. While other companies do offer similar policies for long-term employees, Monzo&amp;rsquo;s policy is unmatched by any other company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising my Hugo Theme</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Hugo website uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Digital Garden Hugo theme&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes in addition to using the theme. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed these changes below both for myself to refer back to and for anyone else that might find these useful to include in their own Hugo website 👇🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating-lastmod-text&#34;&gt;Updating lastmod text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first changes I made was to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/ee9926c786e458476524ac571be01a7ea6a38285&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;change the lastmod front matter text&lt;/a&gt; that was displayed on the theme. Previously it would default to showing &lt;code&gt;Pruned January 2, 2023&lt;/code&gt; on articles with the &lt;code&gt;lastmod&lt;/code&gt; front matter. After my change to the article single layout it now instead shows &lt;code&gt;Last tended to on January 2, 2023&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ if .Date }}
    &amp;lt;p class=&amp;#34;text-sm text-slate-500 !mb-8&amp;#34;&amp;gt; Planted {{ $date }}
		{{ if ne $lastmod $date}}
			&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Last tended to on {{ .Lastmod.Format &amp;#34;January 2, 2006&amp;#34; }}
        {{ end }}
	&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
{{ end }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-analytics&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding Google Analytics to the site is pretty simple as it&amp;rsquo;s natively supported by the theme I&amp;rsquo;m using. Within the config.toml file, you just need to add the Google Analytics tracking ID in the format, &amp;ldquo;googleAnalytics = &amp;lsquo;TRAKCING_CODE_HERE&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue I noticed with this was the fact analytics data would be pinged back to Google Analytics while I worked on the website locally on my own machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix this, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/1bcb816700f2244d7a8337f61be5b410886f88bd#diff-5f948a63b2e0f5e8409b3a709cb74c89451854c6ded2959a6f110d5340001cc1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;replaced the config.toml file stored in the root of the repository with a config folder&lt;/a&gt; and then split the config.toml file into two files, a default file that contained all the config settings for the site, and a production config.toml file that contains only the Google Analytics tracking code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I work on new things for the website I run the command &lt;code&gt;hugo server --environment development -D&lt;/code&gt;, which loads only the default config file. When re-building the website, I use the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command takes both config files and merges them together to build the production website, thus resolving the issue of generating accidently analytics data during testing and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-article-front-matter&#34;&gt;Additional Article Front Matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up adding a few new improvements to the article front matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;article-read-time&#34;&gt;Article read time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/a3cea7373e46fd49c8ab0c0e1499497741153237&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Added a read time for articles&lt;/a&gt;. This is automatically generated and listed for each article item. This is based on the code found &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/readingtime-define/13036/4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ if gt .ReadingTime 1 }}
    {{ .Scratch.Set &amp;#34;readingTime&amp;#34; &amp;#34;minutes&amp;#34; }}
{{ else }}
    {{ .Scratch.Set &amp;#34;readingTime&amp;#34; &amp;#34;minute&amp;#34; }}
{{ end }}
Reading time: {{ .ReadingTime }} {{ .Scratch.Get &amp;#34;readingTime&amp;#34; }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tags&#34;&gt;Tags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be able to nagivate my site articles by tags, so I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/29ede00b08c2f0eabe217eee315ef9924498250d&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;added tags to each article&lt;/a&gt; and updated the autogenerated tags page (was previously blank) as well. The code from the tags page is currently just copied from the theme&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme/tree/main/layouts/portfolio&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;portfolio layout&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect but it works for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Tags:
{{ with .Param &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34; }}
    {{ range $index, $tag := (. | sort) }} 
        {{ with $.Site.GetPage (printf &amp;#34;/%s/%s&amp;#34; &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34; $tag) }}
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;{{ .Permalink }}&amp;#34;&amp;gt;#{{ $tag | urlize }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
        {{ end }}
    {{ end }}
{{ end }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rel-me-verifcation&#34;&gt;rel-me verifcation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modified the social icons sidebar code to &lt;a href=&#34;ttps://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/f7cf25f796ead76c1348da976cb980e899f1302a&#34; &gt;include rel=me&lt;/a&gt;. Used for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.joinmastodon.org/user/profile/#verification&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;verification on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;a class=&amp;#34;px-2 py-1.5 rounded-md text-sm block text-slate-800 dark:text-slate-50 {{ if eq (.URL|absURL) $permalink }} bg-slate-800 text-white dark: {{ else }} hover:bg-slate-200 dark:hover:bg-slate-700 {{ end }}&amp;#34;
    href=&amp;#34;{{ .URL }}&amp;#34; target=&amp;#34;_blank&amp;#34; rel=&amp;#34;noopener noreferrer me&amp;#34;&amp;gt;
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;404-page-copy&#34;&gt;404 page copy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/1dd845aa4b5894753755a2384eb4d1f784067337&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Added some copy to the 404 page&lt;/a&gt; as it was previously a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-me-a-coffee-widget&#34;&gt;Buy me a coffee widget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io/commit/698221f0451372bac9b85b90fcff1b9f92321597&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Added a buy me a coffee widget&lt;/a&gt; to each article page by creating a new partial shortcode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, there has been a flurry of activity around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23513418/bring-back-personal-blogging&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;personal blogs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brycewray.com/posts/2022/11/own-your-stuff/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;owning your own data&lt;/a&gt;, since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23551060/elon-musk-twitter-takeover-layoffs-workplace-salute-emoji&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Musk took the reins of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, a lot of people have been wondering how they can start their own websites. Since re-launching my website, I&amp;rsquo;ve had people ask me how they can make their own website in the last few weeks. To avoid repeating myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a guide on how you can build a website using Hugo and GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kinsta.com/blog/hugo-static-site/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Other guides exist&lt;/a&gt;, but this one covers how I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my website in a simple and easy-to-follow guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this demo, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo Bear Blog theme&lt;/a&gt; as it&amp;rsquo;s a nice minimalist theme to start with. My website uses a theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Digital Garden&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-garden-hugo-theme.vercel.app/articles/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;installation steps&lt;/a&gt; for this theme are slightly more complicated. This guide will focus on using a simpler theme to demonstrate the basics of building websites with Hugo. There are many other &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;free Hugo themes&lt;/a&gt; you can choose from as well on the official Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One minor note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s not needed, I would recommend spending some money and buying a domain name. Usually, most people want a domain in the format of firstNameLastName[dot]com, but you can pick anything you like. For example, Sophie&amp;rsquo;s domain is &lt;a href=&#34;https://localghost.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;localghost.dev&lt;/a&gt;, a fun play on words for localhost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain name shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost too much and you can buy one from several domain name registrars. I bought my domain name, akashgoswami.com via &lt;a href=&#34;https://domains.google/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Google Domains&lt;/a&gt; and pay £10 a year for it (that&amp;rsquo;s less than £1 a month!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;What is Hugo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is a fast static site generator tool written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;. It uses templates and markdown files to generate webpages in seconds. The final result is a set of HTML files that you can deploy as a website using a hosting provider such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use an analogy. Let&amp;rsquo;s pretend that we&amp;rsquo;re making a sandwich, instead of building a website 🥪&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prepare our sandwich by laying out all the ingredients that we want to include in our sandwich. Once that&amp;rsquo;s done, you simply run the &amp;lsquo;make sandwich&amp;rsquo; command to create a sandwich within seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine we want to swap out some of those ingredients, add new ones or remove some we don&amp;rsquo;t like. We can run the &amp;lsquo;make sandwich&amp;rsquo; command again and have a new sandwich created with these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s how Hugo works, but instead of making a sandwich, it generates the files needed to make a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start building our website, there are a few things you&amp;rsquo;ll need beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-text-editor&#34;&gt;A text editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need something to edit your code in. I like using &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;.There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tools/editors/#visual-studio-code&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;handy Hugo extensions&lt;/a&gt; that you can install within Visual Studio Code as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;familiarity-with-using-a-command-line-app&#34;&gt;Familiarity with using a command line app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to navigate around files and run some Hugo commands using the command line interface. On macOS, the built-in command line tool is called &amp;lsquo;Terminal&amp;rsquo; (but I prefer using &lt;a href=&#34;https://iterm2.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;) and on Windows it&amp;rsquo;s Powershell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-package-manager&#34;&gt;A Package Manager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo can be installed as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;prebuilt binary&lt;/a&gt; but I prefer using a package manager. For macOS, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to use Homebrew. For Windows, it&amp;rsquo;s Chocolatey. The installation guides for both of these package managers is well documented so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the links to official installation instructions below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS - &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Installation instructions for Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows - &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/install&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Installation instructions for Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux - If you use a Linux-based OS then you can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/linux/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;correct installation steps for your Linux distro here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-and-git&#34;&gt;GitHub (and Git)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To host the website, we&amp;rsquo;re going to use GitHub Pages, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; account. Create an account (please also enable 2-factor authentication) and then install &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to install Git via your package manager if it&amp;rsquo;s not already on your machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install git.install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-our-website&#34;&gt;Setting up our website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, open the command line and navigate to where you want to create your website project file. I choose to create mine in Users/Akash (the default directory when you open Terminal on macOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run the following command (but replace username with your GitHub username):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site username.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This creates a new folder under the same name that contains some starter files for your Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then run the following two commands to navigate into this newly created folder and create a git repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd username.github.io
git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, we want to add our Hugo theme and set it as well by using the following two commands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog themes/hugo-bearblog
echo &amp;#34;theme = &amp;#39;hugo-bearblog&amp;#39;&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; config.toml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;rsquo;s done you can spin up the website by running &lt;code&gt;hugo server&lt;/code&gt; and then visiting http://localhost:1313/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stop the web server, just enter the command mentioned in your command line application (for macOS its Ctrl+C).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modifying-the-site&#34;&gt;Modifying the site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the website is set up, you can add your own content to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to a theme&amp;rsquo;s recommended instructions. For &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;hugo-bearblog theme&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog/tree/master/exampleSite&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;exampleSite folder&lt;/a&gt; with the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve made your changes, you can build your website by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. This will update the files within your public folder, which you can then deploy to a hosting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uploading-the-website-to-github&#34;&gt;Uploading the website to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;re happy with our website, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to upload it to GitHub. Open the GitHub Desktop application and then go to File &amp;gt; Open Local Repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you tick all the files and then enter a commit message. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be too fancy, &amp;lsquo;first commit&amp;rsquo; works well. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done that, click &amp;lsquo;Commit to main&amp;rsquo; and then the &amp;lsquo;Publish repository&amp;rsquo; button. A popup will appear asking you to name your new repository. Name it &amp;lsquo;username.github.io&amp;rsquo; and set it to be public before you click the &amp;lsquo;Publish Repository&amp;rsquo; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-actions&#34;&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deploy your website, open the new repository via GitHub on a web browser, and then head to Settings &amp;gt; Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here you can switch the source to &amp;lsquo;GitHub Actions&amp;rsquo; and the default Hugo action should be suggested. Click configure button and then commit the code to your main branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you now head back to the Actions tab you can see a workflow running to build your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;setting-your-domain-name-optional&#34;&gt;Setting your domain name (Optional)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a custom domain, you can set your website&amp;rsquo;s name from the Custom Domain section of the Pages settings page. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to set your DNS records from your domain registrar to point to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your website has been built, you can view it by entering either username.github.io or your custom domain name from your web browser!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! You&amp;rsquo;ve built your own website 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know the basics, feel free to edit anything you like; switch themes, write new posts, the choice is yours. You can now host your own website, and push new content to it by syncing your changes from your machine to GitHub via GitHub Desktop. Just remember to also run the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command to rebuild the website after making any changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you found this guide helpful at all or want to suggest an improvement, feel free to reach out to me and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a personal website</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time and time again, we are shown that we cannot rely on third-party platforms to host our content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is constantly changing and with that, the platforms that host our content are constantly in flux. Platforms can fall just as quickly as they can rise, either by just going &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/site-deaths&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;completely offline&lt;/a&gt; or by making drastic changes to how people interact with content on their site/platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless examples of this happening in the past and more recently the 2022 Twitter meltdown has led to some massive changes. One of these changes is that the newsletter platform Twitter acquired just two years ago, Revue is now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/14/23509254/twitter-revue-shutdown-newsletter-data-deletion&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;shutting down&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;digital-platforms-are-fragile&#34;&gt;Digital platforms are fragile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s partly why I’m writing this. The shutdown of Revue has been particularly frustrating for me as someone who moved their &lt;a href=&#34;https://akashandmoney.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; from another newsletter service to Revue thinking it would be a better fit earlier this year. The announced shutdown left me scrambling to migrate my content and subscribers over the Christmas holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just goes to show you the kind of problems we face when we trust third-party platforms to host our content. Thankfully I managed to export my content &amp;amp; subscribers in time, but that got me wondering&amp;hellip;How do I avoid this happening again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;owning-your-content&#34;&gt;Owning your content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to start owning our digital content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning more about IndieWeb, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to follow their &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/principles&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;community principles&lt;/a&gt;. The one that stood out to me was the principle of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/own_your_data&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;owning your data&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So going forward I&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting more of my content here on this website where I don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about another platform dying out and losing my content. Hosting my content also gives me the ability to fully control how my website/content looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean I’m quitting on using other platforms entirely but instead I plan on using this website to complement my activity on other digital platforms. You&amp;rsquo;ll likely see my cross-posting most of my content from here to these other platforms for visibility (A practice coined as &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt; by IndieWeb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-having-a-personal-website&#34;&gt;The benefits of having a personal website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a great number of benefits as to why you should have your own website but here are the reasons that really matter to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform independent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest reason for me at the moment. All my content is owned by me and hosted on my website, overall reducing my dependence on third-party platforms for content hosting. I won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about my account being banned, I won&amp;rsquo;t have to migrate my data after another platform announces that it&amp;rsquo;s shutting down and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about a platform suddenly removing its free tier and demanding payment to continue using their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, this website is built using a static site generator and hosted via &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. In the future, if I wanted to change hosting platforms or the structure of this website, I have the full flexibility to do so all while maintaining access to my content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robust &amp;amp; compact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m using a static site generator for this website now, this has simplified a lot for me and has helped make the website a lot smaller and more compact. Due to its small size, I&amp;rsquo;m able to back up the entire site to several other code hosting/cloud storage platforms with ease. Currently, you can find this website on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Skyth3r.github.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, using a static site generator has also done a lot of the heavy lifting when it comes to SEO optimisation and has drastically improved the website&amp;rsquo;s load times as pointed out by this speed test 👇🏽
&lt;img src=&#34;https://Skyth3r.github.io/img/personal-website/pagespeed-insights-desktop-100.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pagespeed insights results desktop: 100% all pagespeed-insights-desktop-100-performace&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-expect-from-this-website&#34;&gt;What to expect from this website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can you expect from this website then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m someone that has several interests and hobbies so I don&amp;rsquo;t want to box myself in with a particular theme or topic. My interests are not set in stone, and I expect them to change over time but there will likely be many recurring themes &amp;amp; topics I write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I plan on writing things around programming, tech, travel, video games, projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on, things I&amp;rsquo;m learning, life updates and anything else I find interesting or useful that I think is worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-is-not-a-blog&#34;&gt;This is NOT a blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of against the idea of calling this a blog. I found that having a blog always felt really pressurising. It felt like every post had to be perfect and I would end up spending too much time polishing up each post before publishing them. I would end up publishing less and less over time, while fussing over each post, trying to chase that sense of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/posts/perfectionism&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;perfection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-to-my-digital-garden&#34;&gt;Welcome to my Digital Garden!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come to like the term &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;digital garden&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and I think it better suits what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to achieve with this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is my public digital garden. A place for me to cultivate, and grow my thoughts, ideas, and other bits of information freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote from Maggie Appleton explains it well while keeping it short and simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gardens present information in a richly linked landscape that grows slowly over time. Everything is arranged and connected in ways that allow you to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I&amp;rsquo;d like to build. An inter-connected garden of information around the things that interest me. I like to think of it more as being a content &lt;em&gt;curator&lt;/em&gt; rather than being a content creator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I think there is a lot of information out there in the world and there&amp;rsquo;s only so much the human brain can hold and retain. Having a secondary space (almost like a second brain) for collecting and organising meaningful notes, thoughts and ideas can help free cognitive capacity, a bit like backing up your computer&amp;rsquo;s hard drive to cloud storage to free up memory on the local disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have multiple digital gardens, scattered across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instapaper.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/i/akash56&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt;, etc, but this is the first one I&amp;rsquo;ll be publishing publicly as a centralised home to share what I find important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as this is for other people to read, this is also for me to reflect on myself and build upon existing ideas and thoughts of mine that would otherwise usually get lost among the various note-taking apps I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about rebuilding my website for some time, but never got around to doing it. It was thanks to a handful of people that I found the motivation to start working on this site again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to give a little shoutout to them for how they helped me find the direction I wanted to go with this website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shoutouts&#34;&gt;Shoutouts:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localghost.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Sophie Koonin&lt;/a&gt; - For having an awesome personal website that inspired me to redesign mine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bradleyjkemp.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Bradley J Kemp&lt;/a&gt; - For suggesting the static site generator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; to me which has now become my favourite web framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maggieappleton.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Maggie Appleton&lt;/a&gt; - For her brilliant essay on the history of digital gardens leading me to rethink what I wanted my personal website to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apvarun.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;AP Varun&lt;/a&gt; - For the minimal &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;digital garden Hugo theme&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m using for this website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Yusuf Bouzekri&lt;/a&gt; - For his posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/posts/perfectionism&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;perfectionism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yusuf.fyi/posts/the-content-creation-dilemma&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;the content creation dilemma&lt;/a&gt;, which helped me actually publish this post after reading them both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying Back Your Time</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/buying-back-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/buying-back-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A talk I presented at &lt;a href=&#34;https://yougotthis.io/collections/cyberspace/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;You Got This in Cyberspace&lt;/a&gt; about knowing when to prioritise saving time vs saving money and a simple framework for how we can buy back our time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yougotthis.io/library/buying-back-time&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;View the full talk here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akash &amp; Money Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/akash-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/akash-and-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A writing side project I started in 2020 that covers topics around personal finance. Currently the newsletter has 180+ subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://akashandmoney.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;View the Akash &amp;amp;amp; Money website here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual Receipt Generator</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/manual-receipt-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/manual-receipt-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple python third party terminal client based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monzo/reference-receipts-app&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;reference receipts app&lt;/a&gt; that attaches receipts to Monzo transactions using the Monzo Receipts API and a json payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Manual-Receipt-Generator&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;source code here on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity 3D Platformer</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/unity-3d-platformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/unity-3d-platformer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 3d platformer game with randomised powerup mechanics I made for my final year universirty dissertation project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game focus on giving players a different playthrough experience on each playthrough based on the powerups they acquired throughout each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These powerups affected player stats such as movement speed, jump height, and base attack damage. By manipulating these game elements, each playthrough of the game would be unique due to the randomness of the powerups that were presented in each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this 3d platformer also featured a number of classic platformer game mechanics such as pick-up items (coins), moving platforms, enemies, obstacles and portals to teleport the player around different parts of each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this project recieved a 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TfL to Monzo</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/tfl-to-monzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/tfl-to-monzo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TfL to Monzo was an severless application built as my project for my Cloud Computing module at university with a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was written in Python and made use of AWS Lambda to process TfL jounrey data into Monzo recipts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lambda function would recieve incoming transcation webhook events from a linked Monzo account, check if they were TfL transcations and then run a web scraper script to extract the matching journey data from the TfL web portal before then submitting this data as a reciept to the Monzo receipt API endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of my favourite projects at university and overall we recieved a final mark of 98/100. I also posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/akashgoswami_/status/1112685400336855040&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; of this project and it was highly received.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Workout</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/credit-card-workout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/portfolio/credit-card-workout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A website that takes a users credit card balance, interest rate and monthly amount they wish to pay to calculate how long it would take them to pay their debt off as well as showing them how much interest they have accumulated. This was made within 24 hours for the Porticode 2.0 Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skyth3r/Credit-Card-Workout&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;source code is hosted here on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my &lt;a href=&#34;https://nownownow.com/about&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;now page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-what-im-up-to&#34;&gt;⭐ What I&amp;rsquo;m up to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in London and currently work at &lt;a href=&#34;https://monzo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Monzo Bank&lt;/a&gt; as a Cybersecurity Backend Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-learning&#34;&gt;🤓 Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m working on improving my programming skills. I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also learning German 🇩🇪.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-fitness&#34;&gt;🤸🏽‍♂️ Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently getting back into going to the gym regularly 🏋🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing to cycle to work more regularly 🚴🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still trying to get into running 🏃🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got into hiking over the last year. Last month, I hiked up Ben Nevis in Scotland 🏴󠁧󠁢󠁳󠁣󠁴󠁿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-travel&#34;&gt;🌏 Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far this year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the following countries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇳🇱 The Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇩🇪 Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇯🇵 Japan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇻🇳 Vietnam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇮🇩 Indonesia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇸🇬 Singapore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏴󠁧󠁢󠁳󠁣󠁴󠁿 Scotland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-books&#34;&gt;📚 Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently reading through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Product/Charlie-Higson/The-Sacrifice-The-Enemy-Book-4/11732279&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Hunted&lt;/a&gt;, book 6 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hive.co.uk/Search/Search?Series=The%20Enemy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Enemy series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly getting through &lt;a href=&#34;https://shop.peregrinecoast.press/products/filmmakers-without-cameras-the-trilogy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Filmmakers without Cameras: Issue 3&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-films--tv-shows&#34;&gt;🎬 Films &amp;amp; TV Shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recently-watched-films&#34;&gt;Recently watched films&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbenheimer&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Barbenheimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u3V5KDHRQvk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/shW9i6k8cB0?t=5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Spider-man: Across the Spider-Verse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eQfMbSe7F2g&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recently-watched-tv-shows&#34;&gt;Recently watched TV shows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5jY1ecibLYo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Black Mirror, season 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-video-games&#34;&gt;🎮 Video Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nintendo.co.uk/Games/Nintendo-Switch-games/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Tears-of-the-Kingdom-1576884.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom&lt;/a&gt; on my Nintendo Switch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 9th September 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>