<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Akash Goswami</title>
    <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Akash Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DRM free books</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/removing-drm-from-kindle-books/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy reading books on my Kindle. I also buy most of my digital books via Amazon. I never thought about making DRM-free copies of my eBooks until I read about how an engineer has his Amazon account suspended due to a delivery driver&amp;rsquo;s false claim.
That really got me thinking about how I would feel if I lost access to my Amazon account. I’ve purchased most of my ebooks from Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Leave (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/sabbatical-leave-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/sabbatical-leave-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I took 9 weeks off work. Of those 9 weeks, I spent 8 travelling. This is a summary of how I found my time off and what I did, things I learnt from my first long-term travel trip and my favourite highlights.
What is sabbatical leave? A quick 101 - sabbatical leave is an extended period of time away from work. Common reasons for taking sabbatical leave are to pursue interests outside of work; such as travelling, studying, volunteering or even just to take a break to just rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising my Hugo Theme</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/customising-my-hugo-theme/</guid>
      <description>My Hugo website uses the Digital Garden Hugo theme but I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes in addition to using the theme. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed these changes below both for myself to refer back to and for anyone else that might find these useful to include in their own Hugo website 👇🏽
Updating lastmod text One of the first changes I made was to change the lastmod front matter text that was displayed on the theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/building-websites-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Please note
Due to issues with the theme, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to remove the code blocks from this article. The code is still present below but it&amp;rsquo;s not formatted as a code block. I&amp;rsquo;ll update this once this issue is fixed.
In the last few months, there has been a flurry of activity around personal blogs and owning your own data, since Musk took the reins of Twitter.
With that, a lot of people have been wondering how they can start their own websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a personal website</title>
      <link>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Skyth3r.github.io/articles/why-you-need-a-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>Time and time again, we are shown that we cannot rely on third-party platforms to host our content.
The internet is constantly changing and with that, the platforms that host our content are constantly in flux. Platforms can fall just as quickly as they can rise, either by just going completely offline or by making drastic changes to how people interact with content on their site/platform.
There are countless examples of this happening in the past and more recently the 2022 Twitter meltdown has led to some massive changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
